<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oncology | BIG Event Tracker</title>
    <link>/tag/20210602oncology/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/20210602oncology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Oncology</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Oncology</title>
      <link>/tag/20210602oncology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI EIWG Webinar: Estimands in Oncology - How and Why</title>
      <link>/webinar/20210602psi-eiwg-webinar-estimands-in-oncology-how-and-why-session-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20210602psi-eiwg-webinar-estimands-in-oncology-how-and-why-session-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year on after the final ICH E9 estimands addendum was published, we bring estimands to life. Members of the Estimands in Oncology special interest group will describe how the estimand framework provides a common language to describe the diversity of patient journeys and why it is important to address the right question in clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be guided through a case study and interactively deepen the knowledge to gain hands-on experience in developing estimands. You will be introduced to the background and disease context of the case study, the concept of an estimand, and important clinical events (increased dropout rate and crossover therapy) that occurred in the trial and affected interpretation of the results. Using non-technical language and clear graphical presentation of the concepts, you will experience how the estimand framework provides a common language to describe the diversity of patient journeys and why it is important to address the right question in clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI Webinar: Oncology Ted Style Talks (with interaction)</title>
      <link>/webinar/20210525psi-webinar-oncology-ted-style-talks-with-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20210525psi-webinar-oncology-ted-style-talks-with-interaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PSI members: free; non-members: £20+VAT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of this PSI virtual meeting is to enable practical interaction among clinical statisticians actively working in oncology and those interested to work in this area. The simple format of this meeting specifically facilitates these interactions, by balancing equally time dedicated to a sequence of short, engaging talks covering a broad range of relevant topics and to Q&amp;amp;A. A breakout session halfway through the meeting will also enable casual interactions with the speakers and among meeting participants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 4th Stat4Onc Annual Symposium (2021)</title>
      <link>/conference/20210506the-4th-stat4onc-annual-symposium-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/conference/20210506the-4th-stat4onc-annual-symposium-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Topics for this symposium include big data and genomics, novel dose-finding designs, umbrella/basket designs, drug combinations, immune-based oncology, and engagement of under-representative population in oncology research.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: Mar 31, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bias and Randomization 1980 - 2020 - 2060</title>
      <link>/webinar/20210211bias-and-randomization-1980-2020-2060/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20210211bias-and-randomization-1980-2020-2060/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn on history of bias and randomization in oncology clinical trials and how to think about what constitutes persuasive evidence of treatment efficacy and safety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Early Stage Oncology Research with Adaptive Designs and Master Protocols</title>
      <link>/webinar/20200929advancing-early-stage-oncology-research-with-adaptive-designs-and-master-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20200929advancing-early-stage-oncology-research-with-adaptive-designs-and-master-protocols/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved determination of the maximum tolerated dose, comparing different designs for dose selection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantages of basket trial design for finding the most appropriate indication(s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current regulatory positions and outlook of the International Council for Harmonization of Technical Requirements for Pharmaceuticals for Human use (ICH)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operational implications of different designs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Companion Diagnostics and Clinical Development in Oncology: A Statistical Perspective</title>
      <link>/webinar/20200917companion-diagnostics-and-clinical-development-in-oncology-a-statistical-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20200917companion-diagnostics-and-clinical-development-in-oncology-a-statistical-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This webinar provided a discussion around the need for integration of biomarker and IVD validation in clinical development, with a focus in oncology and companion diagnostics. It highlighted how flawed analytical and/or clinical validation can jeopardize a biomarker’s and drug’s clinical utility and showcase why biomarkers deserved statistical rigor throughout the development and validation process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Endpoints and Treatment Effect in Immuno-Oncology</title>
      <link>/webinar/20200707clinical-endpoints-and-treatment-effect-in-immuno-oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20200707clinical-endpoints-and-treatment-effect-in-immuno-oncology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this webinar the speakers reviewed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptations to tumor response and progression criteria for immune therapies. Survival may be the endpoint of choice for clinical trials in some tumor types, but presence of delayed treatment effects and non-proportional hazards may complicate evaluation of treatment benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistical methods to best describe and test for treatment effects in immuno-oncology randomized clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
