<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSE Tracker</title>
    <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CSE Tracker</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 09:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>CSE Tracker</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Randomized Trial with Sample Size Re-estimation - Challenges and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210325designing-a-randomized-trial-with-sample-size-re-estimation-challenges-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210325designing-a-randomized-trial-with-sample-size-re-estimation-challenges-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, we will play the part of a sponsor consulting a statistician with the goal of designing a randomized trial with sample-size re-estimation. We will discuss the concept of conditional power and the promising-zone method, and we will present a pragmatic view of some issues, including when to plan the sample-size re-estimation in the course of the accrual, how to select the amount of sample-size increase, and how to operate such trials in practice. We will also discuss the pros- and cons- of using this type of design in relation to the clinical setting in which the trial is designed and endpoints it uses. Moreover, we will discuss the regulators’ views and illustrate our discussion with practical examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI Journal Club: Survival Analysis</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210324psi-journal-club-survival-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210324psi-journal-club-survival-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non‐proportional hazards in immuno‐oncology: Is an old perspective needed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Publication: Dominic Magirr, Pharmaceutical Statistics. 2020;1-16&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A weighted log‐rank test and associated effect estimator for cancer trials with delayed treatment effect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Publication: Chang Yu, Xiang Huang, Hui Nian and Philip He, Pharmaceutical Statistics. 2021;1-23&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from COVID-19 Data on Transmission, Health Outcomes, Interventions and Vaccination </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210323learning-from-covid-19-data-on-transmission-health-outcomes-interventions-and-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210323learning-from-covid-19-data-on-transmission-health-outcomes-interventions-and-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;br&gt;
ASA Members: $20&lt;br&gt;
Student ASA Member: $15&lt;br&gt;
Nonmembers: $35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will first provide a historical overview of the epidemic in Wuhan. I will then provide the analysis results of 32,000 lab-confirmed COVID-19 cases in Wuhan to estimate the transmission rates using Poisson Partial Differential Equation based transmission dynamic models. This model is also used to evaluate the effects of different public health interventions on controlling the COVID-19 outbreak, such as social distancing, isolation and quarantine. I will present the results on the epidemiological characteristics of the cases. The results show that multi-faceted intervention measures successfully controlled the outbreak in Wuhan. I will next present transmission regression models for estimating transmission rates in USA and other countries, as well as factors including intervention effects using social distancing, test-trace-isolate strategies that affect transmission rates. I will discuss estimation of the proportion of undetected cases, including asymptomatic, pre-symptomatic cases and mildly symptomatic cases, the chances of resurgence in different scenarios, prevalence, and the factors that affect transmissions. I will also present the US county-level analysis to study the demographic, social-economic, and comorbidity factors that are associated with COVID-19 case and death rates. I will also present the analysis results of &amp;gt;500,000 participants of the HowWeFeel project on health outcomes and behaviors in US, and discuss the factors associated with infection, behavior, and vaccine hesitancy. I will provide several takeaways and discuss priorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Representative Samples in Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210323the-importance-of-representative-samples-in-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210323the-importance-of-representative-samples-in-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ds.dfci.harvard.edu/event/data-science-zoominar-the-importance-of-representative-samples-in-clinical-trials/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event Page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cardiac Safety from Preclinical to the Clinic – Industry and Regulatory Trends in T-QT and Concentration-QT Studies for Assessing QT Prolongation Risks</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210323cardiac-safety-from-preclinical-to-the-clinic-industry-and-regulatory-trends-in-t-qt-and-concentration-qt-studies-for-assessing-qt-prolongation-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 08:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210323cardiac-safety-from-preclinical-to-the-clinic-industry-and-regulatory-trends-in-t-qt-and-concentration-qt-studies-for-assessing-qt-prolongation-risks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symposium Agenda (All times are in Pacific Time)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1: March 23, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;8:30-8:45am:&lt;/em&gt; Introductions&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;8:45-9:30am:&lt;/em&gt; State-of-the-Art: TQT studies (QT and C-QT Analyses, Challenges &amp;amp; Examples) - Borje Darpo (ERT)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;9:30-10:15am:&lt;/em&gt; Cardiac safety and TQT waivers (Types of studies - FIH, Food effect, DDI and timing, Issues with ECG collection) - Jay Mason (Spaulding)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;10:15-10:25am:&lt;/em&gt; Sponsor Presentation&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;10:25-10:40am:&lt;/em&gt; Break&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;10:40-11:25am:&lt;/em&gt; TBD&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;11:25am-12:10pm:&lt;/em&gt; New opportunities for C-QT and C-QT in non-ideal scenarios - Lauren Lohmer (Nuventra)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;12:10pm-12:40pm:&lt;/em&gt; Panel Discussion&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2: March 24, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:grey&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;8:30-8:45am:&lt;/em&gt; Introductions&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;8:45-9:30am:&lt;/em&gt; Case Study - Biologics C-QT project supporting a major readout - Yehong Wang (Genentech)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;9:30-10:15am:&lt;/em&gt; TBD&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;10:15-10:25am:&lt;/em&gt; Sponsor Presentation&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;10:25-10:40am:&lt;/em&gt; Break&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;10:40-11:25am:&lt;/em&gt; Non-clinical aspects related to the ICH Q&amp;amp;A - Anne Bonneville (Terns Pharmaceuticals)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;11:25pm-12:05pm:&lt;/em&gt; Panel Discussion 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of Putative Causal Loci in Whole-Genome Sequencing Data via Knockoff Statistics</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210312identification-of-putative-causal-loci-in-whole-genome-sequencing-data-via-knockoff-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210312identification-of-putative-causal-loci-in-whole-genome-sequencing-data-via-knockoff-statistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The analysis of whole-genome sequencing studies is challenging due to the large number of rare variants in noncoding regions and the lack of natural units for testing. Existing association tests often suffer from insufficient power due to the substantially increased burden of multiple testing and correspondingly stringent multiple testing corrections that do not appropriately account for correlations. Using population-level whole-genome sequencing data, we propose a new statistical method to detect and localize rare and common risk variants based on a recently developed knockoff framework. The proposed approach includes a novel sequential knockoff generator for both rare and common variants in whole-genome sequencing studies, paired with a powerful screening method to comprehensively analyze rare and common variants across the genome. The proposed knockoff generator is scalable to large whole-genome sequencing datasets, and the screening method is powerful in detecting signals across the genome with guaranteed false discovery rate control. Furthermore, it can (1) prioritize causal variants over associations due to linkage disequilibrium thereby improving interpretability; (2) help distinguish the signal due to rare variants from shadow effects of significant common variants nearby; (3) integrate multiple knockoffs for improved power, stability and reproducibility; and (4) flexibly incorporate state-of-the-art and future association tests to achieve the benefits proposed here. In applications to whole-genome sequencing data from the Alzheimer’s Disease Sequencing Project (ADSP) and COPDGene samples from NHLBI Trans-Omics for Precision Medicine (TOPMed) Program we show that our method compared with conventional association tests can lead to substantially more discoveries, including several new ones and many previously implicated in GWAS studies on Alzheimer’s Disease and lung function phenotypes with much larger sample sizes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veridical Data Science for biomedical discovery: detecting epistatic interactions with epiTree</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210226veridical-data-science-for-biomedical-discovery-detecting-epistatic-interactions-with-epitree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 09:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210226veridical-data-science-for-biomedical-discovery-detecting-epistatic-interactions-with-epitree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data Science is a pillar of A.I. and has driven most of recent cutting-edge discoveries in biomedical research. In practice, Data Science has a life cycle (DSLC) that includes problem formulation, data collection, data cleaning, modeling, result interpretation and the drawing of conclusions. Human judgement calls are ubiquitous at every step of this process, e.g., in choosing data cleaning methods, predictive algorithms and data perturbations. Such judgment calls are often responsible for the &amp;ldquo;dangers&amp;rdquo; of A.I. To maximally mitigate these dangers, we developed a framework based on three core principles: Predictability, Computability and Stability (PCS). Through a workflow and documentation (in R Markdown or Jupyter Notebook) that allows one to manage the whole DSLC, the PCS framework unifies, streamlines and expands on the best practices of machine learning and statistics - bringing us a step forward towards veridical Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lecture, we will illustrate the PCS framework through the epiTree; a pipeline to discover epistasis interactions from genomics data. epiTree addresses issues of scaling of penetrance through decision trees, significance calling through PCS p-values, and combinatorial search over interactions through iterative random forests (which is a special case of PCS). Using UK Biobank data, we validate the epiTree pipeline through an application to the red-hair phenotype, where several genes are known to display epistatic interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illuminating the Black Box: Variable Importance Measures for Interpretable Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210225illuminating-the-black-box-variable-importance-measures-for-interpretable-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210225illuminating-the-black-box-variable-importance-measures-for-interpretable-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recording passcode&lt;/strong&gt;: 6cleDgX+&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Dr. Wolf will provide an overview of common machine learning methods (e.g. ensemble methods, support vector machines and neural networks) and discuss currently implemented importance measures that provide semi-quantitative measures of associations between variables and outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Randomized Studies and Utilization of Real-World Evidence</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201217non-randomized-studies-and-utilization-of-real-world-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201217non-randomized-studies-and-utilization-of-real-world-evidence/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Monitoring and Adaptive Designs</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201215data-monitoring-and-adaptive-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201215data-monitoring-and-adaptive-designs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Machine Learning &amp; Causal Inference Workshop</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201215interpretable-machine-learning-causal-inference-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201215interpretable-machine-learning-causal-inference-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 2 Fallacy: Or why interpretation needs more than transparency (Peter Tennant)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using causal machine learning to explore heterogeneous responses to policies (Noemi Kreif)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symbolic machine learning for interpretable AI: recent advancements and future directions (Alessandra Russo)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questioning the AI: towards human-centered interpretable machine learning (Vera Liao)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COPSS-NISS COVID-19 Data Science Webinar Series</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201203copss-niss-covid-19-data-science-webinar-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201203copss-niss-covid-19-data-science-webinar-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The COPSS-NISS COVID-19 Data Science webinar series is co-organized by the Committee of the Presidents of Statistical Societies (COPSS) and its five charter member societies (ASA, ENAR, IMS, SSC, and WNAR), as well as NISS.  This twice a month webinar (1st and 3rd Thursday at noon EST) features the latest research that is positioned on the cusp of new understanding and analysis of COVID-19 pandemic data and promotes data-driven research and decision making to combat COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 New England Rare Disease Statistics (NERDS) Webinar Series</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/202011022020-new-england-rare-disease-statistics-nerds-webinar-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/202011022020-new-england-rare-disease-statistics-nerds-webinar-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Introductory NERDS Session&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to Select Endpoints and Quantify Treatment Effect in a Comparative Clinical Study on COVID-19 Diseases (L.J. Wei (Harvard))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borrowing Information from Historical Data: A Double-edged Sword (Ying Yuan (MD Anderson))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pfizerevents.webex.com/pfizerevents/lsr.php?RCID=13985dd6a939e0e4f8998620b4a428b1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recording&lt;/a&gt; (Password: hWFURkY5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. CID Program Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Bayesian Adaptive Trial in Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy (Steve Lake (Wave Life Sciences))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovative Designs in the Rare Disease Setting (Dionne Price (FDA))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pfizerevents.webex.com/pfizerevents/lsr.php?RCID=1bc6e1d02b1002d62c170a17473e3d54&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recording&lt;/a&gt; (Password: pMbpsJT7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Gene Therapy in Rare Disease Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gene Therapy: Opportunities and Challenges for the Treatment of Hemophilia (Michelle Casey (Pfizer))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pfizerevents.webex.com/pfizerevents/lsr.php?RCID=ccaaeefdd89e63e72892e9650397f117&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recording&lt;/a&gt; (Password: NERDS456)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Case Studies in Rare Disease Drug Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lessons from Notable New Drug Application involving External Controls (Margaret (Meg) Gamalo (Pfizer))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design and Analysis of Drop the Losers Studies in the Rare Disease Setting (Glen Laird (Vertex))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Case Study Using Nature History Data to Understand Long Term Disease Progression (Cindy Lu (Biogen))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pfizerevents.webex.com/pfizerevents/lsr.php?RCID=e227bbfd8699459593dffc5ce07cd795&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recording&lt;/a&gt; (Password: Pq8pBWgU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovations in Bayesian Clinical Trials Interactive Workshops</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201015innovations-in-bayesian-clinical-trials-interactive-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201015innovations-in-bayesian-clinical-trials-interactive-workshops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive Workshop 1: Essentials of Bayesian Statistics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
October 15, 2020&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;loginemail=peiwen.wu%40gilead.com&amp;amp;eventid=2691551&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=109B6B88F22396785524BCAD42C50522&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive Workshop 2: Bayesian Meta-Analysis and Hierarchical Models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
October 29, 2020&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;loginemail=peiwen.wu%40gilead.com&amp;amp;eventid=2691558&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=8543F409BD3894D06579F92276808A5D&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive Workshop 3: Prior Distributions (Part I)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
November 12, 2020&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;loginemail=peiwen.wu%40gilead.com&amp;amp;eventid=2691561&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=238DEB3AC5D91E14B89095AF22C63D05&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12th Annual Sentinel Initiative Public Workshop</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/2020101412th-annual-sentinel-initiative-public-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/2020101412th-annual-sentinel-initiative-public-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session I: A Robust Sentinel System for the 21st Century&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Objective: In response to new legislative mandates and the desire to diversify scientific expertise and enhance core key capabilities in the Sentinel System, the Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER) has awarded a new five-year contract that establishes a new organizational structure for the Sentinel Coordinating Center. This new contract builds on FDA successes integrating the active, post-market safety surveillance into regulatory decision-making. This session will feature key leads from each Sentinel coordinating center who will discuss plans on how to advance and transform Sentinel’s data infrastructure into a national resource for evidence generation. Panelists will also discuss opportunities for collaboration to broaden stakeholder involvement, improve access to new data sources and analytic tools, and ensure more efficient and effective safety surveillance activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session II: Building the BEST Network and Establishing New Capabilities for the Surveillance of Biologics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Objective: Launched in 2017, the BEST Initiative enacts the Agency’s mandate to implement active surveillance for biologic products. This session will highlight key achievements of BEST over the last year enhancing its capabilities to execute safety and effectiveness surveillance and inform regulatory decision making. CBER representatives will discuss ongoing work to support the expansion of the BEST data network and methods infrastructure as well as specific studies utilizing the infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session III: Leveraging the Sentinel Initiative for COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Objective: The U.S. FDA’s Sentinel Initiative is engaged in numerous activities to protect and promote public health during the COVID-19 pandemic. This session will highlight key ongoing efforts across CDER and CBER to leverage Sentinel data infrastructure to describe course of illness, and evaluate the utilization, safety, and effectiveness of available COVID-19 therapeutics and vaccines under real-world conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under the Hood of 1Point3Acres COVID-19 Map and Tracker</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200925under-the-hood-of-1point3acres-covid-19-map-and-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200925under-the-hood-of-1point3acres-covid-19-map-and-tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Yu will first discuss how her volunteer team fought to have brought data transparency to CovidNet. Then, Kyle will present his team’s novel approach to continuous data quality monitoring, which combines semantic analysis with time series anomaly detection methods, ending with some examples showing issues (known and benign) detected in the 1point3acres dataset. Prof Shan Lu will also provide an example how the high quality data source can be highly useful for even non-biological scientists to produce meaningful analysis in a situation like COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Multiple Natural Experimental Designs to Triangulate the Impact of a Policy Change</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200717dahshu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200717dahshu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Estimating causal effects is best done using randomized controlled trials. Regrettably, for many policy-relevant questions only observational data are available. In this talk we explore how (i) decomposing a policy into multiple parts, and (ii) leveraging multiple study designs can produce stronger, more defensible causal estimates.&lt;br&gt;
We explore these statistical concepts through an example from health outcomes research: The feasibility and effectiveness of delaying surgery to transfer patients with acute type A aortic dissection—a catastrophic disease that requires prompt intervention—to higher-volume aortic surgery hospitals is unknown. We investigated the hypothesis that regionalizing care at high-volume hospitals for acute type A aortic dissections will lower mortality. We decomposed this hypothesis into subparts, investigating the isolated effect of transfer and the isolated effect of receiving care at a high-volume versus a low-volume facility. We used a preference-based instrumental variable design to address unmeasured confounding and matching to separate the effect of transfer from volume. We used the carefully deployed instrumental variable design, and contrast it with a decomposed propensity score study design, to gain deeper insights into the elements giving rise to confounding. We also develop a simple, but complete, form of sensitivity analysis to bound the effect of censored observations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19: Pandemic Preparedness and Lessons Learned</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200610dia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200610dia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An overview of how COVID-19 progressed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can pharmaceutical companies be better prepared? Should there be plans and clinical development strategies in place?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we build resiliency? What steps could/should be implemented at various stages to ‘flatten the curve’?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vulnerable communities and minority populations are at a disadvantage. How do we address these health disparities?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
