<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science | CSE Tracker</title>
    <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/category/20210323data-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/category/20210323data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Data Science</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Data Science</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/category/20210323data-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from COVID-19 Data on Transmission, Health Outcomes, Interventions and Vaccination </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210323learning-from-covid-19-data-on-transmission-health-outcomes-interventions-and-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210323learning-from-covid-19-data-on-transmission-health-outcomes-interventions-and-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;br&gt;
ASA Members: $20&lt;br&gt;
Student ASA Member: $15&lt;br&gt;
Nonmembers: $35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will first provide a historical overview of the epidemic in Wuhan. I will then provide the analysis results of 32,000 lab-confirmed COVID-19 cases in Wuhan to estimate the transmission rates using Poisson Partial Differential Equation based transmission dynamic models. This model is also used to evaluate the effects of different public health interventions on controlling the COVID-19 outbreak, such as social distancing, isolation and quarantine. I will present the results on the epidemiological characteristics of the cases. The results show that multi-faceted intervention measures successfully controlled the outbreak in Wuhan. I will next present transmission regression models for estimating transmission rates in USA and other countries, as well as factors including intervention effects using social distancing, test-trace-isolate strategies that affect transmission rates. I will discuss estimation of the proportion of undetected cases, including asymptomatic, pre-symptomatic cases and mildly symptomatic cases, the chances of resurgence in different scenarios, prevalence, and the factors that affect transmissions. I will also present the US county-level analysis to study the demographic, social-economic, and comorbidity factors that are associated with COVID-19 case and death rates. I will also present the analysis results of &amp;gt;500,000 participants of the HowWeFeel project on health outcomes and behaviors in US, and discuss the factors associated with infection, behavior, and vaccine hesitancy. I will provide several takeaways and discuss priorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veridical Data Science for biomedical discovery: detecting epistatic interactions with epiTree</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210226veridical-data-science-for-biomedical-discovery-detecting-epistatic-interactions-with-epitree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 09:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210226veridical-data-science-for-biomedical-discovery-detecting-epistatic-interactions-with-epitree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data Science is a pillar of A.I. and has driven most of recent cutting-edge discoveries in biomedical research. In practice, Data Science has a life cycle (DSLC) that includes problem formulation, data collection, data cleaning, modeling, result interpretation and the drawing of conclusions. Human judgement calls are ubiquitous at every step of this process, e.g., in choosing data cleaning methods, predictive algorithms and data perturbations. Such judgment calls are often responsible for the &amp;ldquo;dangers&amp;rdquo; of A.I. To maximally mitigate these dangers, we developed a framework based on three core principles: Predictability, Computability and Stability (PCS). Through a workflow and documentation (in R Markdown or Jupyter Notebook) that allows one to manage the whole DSLC, the PCS framework unifies, streamlines and expands on the best practices of machine learning and statistics - bringing us a step forward towards veridical Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lecture, we will illustrate the PCS framework through the epiTree; a pipeline to discover epistasis interactions from genomics data. epiTree addresses issues of scaling of penetrance through decision trees, significance calling through PCS p-values, and combinatorial search over interactions through iterative random forests (which is a special case of PCS). Using UK Biobank data, we validate the epiTree pipeline through an application to the red-hair phenotype, where several genes are known to display epistatic interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 ASA Conference on Statistical Practice</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210217csp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210217csp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of the conference is to provide participants with opportunities to learn new statistical methodologies and best practices in statistical analysis, design, consulting, and statistical programming.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: 2021-01-11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COPSS-NISS COVID-19 Data Science Webinar Series</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201203copss-niss-covid-19-data-science-webinar-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201203copss-niss-covid-19-data-science-webinar-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The COPSS-NISS COVID-19 Data Science webinar series is co-organized by the Committee of the Presidents of Statistical Societies (COPSS) and its five charter member societies (ASA, ENAR, IMS, SSC, and WNAR), as well as NISS.  This twice a month webinar (1st and 3rd Thursday at noon EST) features the latest research that is positioned on the cusp of new understanding and analysis of COVID-19 pandemic data and promotes data-driven research and decision making to combat COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under the Hood of 1Point3Acres COVID-19 Map and Tracker</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200925under-the-hood-of-1point3acres-covid-19-map-and-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200925under-the-hood-of-1point3acres-covid-19-map-and-tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Yu will first discuss how her volunteer team fought to have brought data transparency to CovidNet. Then, Kyle will present his team’s novel approach to continuous data quality monitoring, which combines semantic analysis with time series anomaly detection methods, ending with some examples showing issues (known and benign) detected in the 1point3acres dataset. Prof Shan Lu will also provide an example how the high quality data source can be highly useful for even non-biological scientists to produce meaningful analysis in a situation like COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
