<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conferences | CSE Tracker</title>
    <link>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Conferences</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Conferences</title>
      <link>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 ASA Conference on Statistical Practice</title>
      <link>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/20210217csp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/20210217csp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of the conference is to provide participants with opportunities to learn new statistical methodologies and best practices in statistical analysis, design, consulting, and statistical programming.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: 2021-01-11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12th Annual Sentinel Initiative Public Workshop</title>
      <link>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/2020101412th-annual-sentinel-initiative-public-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/2020101412th-annual-sentinel-initiative-public-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sentinel Initiative, an active medical product surveillance system, was established in response to the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) Amendments Act of 2007 and has become one of the Agency’s premier evidence generation platforms. The 12th Annual Sentinel Initiative Public Workshop is being convened on October 14, 2020 by the Robert J. Margolis, MD, Center for Health Policy under a cooperative agreement with the FDA. The workshop will be held as a virtual webinar and provides an opportunity to discuss recent achievements and developments and engage with the broader community of patients, consumers, and scientific stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Pharma</title>
      <link>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/20201013r-in-pharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/20201013r-in-pharma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2020 R/Pharma conference was held as a virtual event between October 13th and 15th October. Over 1000 people from 26 countries registered for the main conference. In addition, 11 workshops were held the week before the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Real World Evidence Conference: Applying Lessons Learned from RWE in the Time of COVID-19 to the Future</title>
      <link>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/20201001annual-real-world-evidence-conference-applying-lessons-learned-from-rwe-in-the-time-of-covid-19-to-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/20201001annual-real-world-evidence-conference-applying-lessons-learned-from-rwe-in-the-time-of-covid-19-to-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 has disrupted the evidence-generation paradigm, resulting in the expanded use of novel technologies, data, and evidence. These new advancements not only improve clinical care and medical product development to fight the pandemic, but also have the potential to inform the future of drug development more broadly. This meeting will explore how COVID-19 has accelerated decision-maker understanding and use of real-world data (RWD) and real-world evidence (RWE) and its application in a post-COVID-19 environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Biopharmaceutical Section Regulatory-Industry Statistics Workshop 2020</title>
      <link>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/20200922asa-biopharmaceutical-section-regulatory-industry-statistics-workshop-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pwustat.github.io/csetracker/conference/20200922asa-biopharmaceutical-section-regulatory-industry-statistics-workshop-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ASA Biopharmaceutical Section Regulatory-Industry Statistics Workshop is sponsored by the ASA Biopharmaceutical Section in cooperation with the FDA Statistical Association. The conference lasts two days each year, with invited sessions co-chaired by statisticians from industry, academia, and the FDA. In addition, short courses on related topics are offered the day prior to the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
