<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>survival | BIG Event Tracker</title>
    <link>/tag/20211019survival/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/20211019survival/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>survival</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>survival</title>
      <link>/tag/20211019survival/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment-free Survival as a Novel Outcome Measure of Immuno-oncology-based Therapy</title>
      <link>/webinar/20211019treatment-free-survival/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20211019treatment-free-survival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Biostatistics by Dana-Farber Cancer Institute&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possible Hazards of Proportional Hazards Models</title>
      <link>/webinar/20211015possible-hazards-of-proportional-hazards-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20211015possible-hazards-of-proportional-hazards-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ASA North Carolina Chapter Webinar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cox proportional hazard (PH) model is widely used to determine the effects of risk factors and treatments on survival time of subjects that might be right censored. The selection of covariates may depend crucially on the specific form of the chosen conditional hazard model, which is often assumed to be PH, accelerated failure time (AFT), or proportional odds (PO). However, through empirical and theoretical
examples show that none of these semiparametric models allow for the crossing of the survival functions and hence such strong assumptions may adversely affect the selection of variables. Moreover, the most commonly
used PH assumption may also be violated when there is a delayed effect of the risk factors. A sequence of Bernstein polynomials based model is instead presented which provides (i) a smooth estimator of the conditional hazard function and is shown to be a unique solution of a strictly convex optimization problem; making it computationally attractive, (ii) a model that encompasses PH structure, and (iii) large sample properties including consistency and convergence rates established under a set of mild regularity conditions. Empirical results based on several simulated data scenarios indicate that the superior performances of the model and thereby shown to avoid possible hazards of the proportional hazard like assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survival Outcome Data with High Dimensional Predictors: Methods and Applications</title>
      <link>/course/20210624survival-outcome-data-with-high-dimensional-predictors-methods-and-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/course/20210624survival-outcome-data-with-high-dimensional-predictors-methods-and-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ASA members: $40; non-members: $65&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the era of precision medicine, survival outcome data with high-throughput covariates and predictors are often collected. These high dimensional data defy classical survival regression models, which are either infeasible to fit or likely to incur low predictability because of overfitting. This short course will introduce various cutting-edge methods that handle survival outcome data with high dimensional predictors. I will cover statistical principles and concepts behind the methods, and will also discuss their applications to the real medical examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time permitting, I intend to cover the following topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival analysis overview: basic concepts and models, e.g. Cox, Accelerated Failure Time (AFT), and Censored Quantile Regression (CQR) Models;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival models with high dimensional predictors (p&amp;gt;n): Regularized methods and Dantzig selector;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival analysis with ultra-high dimensional predictors (p&amp;raquo;n): Screening Methods, e.g, Principled sure independent screening (PSIS), Conditional screening, IPOD, Forward selection, etc;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inference for survival models with high dimensional predictors (p&amp;gt;n).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience only needs to have some basic knowledge of regression analysis and survival analysis. The relevant papers and software for this short course can be found in: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~yili/resindex.html&#34;&gt;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~yili/resindex.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: An Introductory Course in Competing Risks</title>
      <link>/course/20210528isi-short-course-an-introductory-course-in-competing-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/course/20210528isi-short-course-an-introductory-course-in-competing-risks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Survival function and hazard function. Right-censoring and left-truncation. Competing risks. Markov and non-Markov multi-state models. Time-homogeneity and time inhomogeneity. Motivating examples (real data).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing risks: The competing risks multi-state model. Non-identifiability in the latent failure time model. Cause-specific hazards (transition intensities) and sub-distribution hazards. Cumulative incidence functions. Simulating competing risks data. Nonparametric estimation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportional hazards regression models: Proportional cause-specific hazards model. Proportional sub-distribution hazards model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Clinical Trial Design - Survival, Stepped-Wedge &amp; MAMS Designs</title>
      <link>/webinar/20200723flexible-clinical-trial-design-survival-stepped-wedge-mams-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20200723flexible-clinical-trial-design-survival-stepped-wedge-mams-designs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible Survival Analysis Designs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Non-proportional hazards and other complex survival curves have become of increasing interest, due to being commonly seen in immunotherapy development. This has led to interest in assessing the robustness of standard methods and alternative methods that better adapt to deviations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, we will look at power analysis assuming complex survival curves and the weighted log-rank test as one candidate model to deal with a delayed survival effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stepped-Wedge designs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Cluster-randomized designs are often adopted when there is a high risk of contamination if cluster members were randomized individually. Stepped-wedge designs are useful in cases where it is difficult to apply a particular treatment to half of the clusters at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, we will introduce stepped-wedge designs and provide an insight into the more complex, flexible randomization schedules available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Arm Multi-Stage (MAMS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
MAMs designs provide the ability to assess more treatments in less time than could be done with a series of two-arm trials and can offer smaller sample size requirements when compared to that required for the equivalent number of two-arm trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, we will look at the design of a Group Sequential MAMS design and explore its design requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
