<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSE Tracker</title>
    <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CSE Tracker</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>CSE Tracker</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Women in Statistics and Data Science Conference</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202110062021-women-in-statistics-and-data-science-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202110062021-women-in-statistics-and-data-science-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: August 19, 2021; ASA member $335, Nonmember $435&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2021 Women in Statistics and Data Science Conference aims to bring together hundreds of statistical practitioners and data scientists. WSDS 2021 will highlight the achievements and career interests of women in statistics and data science. Senior, mid-level, and junior stars representing industrial, academic, and government communities will unite to present their life’s work and share their perspectives on the role of women in today’s statistics and data science fields. Through formal sessions and informal networking opportunities, the conference will empower and challenge women statisticians and biostatisticians to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share knowledge by offering technical talks about important, modern, and cutting-edge research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build community by encouraging discussions establishing fruitful multi-disciplinary collaborations, supporting mentoring relationships, and sharing strategies for resolving problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grow influence by providing advice for establishing and sustaining successful careers, showcasing the accomplishments of successful women professionals, and supporting the development of leadership skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 ASA Biopharmaceutical Section Regulatory-Industry Statistics Workshop</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202109212021-asa-biopharmaceutical-section-regulatory-industry-statistics-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202109212021-asa-biopharmaceutical-section-regulatory-industry-statistics-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: August 16, 2021; ASA BIOP Member $225, Nonmember $300&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ASA Biopharmaceutical Section Regulatory-Industry Statistics Workshop is sponsored by the ASA Biopharmaceutical Section in cooperation with the FDA Statistical Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each year, the conference lasts three days, with invited sessions co-chaired by statisticians from industry, academia, and the FDA and short courses on related topics offered the first day of the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA BIOP Webinar: Putting Pharmacovigilance into Action</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210916asa-biop-webinar-putting-pharmacovigilance-into-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210916asa-biop-webinar-putting-pharmacovigilance-into-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every pharmaceutical company collects, analyzes, and reports safety data collected in trials and in the general use on their products to fulfill regulations and detect new signals to keep their product labels up to date. While those actions have an indirect benefit for the patient, to truly help them and their healthcare practitioners it is necessary to go beyond the raw data and translate the information into the benefit to risk context, informing risk management plans and specific mitigation actions that are derived from data. The goal of pharmacovigilance should be to minimize pain and suffering in patients who strive to benefit from the medicine prescribed by their physician. By properly characterizing benefits and risks of medicines in appropriate populations and semi-quantitatively or quantitatively estimating whether and to which extent the benefits outweigh the risks one can create tangible context for regulators, prescribers, and patients. This informs specific action plans for the health care provider to optimize the use of the treatment ensuring the right medicine gets to right patient. We will present our experience on some specific examples derived directly from our joint experience in safety and pharmacovigilance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Clinical Trial Disclosure and Data Transparency Conference</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210913global-clinical-trial-disclosure-and-data-transparency-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210913global-clinical-trial-disclosure-and-data-transparency-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: July 22, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about the latest requirements in clinical trial disclosure and data transparency, share best practices, and engage in in-depth discussions on hot topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss best practices to achieve good compliance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assess the operational challenges and considerations in executing Innovative Trial Designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss the interplay between clinical data disclosure and transparency requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA SF Bay Area Chapter Webinar: K-12 Students Summer Project Presentation</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210912k-12-students-summer-project-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210912k-12-students-summer-project-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demographic and Social Factors Associated with COVID-19 Vaccination Rate in California&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Presenters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Avelyn Liang, 10th Grade, San Mateo High school&lt;br&gt;
Elaina Li, 8th Grade, Bowditch Middle School &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mentors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ray Lin, Ph.D., Principal Statistical Scientist, Department of Biostatistics, Genentech/Roche; President of SFASA&lt;br&gt;
Priscilla Yen, Ph.D., Biostatistics Manager at Amgen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistical analysis of data on beach pollution in the United States&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Presenters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Anna Khodakovskaia, 8th Grade, Lycee  Francais  de San Francisco&lt;br&gt;
Katherine Tsvirkunova, 12th Grade, Carlmont High School&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mentor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Tao He, Ph.D., Assistant Professor, Department of Mathematics, San Francisco State University; Past President of SFASA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breast Cancer Prediction Using Statistical Models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt;
Anwen Huang, 12th Grade, Lynbrook High School&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mentor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ron Yu, Ph.D., Senior Director of Biostatistics, Gilead Sciences; Director of Public Relations of SFASA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Impact of COVID-19 on Recology Waste Disposal Trends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Presenter:&lt;/strong&gt; 
Weiran Wang, 11th Grade, Aragon High School&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mentor:&lt;/strong&gt;
Jerry Ping, Ph.D., Director of Biostatistics at Pharmacyclics, An Abbvie Company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICSA 2021 Applied Statistics Symposium</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210912icsa-2021-applied-statistics-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210912icsa-2021-applied-statistics-symposium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: July 15, 2021; Member $100, Nonmember $130&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be the 30th annual symposium for the International Chinese Statistical Association (ICSA). The theme of this year’s conference is Leading with Statistics and Innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Boston Chapter Short Course: Master Protocol in Drug Development - Methodology and Implementation</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210910asa-boston-chapter-short-course-master-protocol-in-drug-development-methodology-and-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210910asa-boston-chapter-short-course-master-protocol-in-drug-development-methodology-and-implementation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The scientific communities are in great need to develop innovative trial designs that can incorporate multiple treatments and/or multiple diseases. Such designs provide results for multiple complex hypotheses of clinical interest and reduce the cost and timeline of development. There has been increasing interest in adopting master protocols to expedite clinical development programs. Master protocol have the potential to drive tremendous efficiencies in the development of new therapeutics or vaccines. These trials, in general, are more efficient and less costly than to perform trials individually. These efficiencies can be operational and/or statistical in nature. The master protocol is defined as one overarching protocol that would answer multiple questions or hypotheses. It includes a wide variety of designs with one potential treatment and different disease/population (basket design), multiple potential treatment and one disease (umbrella design), and multiple potential treatment along with multiple disease/population (platform design). In addition, master protocols are adaptive to include early stopping for efficacy or futility, sample size adjustment, dropping an arm, changing randomization ratio, and introducing a new treatment arm during trial. Further statistical efficiency can be gained by use of a shared control. In rare or difficult to enroll populations, a master protocol offers the opportunity to steer important new therapies into a standing clinical trials infrastructure, potentially expediting the availability of badly needed new therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short course will provide an overview of the master protocol along with statistical and operational aspects. This will cover methodology, general design framework and strategies, sample size calculation, and necessary steps for protocol implementation. In addition, we will share through case studies on practical points to consider when running master protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of master protocol: definitions, terminology, and general framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical considerations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operational considerations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practical implementation: study protocol, DSMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Case Study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regulatory guidance: US and rest of the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summary and discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Traveling Course (Hosted by Connecticut Chapter): Guidelines for using State-of-the-Art Methods to Estimate Propensity Score and Inverse Probability of Treatment Weights When Drawing Causal Inferences </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210910asa-traveling-course-hosted-by-connecticut-chapter-causal-inferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210910asa-traveling-course-hosted-by-connecticut-chapter-causal-inferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The estimation of causal effects is one of the primary activities of most longitudinal research studies. For example, analysts might want to understand whether a particular substance abuse treatment program is effective for its clients, whether school-based substance prevention actually reduces substance use, whether interventions can improve the quality and efficiency of mental health care, or whether incentives can increase military recruiting or the retention of service members. Controlled experiments are held as the gold standard for estimating such effects. However, experiments are often infeasible for many reasons and only observational data, in which participation in a program or intervention is out of the control of the researchers, are available for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This short course will provide an introduction to causal modeling using the potential outcomes framework and use of propensity score weights in the estimation of causal effects from observational data. The course will also provide step-by-step guidelines on how to estimate and perform diagnostic checks of propensity score weights for evaluations examining the relative effectiveness of two interventions. The course will also discuss methods for assessing the sensitivity of finding to unobserved covariates. Attendees will gain hands on experience estimating propensity score weights, evaluating the quality of those weights, and utilizing the weights for estimating intervention effects. The course can provide demonstrations of available software in R, SAS, Stata and Shiny (as needed) for fitting the models and opportunities for conducting analyses. The primary goals of the course are for attendees to have an understanding of how to implement propensity score weighting using state-of-art-methods and insights into some of the practical issues that evaluating the quality of propensity score weights involve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Traveling Course (Hosted by Central Indiana Chapter): Guidelines for using State-of-the-Art Methods to Estimate Propensity Score and Inverse Probability of Treatment Weights When Drawing Causal Inferences </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210908asa-traveling-course-central-indiana-chapter-guidelines-to-estimate-propensity-score-and-inverse-probability-of-treatment-weights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210908asa-traveling-course-central-indiana-chapter-guidelines-to-estimate-propensity-score-and-inverse-probability-of-treatment-weights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt; September 8 and 9, 2021, 6:00-9:00am PST &lt;span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Short Course: An Introduction to R for Non-Programmers </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210907asa-short-course-an-introduction-to-r-for-non-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210907asa-short-course-an-introduction-to-r-for-non-programmers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;This will be a three-part webinar presentation from 8-10am PST on September 7th, 8th, and 9th. ASA members: $85; non-members: $135 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outline:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Day 1: 9/7/21: 11 AM EST&lt;br&gt;
Hour 1: R is a Big Fancy Calculator - Topics include vectors, matrices, and math operations.&lt;br&gt;
Hour 2: Computing Things Quickly - Topics include functions and computing linear regression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 2: 9/8/21: 11 AM EST&lt;br&gt;
Hour 1: Dealing with Data - Topics include objects, object types, and data frames.&lt;br&gt;
Hour 2: Plotting Data Part 1 - Topics include scatterplots, color, and titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 3: 9/10/21: 11 AM EST&lt;br&gt;
Hour 1: Plotting Data Part 2 - Topics include histograms and combining plots.&lt;br&gt;
Hour 2: R Packages for Visualization, Discussion, and Questions - Topics include R packages and other resources available. This time will also be allotted for specific questions from the participants. If there is extra time, additional topics such as ggplot2 may be introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
By the end of the course, participants will have been introduced to introductory R programming. The material presented will provide the foundations to understand more complicated R functionalities. The material provides the basic knowledge to understand programming at a more general level with the use of text editors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content and Instructional Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The course will have slides for the content. However, many hands on examples are done throughout the course. Generally speaking, each hour will end with an example which summarizes the content for that hour. Participants will have an opportunity to work together to solve the example. The hour ends with presenting a solution to the example provided.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Designs for Optimal Dose Determination in I-O and Cell Therapy</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210903adaptive-designs-for-optimal-dose-determination-in-i-o-and-cell-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210903adaptive-designs-for-optimal-dose-determination-in-i-o-and-cell-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is part of the Fifth Boston Pharmaceutical Symposium.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Data Science is Transforming Healthcare </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210902how-data-science-is-transforming-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210902how-data-science-is-transforming-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Takeaways:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand what is the current state of healthcare and summarize the main barriers that are slowing down its data transformation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify the main verticals of value data transformation can provide the healthcare sector&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand the various data science use cases underpinning scalable data transformation in healthcare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing the Development of Pediatric Therapeutics (Adept 7) Complex Innovative Trial Design</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210901advancing-the-development-of-pediatric-therapeutics-adept-7-complex-innovative-trial-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210901advancing-the-development-of-pediatric-therapeutics-adept-7-complex-innovative-trial-design/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purdue University Distinguished Theme Seminar Series 2021 on Causal Inference</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210827purdue-university-distinguished-theme-seminar-series-2021-on-causal-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 07:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210827purdue-university-distinguished-theme-seminar-series-2021-on-causal-inference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;A seminar series from 7:30 to 8:30 am PST on Aug 27th, Sep 3rd, 10th, 17th, and 24th&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 27, Introductory Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Associate Professor Arman Sabbaghi - Department of Statistics, Purdue University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 3, Clutter-Free Causal Inference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Professor Donald B. Rubin - Temple, Tsinghua, and Harvard Universities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 10, Single World Intervention Graphs (SWIGs): A Unification of the Graphical and Counterfactual Approaches to Causality with Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Professor James M. Robins - Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 17, What is Causal Inference? - A Logical Perspective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Professor Judea Pearl, Samueli School of Engineering, University of California-Los Angeles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 17, Causal Inference and Data Fusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Professor Elias Bareinboim, Department of Computer Science, Columbia University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 24, Statistical Learning: Causal-oriented and Robust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Professor Peter Bühlmann, Department of Mathematics, ETH Zürich&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics in Pharmaceuticals 2021 (SIP 2021)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210827statistics-in-pharmaceuticals-2021-sip-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210827statistics-in-pharmaceuticals-2021-sip-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBSW 2021 August Meetup: Genetic-Driven Drug Target Discovery </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210826bbsw-2021-august-meetup-genetic-driven-drug-target-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210826bbsw-2021-august-meetup-genetic-driven-drug-target-discovery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The discussion will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intro on genetic-driven drug target discovery and development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenges and opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Scientists’ contributions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Webinar: Advanced R Markdown &#43; RStudio Connect</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210826rstudio-webinar-advanced-r-markdown-rstudio-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210826rstudio-webinar-advanced-r-markdown-rstudio-connect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R Markdown is an incredible tool for being a more effective data scientist. It lets you share insights in ways that delight end users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, Tom Mock will teach you some advanced tips that will let you get the most out of R Markdown. Additionally, RStudio Connect will be highlighted, specifically how it works wonderfully with tools like R Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA SLDS Webinar: Variable Selection and Architecture Search for Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210824asa-slds-webinar-variable-selection-and-architecture-search-for-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210824asa-slds-webinar-variable-selection-and-architecture-search-for-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep learning has accomplished unprecedented performance accuracies in settings with big data and large computational resources. In this talk, we explore whether deep learning can be successful in smaller-scale settings, even those where the number of variables far exceeds the number of observations. We show that adding a sparse group lasso penalty to the training loss induces variable selection and drastically improves prediction accuracy. We then introduce skip-connections, which allow us to perform variable selection and architecture search simultaneously. The resulting training procedure only requires tuning two hyper-parameters, making deep learning practical even in settings with limited data or computational resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dahshu Webinar: In Search of Effective and Reproducible Clinical Imaging Biomarkers for Population Health and Oncology Applications of Screening, Diagnosis and Prognosis</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210820in-search-of-effective-and-reproducible-clinical-imaging-biomarkers-for-population-health-and-oncology-applications-of-screening-diagnosis-and-prognosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210820in-search-of-effective-and-reproducible-clinical-imaging-biomarkers-for-population-health-and-oncology-applications-of-screening-diagnosis-and-prognosis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk describes a roadmap on three key problems in pancreatic cancer imaging solution: early screening, precision differential diagnosis, and deep prognosis on patient survival prediction. (1) Based on a new self-learning framework, we train the pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) segmentation model using a larger quantity of patients (≈1,000, four institutions), with a mix of annotated/unannotated venous or multi-phase CT images. Pseudo annotations are generated by combining two teacher models with different PDAC segmentation specialties on unannotated images, and can be further refined by a teaching assistant model that identifies associated vessels around the pancreas. Our approach makes it technically feasible for robust large-scale PDAC screening from multi-institutional multi-phase partially-annotated CT scans. (2) We propose a holistic segmentation-mesh classification network (SMCN) to provide patient-level diagnosis, by fully utilizing the geometry and location information. SMCN learns the pancreas and mass segmentation task and builds an anatomical correspondence-aware organ mesh model by progressively deforming a pancreas prototype on the raw segmentation mask. Our results are comparable to a multimodality clinical test that combines clinical, imaging, and molecular testing for clinical management of patients with cysts. (3) Accurate preoperative prognosis of resectable PDACs for personalized treatment is highly desired in clinical practice. We present a novel deep neural network for the survival prediction of resectable PDAC patients, 3D Contrast-Enhanced Convolutional Long Short-Term Memory network (CE-ConvLSTM), to derive the tumor attenuation signatures from CE-CT imaging studies. Our framework can significantly improve the prediction performances upon existing state-of-the-art survival analysis methods. This deep tumor signature has evidently added values (as a predictive biomarker) to be combined with the existing clinical staging system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Model Averaging of Longitudinal Dose-Response Models</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210820bayesian-model-averaging-of-longitudinal-dose-response-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210820bayesian-model-averaging-of-longitudinal-dose-response-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt; &lt;em&gt;DIA Bayesian Scientific Working Group (BSWG) KOL lecture series&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selecting a clinically beneficial and safe dose (or doses) is one of the most difficult and consequential decisions in the drug development process.  Dose justification often relies on dose-response modeling, but parametric assumptions must be made a priori, often with little information, potentially leading to a situation where the chosen model does not fit the data well.  This is particularly problematic in longitudinal dose-response models, where additional parametric assumptions must be made on the longitudinal trajectory of each dose.  This presentation proposes a class of longitudinal dose-response models to be used in the Bayesian model averaging paradigm which can improve trial operating characteristics while maintaining flexibility a priori.  The benefits and trade-offs of the proposed method are demonstrated through a simulation study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIA IDSWG KOL Webinar: A Staged Phase 2b/2c Trial Design to Accelerate pan-TB Drug Regimen Development</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210813dia-idswg-kol-webinar-a-staged-phase-2b-2c-trial-design-to-accelerate-pan-tb-drug-regimen-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210813dia-idswg-kol-webinar-a-staged-phase-2b-2c-trial-design-to-accelerate-pan-tb-drug-regimen-development/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Webinar: Practical Advice for R in Production, Part 2: How? </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210812rstudio-webinar-practical-advice-for-r-in-production-part-2-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210812rstudio-webinar-practical-advice-for-r-in-production-part-2-how/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This webinar will be a hands-on workshop where you will learn best practices for securely putting R in production in a way that your IT team would approve of. This includes administering RStudio products, version control with Git, CI/CD pipelines, and even working in containerized environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Apps from Concept to Production </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210810shiny-apps-from-concept-to-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210810shiny-apps-from-concept-to-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shepherding your Shiny App from Proof of Concept to Production:&lt;/strong&gt; Marcin Dubel will present Appsilon&amp;rsquo;s preferred workflow for creating production quality Shiny apps. He&amp;rsquo;ll touch on key topics in the app development process that lead to apps which users enjoy and developers find easy to maintain and extend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve Your Code - Best Practices for Durable Code:&lt;/strong&gt; Anna Skrzydło discusses code maintenance, and the strategies you can employ to create enduring code. Avoid future delays and growing pains for your Shiny app by using better coding practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scaling &amp;amp; Infrastructure - Why is My Shiny App Slow?:&lt;/strong&gt; Pedro Silva will explore scaling and infrastructure issues common when deploying large scale Shiny apps, and how to overcome them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI/UX in Shiny Apps and Live Coding Session (shiny.fluent and shiny.react):&lt;/strong&gt; Kamil Żyła will demonstrate how to use shiny.fluent to build beautiful Shiny apps with Microsoft’s Fluent UI, and explain how to integrate React and Shiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head-to-Head Comparisons Using Real World Data</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210809head-to-head-comparisons-using-real-world-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210809head-to-head-comparisons-using-real-world-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cytel Webinar Series on August 9, 16, 23, 26 &amp;amp; 31. Replays are available.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speakers will present:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Webinar 1: The Time for Causal Inference is Now &lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=3335412&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=7EE42AA652D3E9E4A5E98E388D759A9B&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Replay Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce the concept of head to head comparisons using real world data and present case studies of the approach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outline the plan of pilot investigations in oncology and cardiovascular disease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Webinar 2: Design and data source considerations from pilot investigations in CVD &lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3335430/D5F8722158B3521E9D3B04B208CFC30D?mode=login&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Replay Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss the data requirements and the data source to be used in the pilot investigation with the focus on how to assess if the data is sufficient for the purposes of trial emulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Webinar 3: Study Design Considerations and an update on the pilot investigation in Cancer &lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3335449/851418F9D50BAE89FDF5831BAB74490A?mode=login&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Replay Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide an overview of challenges posed by the design of the ongoing pilot project in which we are leveraging real-world data to explicitly emulate a target trial comparing the efficacy of three different systemic therapies used to treat pancreatic cancer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Webinar 4: Practical Applications &lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3335457/9A80F86C4B23DDB0DD861A27FA09B420?mode=login&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;[Replay Link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss how Head to Head comparisons using real world data helps:
Generate efficacy or safety evidence for conditional regulatory approval or post-market assessment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a comparison when network meta analysis is not possible.
Expand the scope of a randomized trial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Webinar 5: Target trial emulation using real-world data: head-to-head comparison of antihyperglycemic therapies for type 2 diabetes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss when a randomized trial to compare effectiveness of healthcare interventions can be emulated using real-world data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The target trial framework, which couples causal inference methods to an explicit causal question posed in the form of a protocol for a randomized trial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How this approach helps to avoid common methodological pitfalls encountered in naïve analyses of observational data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Joint Statistical Meetings (JSM)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210807jsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210807jsm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration open: May 17; Early registration Deadline: June 15&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Traveling Course: Introduction to Data Science,  Machine Learning and Deep Learning (in R and Python)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210806asa-traveling-course-introduction-to-data-science-machine-learning-and-deep-learning-in-r-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210806asa-traveling-course-introduction-to-data-science-machine-learning-and-deep-learning-in-r-and-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: $35&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This short course will provide an overview of using R and Python for some of the most popular machine learning and deep learning models in real-world data science applications in the cloud environment. The sessions will step through the basic theoretical concepts behind those models and mainly focus on applications. Students will learn the motivation and use cases of these models through hands-on exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main topics of the course include: big data cloud environment, tree-based models, regularization methods, feedforward neural network, convolutional neural network, and recurrent neural network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course syllabus, program, and materials are available on the website &lt;a href=&#34;https://course2021.scientistcafe.com/&#34;&gt;https://course2021.scientistcafe.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bayesian phase I/II platform design for co-developing drug combination therapies for multiple indications</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210805a-bayesian-phase-i-ii-platform-design-for-co-developing-drug-combination-therapies-for-multiple-indications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210805a-bayesian-phase-i-ii-platform-design-for-co-developing-drug-combination-therapies-for-multiple-indications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is increasingly common to combine a new targeted or immunotherapy agent with the cancer-specific standard of care to treat different types of cancers. We propose a master-protocol-based, Bayesian phase I/II platform design to co-develop combination (BPCC) therapies in multiple cancers. Under the BPCC design, only a single master protocol is needed, and the drug is evaluated in different cancers in a concurrent or staggered fashion. For each cancer, we jointly model dose-toxicity and -efficacy relationships and employ Bayesian hierarchical models to borrow information across them for more efficient cancer-specific decision making. To account for the characteristic of targeted or immunotherapy agents that their efficacy may not monotonically increase with the dose, and often plateau at high doses, we use the utility to quantify the risk-benefit tradeoff of the treatment. At each interim, we update the toxicity and efficacy model, as well as the estimate of the utility, based on the observed data across cancers to inform the cancer-specific decision of dose escalation and de-escalation and identify the optimal biological dose for each cancer. Simulation study shows that the BPCC design has desirable operating characteristics, and that it provides an efficient approach to accelerate the development of combination therapies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying Operations Research Methods to Trial Design Selection</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210804applying-operations-research-methods-to-trial-design-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210804applying-operations-research-methods-to-trial-design-selection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nitin will show that Pareto Optimality, a simple and intuitive concept for partial ordering, is very effective in sifting through results of a large number of trial design simulations to identify a set of designs that collectively dominate all other designs for the three criteria of power, cost and duration in an oncology Ph3 trial design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying Brain Tumor Types by MRI Scans with Convolutional Neural Network</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210729classifying-brain-tumor-types-by-mri-scans-with-convolutional-neural-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210729classifying-brain-tumor-types-by-mri-scans-with-convolutional-neural-network/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMA Webinar: How Sponsor Organisations can Prepare for Clinical Trials Information System (CTIS)?</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210729ema-webinar-how-sponsor-organisations-can-prepare-for-clinical-trials-information-system-ctis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210729ema-webinar-how-sponsor-organisations-can-prepare-for-clinical-trials-information-system-ctis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clinical Trials Information System (CTIS) will act as the single entry point for clinical trials authorisation and supervision in the EEA. CTIS was created as part of the EU Clinical Trials Regulation (Regulation (EU) No 536/2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This EMA hosted webinar is open to all sponsor organisations, including pharmaceutical companies, contract research organisations, small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) and academic organisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics presented during the webinar include how sponsor organisations can prepare for CTIS, how Member States aim to support sponsor preparedness and adoption of CTIS, the role of the Clinical Trial Regulation and how sponsors can best make use of EMA’s CTIS training materials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reusable, Reproducible, Useful Computational Science in Python</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210728reusable-reproducible-useful-computational-science-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210728reusable-reproducible-useful-computational-science-in-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will cover organization of Python code, packaging with setuptools, installing code in development mode with pip, unit testing with unittest/pytest, linting with black, code quality assurance with flake8, documentation with Sphinx, automation with Tox, continuous integration with GitHub Actions, documentation hosting with ReadTheDocs, implementation of command line interfaces using Click, versioning with bumpversion, archiving on Zenodo, and ultimately, deployment to PyPI. This tutorial will be appropriate for Python programmers of all skill levels and for projects of all sizes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring Functions: A New Approach to Trial Design Optimization</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210728scoring-functions-a-new-approach-to-trial-design-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210728scoring-functions-a-new-approach-to-trial-design-optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The presentation describes a logical scoring algorithm, as implemented in the new clinical trial simulation software Solara and illustrates its use in facilitating the selection of an optimal study design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SFASA Student Travel Award Presentations </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210723sfasa-student-travel-award-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210723sfasa-student-travel-award-presentations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation Titles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swarnadip Ghosh (Stanford):&lt;/strong&gt;
Scalable Logistic Regression with Crossed Random Effects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rocky Aikens (Stanford):&lt;/strong&gt;
Assignment-Control Plots: A Visual Companion for Causal
Inference Study Design&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brian Neal (San Francisco State)&lt;/strong&gt;
An Adaptive Multivariate Kernel-Based Test for Association with
Multiple Quantitative Traits in High-Dimensional Data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Kluger (Stanford)&lt;/strong&gt;
The Benjamini-Hochberg False Discovery Exceedance under
Dependence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hung Tong (San Jose State)&lt;/strong&gt;
Clustering and Directional Outlier Detection with Missing
Information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suyash Gupta (Stanford)&lt;/strong&gt;
The s-value: Evaluating Stability with Respect to Distributional
Shifts&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding hypothetical strategies and defining the clinical question of interest</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210723understanding-hypothetical-strategies-and-defining-the-clinical-question-of-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210723understanding-hypothetical-strategies-and-defining-the-clinical-question-of-interest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More and more clinical trials have started adopting the estimand framework in protocols after the release of the ICH E9(R1) &amp;ldquo;Addendum on Estimands and Sensitivity Analysis in Clinical Trials&amp;rdquo;.  However, there is currently still a lack of clarity on the role of hypothetical strategies. The addendum recognizes that &amp;ldquo;when using the hypothetical strategy, some conditions are likely to be more acceptable for regulatory decision making than others&amp;rdquo;. However, it is still unclear as to what constitutes &amp;ldquo;acceptable hypothetical conditions&amp;rdquo; which could lead to an interpretable treatment effect.  Therefore, it is of great interest to have a diverse group of experts take a deep dive into this topic and help shed light on considerations of hypothetical strategies relevant to the clinical question of interest.  In this webinar, we will have speakers from regulatory agencies and industry to share their perspectives on this interesting topic and also participate in a panel-discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related publications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mats J. Stensrud, Jessica G. Young, Vanessa Didelez, James M. Robins &amp;amp; Miguel A. Hernán (2020) &lt;strong&gt;Separable Effects for Causal Inference in the Presence of Competing Events&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Journal of the American Statistical Association&lt;/em&gt;, DOI: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01621459.2020.1765783&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1080/01621459.2020.1765783&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hege Michiels, Cristina Sotto, An Vandebosch, Stijn Vansteelandt (2021) &lt;strong&gt;A novel estimand to adjust for rescue treatment in randomized clinical trials&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Statistics In Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, DOI: &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/sim.8901&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1002/sim.8901&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elena Polverejan &amp;amp; Vladimir Dragalin (2020) &lt;strong&gt;Aligning Treatment Policy Estimands and Estimators—A Simulation Study in Alzheimer’s Disease&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Statistics in Biopharmaceutical Research&lt;/em&gt;, 12:2, 142-154, DOI: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19466315.2019.1689845&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1080/19466315.2019.1689845&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Promising Zone Designs for Return on Investment</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210721optimizing-promising-zone-designs-for-return-on-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210721optimizing-promising-zone-designs-for-return-on-investment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Constraint Promising Zone (CPZ) design, a new innovation on the promising zone design. The CPZ is a design that is easy to implement, and easy for all stakeholders to understand and accept. It is based on the intuitively plausible notion that any additional investment of sample size at an interim analysis should be contingent on a minimal acceptable return on the investment, expressed in terms of guaranteed conditional power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 SIAM (Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics) Annual Meeting (AN21)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202107192021-siam-society-for-industrial-and-applied-mathematics-annual-meeting-an21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202107192021-siam-society-for-industrial-and-applied-mathematics-annual-meeting-an21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: July 5, 2021; Member $175, Nonmember $315&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 UW Biostatistics Online Summer Institutes</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/202107072021-uw-biostatistics-online-summer-institutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/202107072021-uw-biostatistics-online-summer-institutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: Jun 18, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI Journal Club: The Use of External Controls in Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210706psi-journal-club-the-use-of-external-controls-in-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210706psi-journal-club-the-use-of-external-controls-in-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris Harbron (Roche):&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/pst.2120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The use of external controls: To what extent can it currently be recommended?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Authors: Hans Ulrich Burger, Christoph Gerlinger, Chris Harbron, Armin Koch, Martin Posch, Justine Rochon and Anja Schiel
Pharmaceutical Statistics. 20 21;1– 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Margaret Gamalo (Pfizer):&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/pst.1879&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Propensity score matched augmented controls in randomized clinical trials: A case study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Authors: Junjing Lin, Margaret Gamalo‐Siebers and Ram Tiwari
Pharmaceutical Statistics. 2018;17: 629–647&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of these published papers there will be a 20 minute presentation by the author followed by a 10 minute discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Papers will be made available to view prior to the meeting and presentation slides will be available a week before the JC. Journal subscribers can access papers at any time.  Audio recordings will be available shortly after the JC to download from the PSI website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meetings are open to both PSI and non-PSI members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>useR! 2021</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210705user-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210705user-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration Deadline: June 25, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data for AI - Patient Safety, Laboratory Interoperability, and SHIELD </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210701data-for-ai-patient-safety-laboratory-interoperability-and-shield/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 08:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210701data-for-ai-patient-safety-laboratory-interoperability-and-shield/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Laboratory data is critical to patient safety and essential for a wide variety of uses from public health surveillance to research.  Despite the fact that laboratory data has been digitalized for decades, aggregation is difficult because of problems with semantic interoperability. SHIELD (Systemic Harmonization and Interoperability Enhancement for Lab Data) is a public-private partner with over 70 partners devoted to establishing a national system for “describing the same test the same way, every time.”  Gregory will set out current barriers to laboratory interoperability and the SHIELD Strategic Planning Effort that is currently underway.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDDI Webinar: Estimands in Oncology – Are We Censoring for the Right Reason?</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210701iddi-webinar-estimands-in-oncology-are-we-censoring-for-the-right-reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210701iddi-webinar-estimands-in-oncology-are-we-censoring-for-the-right-reason/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The estimands framework, introduced in the ICH E9 (R1) guideline, facilitates discussions during design of clinical trials to ensure alignment between the key scientific question of interest, analysis and interpretation. In the context of oncology solid tumor randomized studies, commonly performed analyses of progression-free survival (PFS) will be reviewed, with a critical eye on which question they address, using the estimands terminology. The estimands framework will not necessarily change common analysis methods within oncology, but will describe in detail how intercurrent events (such as subsequent therapy) will be taken into account and increase transparency on the treatment effect being evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Literacy in Health Research in the Age of Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210629statistical-literacy-in-health-research-in-the-age-of-machine-learning-and-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 02:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210629statistical-literacy-in-health-research-in-the-age-of-machine-learning-and-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years there has been rapid growth in the use of machine learning (ML) and artificial intelligence (AI) to analyse the vast amounts of data being generated in all areas of society. ML and AI approaches are increasingly being employed in health research, and sometimes are even explicitly called for by funders. While ML and AI may offer advantages over traditional statistical methods for certain tasks, they tend to use complex algorithms and are often regarded as analytical “black boxes”. Hence these novel methods pose new challenges of statistical literacy for producers and consumers of health research. Such challenges may be compounded by an underlying lack of communication and understanding between the statistics and ML/AI communities. Are statisticians slow to embrace the potential of ML and AI methods, and guilty of trying to protect their role in collaborative research in the face of competition from other fields? Or are they rightly concerned about the fundamentals of robust, reproducible and interpretable research being forgotten in the clamour for applying fashionable methods understood by few? This meeting will explore issues in statistical literacy raised by the growth of ML and AI in health research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Cure Models - Methods, Applications, and Implementation</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210629isi-short-course-cure-models-methods-applications-and-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210629isi-short-course-cure-models-methods-applications-and-implementation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course will provide a comprehensive introduction to cure models, including basics of the cure models as well as many recent developments related to the methodological issues and software implementations of cure models for right-censored time-to-event data subject to non-informative censoring. The course will feature real-world examples from clinical trials and population-based studies and a detailed introduction to R packages, SAS macros, and WinBUGS programs to fit some cure models. Applications of cure models in other disciplines will be discussed. This course will be useful for statistical researchers and graduate students, and practitioners in other disciplines to have a thorough review of modern cure model methodology and to seek appropriate cure models in applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Precision Medicine - A Statistical Perspective on Estimating the Best Treatment Strategy </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210628isi-short-course-precision-medicine-a-statistical-perspective-on-estimating-the-best-treatment-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210628isi-short-course-precision-medicine-a-statistical-perspective-on-estimating-the-best-treatment-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidence-based medicine relies on using data to provide recommendations for effective treatment or prevention decisions. However, in many settings, effects may be heterogeneous across individuals, and within individuals over time. Healthcare providers are faced with the daunting task of making sequential therapeutic decisions having seen few patients with a given clinical history. Adaptive treatment strategies (ATS) operationalize the sequential decision-making process in the precision medicine paradigm, offering statisticians principled estimation tools that can be used to incorporate patient’s characteristics into a clinical decision-making framework so as to adapt the type, dosage or timing of intervention according to patients’ evolving needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yale Summer Course in Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210628yale-summer-course-in-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210628yale-summer-course-in-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Register by June 27; Registration fee: $450&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants will gain knowledge of the key components of clinical trials including but not limited to trial phase and design, randomization schemes, selection of outcome and appropriate statistical analysis including sample size and power considerations, ethics, and regulatory affairs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIA 2021 Global Annual Meeting</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210627dia-2021-global-annual-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210627dia-2021-global-annual-meeting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dahshu Webinar: The New FIRRMA Regulations and Their Impact on Biotechnology and Life Science Industries</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210625the-new-firrma-regulations-and-their-impact-on-biotechnology-and-life-science-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210625the-new-firrma-regulations-and-their-impact-on-biotechnology-and-life-science-industries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, new FIRRMA final regulations have been published to further clarify the definition of “sensitive personal data” which was previously left to be developed by CFIUS. The final regulations clarify the provision on genetic testing in two ways: 1) by focusing the definition on genetic tests and 2) by limiting the coverage of the rule to identifiable data. The final regulations implement CFIUS’s jurisdiction over 11 specific categories of sensitive personal data, including health, biometric, and genetic data. CFIUS now have expanded jurisdiction over U.S. companies that collect or maintain records relating to a U.S. citizen&amp;rsquo;s genetic information, such as a genetic test or individual or family history, which biotechnology or life sciences companies might collect and could lead to CFIUS review. CFIUS will closely monitor biotechnology and life sciences companies that operate in these relevant sectors and identify transactions in which a foreign investment raises a national security concern.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airborne Transmission of the Virus SARS-CoV-2</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210624airborne-transmission-of-the-virus-sars-cov-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210624airborne-transmission-of-the-virus-sars-cov-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists realized soon after the detection of the SARS-CoV-2 virus that airborne transmission, which is by inhalation of small airborne virus laden particles (often called aerosols), generated during human respiratory activities was the main mode of the spread of the infection. The prevailing theory of infection transmission, that it was via the direct contact with much bigger particles (often called droplets), leading to distancing at 6 feet arose from work by Flugge in 1897 and later theory by Well-Riley. Immediately upon the detection of the virus, Dr. Morawska and other aerosol experts recognized that the virus may be transmitted by much smaller particles than recognized by Flugge, over longer distances (as far as 60 feet and further) and lingering longer in the air. This is a major change in understanding and public health implications of virus transmission. WHO guidance was modified to reflect the possibility of virus transmission over longer distances and lingering longer in the air. It is expected that this will lead to changes in public health policy regarding mask usage, and ventilation of buildings and other areas people may gather.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survival Outcome Data with High Dimensional Predictors: Methods and Applications</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210624survival-outcome-data-with-high-dimensional-predictors-methods-and-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210624survival-outcome-data-with-high-dimensional-predictors-methods-and-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ASA members: $40; non-members: $65&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the era of precision medicine, survival outcome data with high-throughput covariates and predictors are often collected. These high dimensional data defy classical survival regression models, which are either infeasible to fit or likely to incur low predictability because of overfitting. This short course will introduce various cutting-edge methods that handle survival outcome data with high dimensional predictors. I will cover statistical principles and concepts behind the methods, and will also discuss their applications to the real medical examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time permitting, I intend to cover the following topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival analysis overview: basic concepts and models, e.g. Cox, Accelerated Failure Time (AFT), and Censored Quantile Regression (CQR) Models;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival models with high dimensional predictors (p&amp;gt;n): Regularized methods and Dantzig selector;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival analysis with ultra-high dimensional predictors (p&amp;raquo;n): Screening Methods, e.g, Principled sure independent screening (PSIS), Conditional screening, IPOD, Forward selection, etc;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inference for survival models with high dimensional predictors (p&amp;gt;n).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience only needs to have some basic knowledge of regression analysis and survival analysis. The relevant papers and software for this short course can be found in: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~yili/resindex.html&#34;&gt;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~yili/resindex.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISSI Online Seminar Series: Confident Directional Selective Inference, from Multiple Comparisons with the Best to Precision Medicine</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210624issi-online-seminar-series-confident-directional-selective-inference-from-multiple-comparisons-with-the-best-to-precision-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 08:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210624issi-online-seminar-series-confident-directional-selective-inference-from-multiple-comparisons-with-the-best-to-precision-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MCB (multiple comparisons with the best, 1981, 1984), comparing treatments to the best without knowing which one is the best, can be considered an early example of selective inference. With the thinking that &amp;ldquo;there is only one true best&amp;rdquo;, the relevance of MCB to this presentation is it led to the Partitioning Principle, which is essential for deriving confidence sets for stepwise tests. Inference based on confidence sets control the directional error rate, inference based on tests of equalities may not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FDA gave Accelerated Approval to Aduhelm^{TM} (aducanumab) for Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Disease (AD) on 8 June 2021, based on its reduction of beta-amyloid plaque (a surrogate biomarker endpoint). When clinical efficacy of a treatment for the overall population is not shown, genome-wide association studies (GWAS) are often used to discover SNPs that might predict efficacy in subgroups. In the process of working on GWAS with real data, we came to realization that, if one causal SNP makes its zero-null hypothesis false, then all other zero-null hypotheses are statistically false as well. While the majority of no-association null hypotheses might well be true biologically, statistically they are false (if one is false) in GWAS. I will indeed illustrate this with a causal SNP for the ApoE gene which is involved in the clearance of beta-amyloid plaque in AD. We suggest our confidence interval CE4 approach instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targeted therapies such as OPDIVO and TECENTRIQ naturally have patient subgroups, already defined by the extent to which the drug target is present or absent in them, subgroups that may derive differential efficacy. An additional danger of testing equality nulls in the presence of subgroups is that the illusory logical relationships among efficacy in subgroups and their mixtures created by exact quality nulls leads to too drastic a stepwise multiplicity reduction, resulting in inflated directional error rates, as I will explain. Instead, Partition Tests, which would be called Confident Direction methods in the language of Tukey, might be safer to use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Communicating Health Data - The COVID-19 Experience</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210624isi-short-course-communicating-health-data-the-covid-19-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210624isi-short-course-communicating-health-data-the-covid-19-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two-day course on June 24 and July 1; Registration fee: €100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course  is an  introduction to effectively communicating, to general audiences,  complex statistical modelling and estimation related to Covid-19 data.  The instruction will be at a beginner level. The 6 hours course is split in 2 days and will cover “Basics of effective communication to a general audience” on day 1  and  “Introduction to estimation and  modelling of covid-19 data: prevalence, incidence, epi-curves, transmissibility and reproduction numbers” on day 2.  Classes  will include  stop&amp;amp;go discussion upon broadcasting of video-recorded interviews with experts and professionals  in media monitoring and communication of health data. A student assignment is scheduled at the end of day 1 lessons with feedback on day 2 for shared learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA SLDS Webinar: Calibrating Machine Learning Prediction Models</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210623asa-slds-webinar-calibrating-machine-learning-prediction-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210623asa-slds-webinar-calibrating-machine-learning-prediction-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Statistical prediction models for estimating probabilities have gained popularity in applied research. An adaptation to a new population can be achieved by calibrating the model to the characteristics of the target population, and numerous calibration techniques exist. In this presentation, I will provide a review of the different calibration approaches used in classical statistics and in machine learning for two-class probability estimation. I will present results of a comprehensive analysis using both simulated and real data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Statistics in Epidemiology Webinar: Pursuit of COVID Vaccine Approval Based on an Immune Marker Surrogate Endpoint</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210622asa-statistics-in-epidemiology-webinar-pursuit-of-covid-vaccine-approval-based-on-an-immune-marker-surrogate-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210622asa-statistics-in-epidemiology-webinar-pursuit-of-covid-vaccine-approval-based-on-an-immune-marker-surrogate-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An objective of randomized, placebo-controlled efficacy trials of COVID-19 vaccines is to develop evidence for whether and how antibody biomarkers can be appropriately used as surrogate endpoints for accelerating approval and increasing distribution of effective vaccines. I will summarize the COVID-19 Prevention Trial Network’s harmonized statistical analysis plan for generating this evidence based on the analysis of several phase 3 trials. The statistical methods include causal inference methods within the principal stratification, controlled effects, stochastic interventional effects, and mediation frameworks. The webinar seeks to describe the distinct contributions of the different methods and a strategy for synthesizing the set of results. The webinar also considers how the analyses can account for the genetic sequences of the SARS-CoV-2 viruses, which may impact vaccine efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytel Webinar: Using Robust Bayesian Priors to Borrow Information from Historical Adult Trials for a Clinical Trial in Pediatric Multiple Sclerosis</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210622cytel-webinar-using-robust-bayesian-priors-to-borrow-information-from-historical-adult-trials-for-a-clinical-trial-in-pediatric-multiple-sclerosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210622cytel-webinar-using-robust-bayesian-priors-to-borrow-information-from-historical-adult-trials-for-a-clinical-trial-in-pediatric-multiple-sclerosis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating R into your Clinical Legacy Workflows</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210622incorporating-r-into-your-clinical-legacy-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210622incorporating-r-into-your-clinical-legacy-workflows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What you will learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can two enterprise organizations collaborate on open source pharma projects?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the organizational changes required for adopting open source tooling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can open source tools augment and improve propriety tooling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FDA Sentinel Webinar: Measure What You Treasure - The Challenges and Opportunities of Collecting Real World Endpoints </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210622fda-sentinel-webinar-measure-what-you-treasure-the-challenges-and-opportunities-of-collecting-real-world-endpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210622fda-sentinel-webinar-measure-what-you-treasure-the-challenges-and-opportunities-of-collecting-real-world-endpoints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The high quality capture of real world endpoints is vitally important to the growing use, acceptance, and utility of real world data. This presentation will discuss the opportunities, challenges, and potential remedies to this complex problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Nonclinical Biostatistics Conference</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202106212021-nonclinical-biostatistics-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202106212021-nonclinical-biostatistics-conference/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI 2021 Online Conference</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210621psi-2021-online-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210621psi-2021-online-conference/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Detection of Potential Safety Signal from Blinded Clinical Trial Data</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210618bayesian-detection-of-potential-safety-signal-from-blinded-clinical-trial-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210618bayesian-detection-of-potential-safety-signal-from-blinded-clinical-trial-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The DIA Bayesian Scientific Working Group (BSWG) KOL lecture series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensuring patients&#39; safety in clinical trials is extremely important and is a major responsibility of the sponsors of the clinical trials. Regulatory authorities also encourage aggregate review of safety from ongoing clinical trials, specifically to identify potential risks of adverse events of special interest. Sponsors may decide that a blinded review of safety data can meet these needs while also ensuring clinical trial integrity. A Bayesian methodological framework has been developed that leverages historical data of the background rates of events of interest to monitor and detect potential safety signals using blinded data from ongoing clinical trials. This new method is a two‐step Bayesian evaluation of potential safety signals composed of a screening analysis followed by a sensitivity analysis. The blinded safety teams can use these steps to make an informed decision if any events of interest should be escalated for unblinded review.&lt;br&gt;
To ease implementation and operationalization of the method, an R package called BDRIBS (Bayesian Detection of potential Risk using Inference on Blinded Safety data) and an associated R-Shiny application have been developed. The R-package and the R-Shiny tool are both publicly available.&lt;br&gt;
The first part of the presentation will focus on the methodological development and the second part will feature the BDRIBS R-Shiny application to illustrate visualization and assessment of the events of interest to help in exploration of various scenarios and sensitivity analyses in real‐time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Recent Developments in Machine Learning for Addressing Multiple Outcomes in Data Driven Decision Support </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210618some-recent-developments-in-machine-learning-for-addressing-multiple-outcomes-in-data-driven-decision-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210618some-recent-developments-in-machine-learning-for-addressing-multiple-outcomes-in-data-driven-decision-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mathematical Foundations of Data Science Webinar Series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this presentation, we will discuss some recent developments in machine learning based precision health for estimating dynamic treatment regimes which seek to balance two or more outcomes, such as, for example, balancing treatment efficacy against side effect burden. The first approach involves obtaining individual patient input on the relative priority of outcomes through preference instruments based on, for example, item response theory or discrete choice modeling. The second approach adapts inverse reinforcement learning to infer physician outcome priorities, allowing for the possibility of errors in decision making. Both approaches are illustrated with practical examples from mental health.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Bootstrap Methods and Permutation Tests</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210618isi-short-course-bootstrap-methods-and-permutation-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210618isi-short-course-bootstrap-methods-and-permutation-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We begin with a graphical approach to bootstrapping and permutation testing, illuminating basic statistical concepts of standard errors, confidence intervals, p-values and significance tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We consider a variety of statistics (mean, trimmed mean, regression, etc.), and a number of sampling situations (one-sample, two-sample, stratified, finite-population), stressing the common techniques that apply in these situations. We’ll look at applications from a variety of fields, including telecommunications, finance, and biopharm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These methods let us do confidence intervals and hypothesis tests when formulas are not available, so we can do better statistics, e.g. use robust methods like medians, trimmed means, or robust regression. They can help clients understand statistical variability. And some of the methods are more accurate than standard methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Webinar: Statistical Issues in Agent-Based Models for Risk Assessment </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210617asa-webinar-statistical-issues-in-agent-based-models-for-risk-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210617asa-webinar-statistical-issues-in-agent-based-models-for-risk-assessment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ASA members: $20; non-members: $35&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agent-based models (ABMs) are computational models used to simulate the actions and interactions of agents within a system. Usually, each agent has a relatively simple set of rules for how it responds to its environment and to other agents. These models are used to gain insight into the emergent behavior of complex systems with many agents, in which the emergent behavior depends upon the micro-level behavior of the individuals. ABMs are widely used in many fields, and this talk emphasizes the challenges that arise in the context various risk analyses (e.g., epidemics, invasive species, insurance). Relatively little work has been done on statistical theory for such models, this talk also points out some of those gaps and recent strategies to address them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytel Webinar: Hi3&#43;3 – A Model-Assisted Dose-Finding Design Borrowing Historical Data </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210617cytel-webinar-hi3-3-a-model-assisted-dose-finding-design-borrowing-historical-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210617cytel-webinar-hi3-3-a-model-assisted-dose-finding-design-borrowing-historical-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yuan Ji will discuss his recent publication, Hi3+3: A Model-Assisted Dose-Finding Design Borrowing Historical Data, in the webinar presentation. The purpose of the publication was based on a hybrid design that partly uses probability models and partly uses algorithmic rules for decision making. The aim is to improve the efficiency of the dose-finding trials in the presence of historical data, maintain safety for patients, and achieve a level of simplicity for practical applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Methods for Biomarker Discovery in Studies with Many Candidate Biomarkers but Limited Sample Size</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210616robust-methods-for-biomarker-discovery-in-studies-with-many-candidate-biomarkers-but-limited-sample-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 09:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210616robust-methods-for-biomarker-discovery-in-studies-with-many-candidate-biomarkers-but-limited-sample-size/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meeting ID: 999 5977 8908; Passcode: 129259&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington Statistical Society (WSS) Virtual Seminar&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REMAP-CAP: A Bayesian Approach to Learning and Treating COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210616remap-cap-a-bayesian-approach-to-learning-and-treating-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210616remap-cap-a-bayesian-approach-to-learning-and-treating-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related Publication:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nejm.org/doi/10.1056/NEJMoa2100433&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Interleukin-6 Receptor Antagonists in Critically Ill Patients with Covid-19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2770278&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Effect of Hydrocortisone on Mortality and Organ Support in Patients With Severe COVID-19, The REMAP-CAP COVID-19 Corticosteroid Domain Randomized Clinical Trial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Approaches for Addressing Missing Data in Cost-Effectiveness Analysis (alongside Randomised Controlled Trials) </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210616bayesian-approaches-for-addressing-missing-data-in-cost-effectiveness-analysis-alongside-randomised-controlled-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210616bayesian-approaches-for-addressing-missing-data-in-cost-effectiveness-analysis-alongside-randomised-controlled-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Health economics has become an increasingly important discipline in medical research. Bodies such as NICE provide guidance based on health economic evaluation. Much of recent research has focused on using advanced statistical decision theoretic approaches in health economic evaluation studies where the interest is in the analysis of a multivariate outcome comprising of clinical benefit and associated costs. Missing data on one or both outcomes is common in these studies. The complex structure of the relationships between the outcomes makes handling missing data more challenging in these studies. In this talk the issues related to missing data in health economic evaluation studies will be discussed and novel statistical models developed to handle missing data using a full Bayesian approach will be described, using as motivating example a pilot study conducted at UCL.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Data Science and Predictive Analytics</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210616isi-short-course-data-science-and-predictive-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210616isi-short-course-data-science-and-predictive-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The training will provide intermediate to advanced learners with a solid data science foundation to address challenges related to collecting, managing, processing, interrogating, analyzing and interpreting complex health and biomedical datasets using R. Participants will gain skills and acquire a tool-chest of methods, software tools, and protocols that can be applied to a broad spectrum of Big Data problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the mathematical algorithms, statistical computing methods, software tools, and health analytics, we will discuss a number of driving motivational problems. These will ground all the subsequent scientific discussions, data modeling, and computational approaches. The training will involve active-learning and integrate driving motivational challenges with mathematical foundations, computational statistics, and modern scientific inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on open-science principles, training will focus on effective, reliable, reproducible, and transformative data-driven discovery. Trainees will develop scientific intuition, computational skills, and data-wrangling abilities to tackle Big biomedical and advanced health data problems. The instructor will provide well-documented R-scripts and software recipes implementing atomic data-filters, as well as complex end-to-end predictive big data analytics solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Health Data - Too Important to be a Toy Example</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210615electronic-health-data-too-important-to-be-a-toy-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210615electronic-health-data-too-important-to-be-a-toy-example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Washington Statistical Society (WSS) Gertrude M. Cox Award Presentation&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytel Webinar: Bayesian Inference Using Poisson-Gamma Model Under Non-Proportional Hazards</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210615cytel-webinar-bayesian-inference-using-poisson-gamma-model-under-non-proportional-hazards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210615cytel-webinar-bayesian-inference-using-poisson-gamma-model-under-non-proportional-hazards/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Introduction to Machine Learning </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210615isi-short-course-introduction-to-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210615isi-short-course-introduction-to-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course describes nonparametric regression, including the additive model and its generalizations, also the LASSO, and LARS.  Then it proceeds to classification (SVMs, random forests, boosting). The Curse of Dimensionality is described in both contexts.  Bagging and stacking are covered. There is some coverage of cluster analysis, and some text analytics.  The emphasis is upon the strengths and weaknesses of the tools, and guidance on when a particular method should be used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 WNAR Virtual Meeting</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202106132021-wnar-virtual-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202106132021-wnar-virtual-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WNAR members: $50; IBS members: $50; Non-members: $150&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ENAR Webinar: Novel Applications of Real-world Data to Support Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210611enar-webinar-novel-applications-of-real-world-data-to-support-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210611enar-webinar-novel-applications-of-real-world-data-to-support-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENAR members: free; IBS members: $65; Non-members: $85&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real-world data (RWD) have played an increasingly important role in healthcare decisions, for example supporting the design, analysis, and contextualization of clinical trials. In this webinar, we invite panelists from industry with backgrounds in statistics, clinical trials, data science, epidemiology, and health outcomes research to discuss novel applications where RWD can be used to support clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discuss propensity-score based methods to leverage RWD as an external data source to augment single-arm clinical trials, enhanced extrapolation of long-term clinical trial survival outcomes using electronic health record (EHR)-derived RWD, and enrollment projection for a prospective pragmatic trial design that utilizes RWD. Finally, we tie the three topics together with a panel discussion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Clinical Trials for Personalized Medicine via Bayesian Adaptive Design (DACTPerM)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210611analyzing-clinical-trials-for-personalized-medicine-via-bayesian-adaptive-design-dactperm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210611analyzing-clinical-trials-for-personalized-medicine-via-bayesian-adaptive-design-dactperm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASEM Symposium: Data Collection and Integration to Enhance Public Health – Making Sense of a Patchwork of Data</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210610nasem-symposium-data-collection-and-integration-to-enhance-public-health-making-sense-of-a-patchwork-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210610nasem-symposium-data-collection-and-integration-to-enhance-public-health-making-sense-of-a-patchwork-of-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As policymakers and community leaders have worked to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic, it has become increasingly clear that statistics and data science can play a critical role in protecting public health and determining the best path forward. Moving from theory to practice presents challenges for working with a patchwork of data from many different sources across public and private sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers will discuss how their work in modeling, inference, predictive analysis, and machine learning has been applied to track the spread of COVID-19, drug use, air pollution, and human trafficking. Panelists will explore the strengths and weaknesses of available surveillance data and how to integrate and draw insight from multiple imperfect data sources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Vaccines/Treatment Trials, and Predictive Modeling</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210610covid-19-vaccines-treatment-trials-and-predictive-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210610covid-19-vaccines-treatment-trials-and-predictive-modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Day 2 on June 11, 06:00 - 08:30 PST,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://rutgers.webex.com/mw3300/mywebex/default.do?nomenu=true&amp;amp;siteurl=rutgers&amp;amp;service=6&amp;amp;rnd=0.91598952072901&amp;amp;main_url=https%3A%2F%2Frutgers.webex.com%2Fec3300%2Feventcenter%2Fevent%2FeventAction.do%3FtheAction%3Ddetail%26%26%26EMK%3D4832534b00000004ccfe17c46bed0464ec584839c2e9e63bee1abcffc3e5fc074828b0ccd1d8a813%26siteurl%3Drutgers%26confViewID%3D194838788450583441%26encryptTicket%3DSDJTSwAAAARC1c0o--SgmZ3tEVx2QxUCiA079yE_Che20yPxxVgUAQ2%26&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;register&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASA New Jersey Chapter and Princeton-Trenton Chapter Joint Spring Symposium Day 1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this year’s Spring Symposium, we will discuss efficient Covid-19 vaccine trial designs, rapid data collection and analysis techniques while assessing the impact of vaccines in bringing this pandemic under control. A panel will debate the determinants of a more robust public health policy to prevent future pandemics with potential to cause catastrophic damage in populations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biopharmaceutical Software Working Group</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210609biopharmaceutical-software-working-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210609biopharmaceutical-software-working-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Working Group is planning to solicit ideas for new software tools with biopharmaceutical applications, set up a network of testers and reviewers, and ultimately cultivate a community focused on the development of software tools for biopharmaceutical statisticians by biopharmaceutical statisticians.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BNP-ISBA</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210609bnp-isba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210609bnp-isba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Bayesian Nonparametric Section of the International Society for Bayesian Analysis&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA - International Society of Bayesian Analysis</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210609isba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210609isba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of the Section is to promote the research, application and dissemination of Bayesian methods and solutions for problems in Biostatistics and Pharmaceutical statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oncology estimand working group</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210609oncology-estimand-working-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210609oncology-estimand-working-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A cross-industry international working group&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontiers in Biostatistics Seminar: The Use of External Control Data for Predictions and Interim Analyses in Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210608frontiers-in-biostatistics-seminar-the-use-of-external-control-data-for-predictions-and-interim-analyses-in-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210608frontiers-in-biostatistics-seminar-the-use-of-external-control-data-for-predictions-and-interim-analyses-in-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytel Webinar: Leveraging External Control Data for Clinical Trials with Time-to-Event Endpoints</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210608cytel-webinar-leveraging-external-control-data-for-clinical-trials-with-time-to-event-endpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210608cytel-webinar-leveraging-external-control-data-for-clinical-trials-with-time-to-event-endpoints/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Penn State ICDS Biomedical AI and Data Science Seminar Series: AI Expeditions in Healthcare</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210608penn-state-icds-biomedical-ai-and-data-science-seminar-series-ai-expeditions-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210608penn-state-icds-biomedical-ai-and-data-science-seminar-series-ai-expeditions-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) has tremendous potential to improve prediction of health risks and health  outcomes. The Biomedical AI and Data Sciences seminar series aims to initiate a dialog between healthcare practitioners, clinical researchers, and AI and Data Science experts on strategies for realizing the promise and potential of AI in healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series kicks off on June 8 with several lightning talks from Penn State researchers, followed by discussions about the topics discussed, and next steps. In fall 2021, the series will continue and will feature prominent researchers within and beyond Penn State who are leading foundational and translational research on AI in healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHASTAR Life Science Summit (PLSS21)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210608phastar-life-science-summit-plss21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210608phastar-life-science-summit-plss21/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Statistical Theory of Deep Learning </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210607isi-short-course-statistical-theory-of-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210607isi-short-course-statistical-theory-of-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course outline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation: The present great success of Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical learning theory: Regression and Classification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theory behind Deep Learning:&lt;br&gt;
a. Introduction of Neural Networks&lt;br&gt;
b. Different network architectures and activation functions&lt;br&gt;
c. Approximation theory: Which function classes can be efficiently   approximated by DNNs?&lt;br&gt;
d. Generalization: Convergence rates of DNNs for different regression and classification problems. When are those networks able to circumvent the curse of dimensionality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limits and open questions of DNNs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Reshaping Challenging Data to Produce Insightful Graphs - A Quick Start to Using R Tidyverse Tools </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210604isi-short-course-reshaping-challenging-data-to-produce-insightful-graphs-a-quick-start-to-using-r-tidyverse-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210604isi-short-course-reshaping-challenging-data-to-produce-insightful-graphs-a-quick-start-to-using-r-tidyverse-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this short course, you will learn to read and reshape a dataset from the World Bank, filter observations and select variables to produce an analysis data set and finally to produce figures. Customizing, enhancing and annotating data visualizations follows. R software with be used with functions included the tidyverse suite of packages being highlighted (dplyr, tidyr and ggplot2 in particular).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Webinar: S, R, and Data Science</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210603asa-webinar-s-r-and-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210603asa-webinar-s-r-and-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ASA members: $20, non-members: $35&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses the history and characteristics of the R software. R began, 20-odd years ago, as the open source clone of the S software. So the story of R has to start with S and with its history. S came from the Statistics and Data Analysis Research group at AT&amp;amp;T Bell Labs. We&amp;rsquo;ll see that the design goal of S, and so of R, is to support studies in what we&amp;rsquo;d now call data science. The principles resulting from this goal are still central to computing for data science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI EIWG Webinar: Estimands in Oncology - How and Why (Session 2)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210602psi-eiwg-webinar-estimands-in-oncology-how-and-why-session-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210602psi-eiwg-webinar-estimands-in-oncology-how-and-why-session-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year on after the final ICH E9 estimands addendum was published, we bring estimands to life. Members of the Estimands in Oncology special interest group will describe how the estimand framework provides a common language to describe the diversity of patient journeys and why it is important to address the right question in clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be guided through a case study and interactively deepen the knowledge to gain hands-on experience in developing estimands. You will be introduced to the background and disease context of the case study, the concept of an estimand, and important clinical events (increased dropout rate and crossover therapy) that occurred in the trial and affected interpretation of the results. Using non-technical language and clear graphical presentation of the concepts, you will experience how the estimand framework provides a common language to describe the diversity of patient journeys and why it is important to address the right question in clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Symposium on Data Science &amp; Statistics (SDSS)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202106022021-symposium-on-data-science-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/202106022021-symposium-on-data-science-statistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration deadline: Apr 7, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDDI Seminar: Practice-Oriented Pragmatic Trials can Integrate Innovations More Rapidly in Evidence-Based Medicine</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210601iddi-seminar-practice-oriented-pragmatic-trials-can-integrate-innovations-more-rapidly-in-evidence-based-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210601iddi-seminar-practice-oriented-pragmatic-trials-can-integrate-innovations-more-rapidly-in-evidence-based-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Governments, their regulatory agencies and health technology assessment (HTA) bodies informing the healthcare payers have the ambition of providing patients with fast access to evidence-based innovations in healthcare. The historical split in objectives and responsibilities of the regulators and the HTA bodies can be seen as one of the reasons for the growing evidence gap remaining after the private sector has performed the trials needed to bring their product to the market. Regulators and HTA bodies differ in their recommendations on patient population, comparators and trial endpoints. The confirmatory trials asked by the regulators may not be fit for purpose to perform HTA nor to inform physicians wanting to practice evidence-based medicine. A better alignment of evidentiary requirements of regulators and HTA/payers could accelerate patient access to evidence-based innovations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An additional option is to perform the missing comparative effectiveness trial in the post-marketing phase. Most informative to healthcare decision-makers are practice-oriented, also named pragmatic trials. Such trials have patient relevant outcomes, recruit a broad patient population and have usual care as comparator. Practice-oriented trials lead to real-world evidence and have proven to be practice-changing. A clear pathway towards the realization of such efficient trial methods is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KEY TAKEWAYS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patient access to evidence-based innovations can be accelerated if practice-oriented trials are timely conducted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Such trials have patient relevant outcomes, recruit a broad patient population and have usual care as comparator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitators would be an alignment of the evidentiary requirements of regulators and HTA/payers as well as a framework for an efficient conduct of trials based on coded electronic health records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI EIWG Webinar: Estimands in Oncology - How and Why (Session 1) </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210601psi-eiwg-webinar-estimands-in-oncology-how-and-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210601psi-eiwg-webinar-estimands-in-oncology-how-and-why/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You will be guided through a case study and interactively deepen the knowledge to gain hands-on experience in developing estimands. You will be introduced to the background and disease context of the case study, the concept of an estimand, and important clinical events (increased dropout rate and crossover therapy) that occurred in the trial and affected interpretation of the results. Using non-technical language and clear graphical presentation of the concepts, you will experience how the estimand framework provides a common language to describe the diversity of patient journeys and why it is important to address the right question in clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical University of South Carolina (MUSC) Short Course: Using R for Bayesian Spatial and Spatio-Temporal Health Modeling</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210601medical-university-of-south-carolina-musc-short-course-using-r-for-bayesian-spatial-and-spatio-temporal-health-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210601medical-university-of-south-carolina-musc-short-course-using-r-for-bayesian-spatial-and-spatio-temporal-health-modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration ends by May 10, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Recurrent Event Analysis in R with the reReg Package</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210531isi-short-course-recurrent-event-analysis-in-r-with-the-rereg-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210531isi-short-course-recurrent-event-analysis-in-r-with-the-rereg-package/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare recurrent event data in R with the Recur() function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploring recurrent event data with event plots and mean cumulative function with the plotEvent() and mcf() functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simulating recurrent event data and fitting regression models with the simSC() and reReg() functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: An Introductory Course in Competing Risks</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210528isi-short-course-an-introductory-course-in-competing-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210528isi-short-course-an-introductory-course-in-competing-risks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Survival function and hazard function. Right-censoring and left-truncation. Competing risks. Markov and non-Markov multi-state models. Time-homogeneity and time inhomogeneity. Motivating examples (real data).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing risks: The competing risks multi-state model. Non-identifiability in the latent failure time model. Cause-specific hazards (transition intensities) and sub-distribution hazards. Cumulative incidence functions. Simulating competing risks data. Nonparametric estimation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportional hazards regression models: Proportional cause-specific hazards model. Proportional sub-distribution hazards model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA BIOP Webinar: Generalized Pairwise Comparisons for Benefit/Risk Assessment in Personalized Medicine </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210527asa-biop-webinar-generalized-pairwise-comparisons-for-benefit-risk-assessment-in-personalized-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210527asa-biop-webinar-generalized-pairwise-comparisons-for-benefit-risk-assessment-in-personalized-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A novel statistical approach to the analysis of randomized clinical trials uses all pairwise comparisons between two patients, one in the treatment arm and one in the control arm. Each pair favors treatment (“win”), control (“loss”), or neither. The “net treatment benefit” is the difference between the proportion of wins minus the proportion of losses. Pairwise comparisons can incorporate several outcomes of interest and several thresholds of clinical relevance in the analysis, and as such, they can be used to personalize treatment choices and to assess the benefit/risk of randomized therapeutic interventions in a rigorous yet flexible manner (Buyse 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages and limitations of generalized pairwise comparisons will be illustrated using two typical examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a single time-to-event endpoint, the net survival benefit is a meaningful measure of treatment effect whether or not hazards are proportional. When a delayed treatment effect is anticipated, for example in immune-oncology trials, the net benefit is appealing because it stresses benefits that are clinically worthwhile on the time scale. The test based on the net survival benefit can also gain power as compared to the traditional logrank test if interest focuses on long-term survival differences (Péron 2016a).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most anticancer treatment have substantial toxicities that may counterbalance treatment benefits. Generalized pairwise comparisons can be used to assess the benefit-risk balance of new treatments. This will be illustrated using several randomized trials in patients with metastatic pancreatic cancer (Péron 2016b).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buyse M. Generalized pairwise comparisons for prioritized outcomes in the two-sample problem. Stat Med 2010; 29: 3245-3257.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Péron J, Roy P, Ozenne B, Roche L, Buyse M. The net chance of a longer survival as a patient-oriented measure of benefit in randomized clinical trials. JAMA Oncology 2016a; 2:901-5.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Péron J, Roy P, Conroy T, Desseigne F, Ychou M, Gourgou-Bourgade S, Stanbury T, Roche L, Ozenne B, Buyse M. An assessment of the benefit-risk balance of FOLFIRINOX in metastatic pancreatic adenocarcinoma. Oncotarget 2016b;7:82953-82960.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Healthcare &amp; Life Sciences Virtual Symposium</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210527aws-healthcare-life-sciences-virtual-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210527aws-healthcare-life-sciences-virtual-symposium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The era of personalization is here. From the integration of genomics data into pharma R&amp;amp;D, to creating personalized diagnostics tools and therapies, to the delivery of healthcare anywhere, anytime, to those who need it most- AWS is powering the personalization revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us for our third annual free event focusing on how healthcare &amp;amp; life science organizations are using cloud technology to power precision medicine, personalize patient journeys, engage more closely with customers, and ultimately improve outcomes. Hear from industry leaders on how they innovate on AWS to power their business and advance their initiatives, across segments such as genomics, biopharma, medical devices, health IT, healthcare providers, and payors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Webinar: Rethink Reporting with Automation </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210526rstudio-webinar-rethink-reporting-with-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210526rstudio-webinar-rethink-reporting-with-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We invite you to join Claudio Rebelo, Actuary at Swiss Re, to learn about how companies in every industry, but especially in insurance, can revolutionize their reporting capabilities with automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll learn about his team’s journey transitioning from a reporting frankenstack, involving SAS, Excel, and SQL, to a more effective way with free, open-source tools like R Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA SLDS Webinar: Towards Secure and Interpretable AI - Scalable Methods, Interactive Visualizations, and Practical Tools </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210525asa-slds-webinar-towards-secure-and-interpretable-ai-scalable-methods-interactive-visualizations-and-practical-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210525asa-slds-webinar-towards-secure-and-interpretable-ai-scalable-methods-interactive-visualizations-and-practical-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI and ML models are often vulnerable to adversarial attacks, and their predictions can be difficult to understand, evaluate and ultimately act upon. We present recent research highlights: ShapeShifter, the world’s first targeted adversarial technique that fools state-of-the-art object detector; MalNet, the largest public cybersecurity database with over 1.2M graphs and images; Summit and Bluff, systems that scalably summarize and visualize what features a deep learning model has learned, how those features interact to make predictions; CNN Explainer and GAN Lab (with Google Brain): a suite of accessible tools for students and experts alike to learn about AI models (both went viral).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DFCI Data Science Zoominar: Modeling Cancer Etiology and Evolution, and its Implications for Prevention</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210525data-science-zoominar-modeling-cancer-etiology-and-evolution-and-its-implications-for-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210525data-science-zoominar-modeling-cancer-etiology-and-evolution-and-its-implications-for-prevention/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Sample Size Determination - Approaches to Interval Estimation and Hypothesis testing</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210525bayesian-sample-size-determination-approaches-to-interval-estimation-and-hypothesis-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210525bayesian-sample-size-determination-approaches-to-interval-estimation-and-hypothesis-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background and Introduction to Bayesian Sample Size Determination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bayesian Credible Intervals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consensus-based approaches to constructing Credible Intervals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypothesis testing using the Bayesian Posterior Error Approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypothesis testing using Bayes Factors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI Webinar: Oncology Ted Style Talks (with interaction)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210525psi-webinar-oncology-ted-style-talks-with-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210525psi-webinar-oncology-ted-style-talks-with-interaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PSI members: free; non-members: £20+VAT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of this PSI virtual meeting is to enable practical interaction among clinical statisticians actively working in oncology and those interested to work in this area. The simple format of this meeting specifically facilitates these interactions, by balancing equally time dedicated to a sequence of short, engaging talks covering a broad range of relevant topics and to Q&amp;amp;A. A breakout session halfway through the meeting will also enable casual interactions with the speakers and among meeting participants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytel Webinar: Information Borrowing in Clinical Trials - Methods for Basket Trials and External Data</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210525cytel-webinar-information-borrowing-in-clinical-trials-methods-for-basket-trials-and-external-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210525cytel-webinar-information-borrowing-in-clinical-trials-methods-for-basket-trials-and-external-data/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASQ RRD Series Webinar: Covid-19 Statistical Modeling, Summary of a Year Work</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210521asq-rrd-series-webinar-covid-19-statistical-modeling-summary-of-a-year-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210521asq-rrd-series-webinar-covid-19-statistical-modeling-summary-of-a-year-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Jorge Romeu will share with us, how  groups from different sectors including from healthcare, education  and research apply Statistical Models to understand and identify new learning or  to prompt future follow ups and/or investigation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSWG KOL Lecture Series: Slamming the Sham - A Bayesian Model for Adaptive Adjustment with Noisy Control Data</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210521dia-bswg-kol-lecture-series-slamming-the-sham-a-bayesian-model-for-adaptive-adjustment-with-noisy-control-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210521dia-bswg-kol-lecture-series-slamming-the-sham-a-bayesian-model-for-adaptive-adjustment-with-noisy-control-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not always clear how to adjust for control data in causal inference, balancing the goals of reducing bias and variance. We show how, in a setting with repeated experiments, Bayesian hierarchical modeling yields an adaptive procedure that uses the data to determine how much adjustment to perform. The result is a novel analysis with increased statistical efficiency compared to the default analysis based on difference estimates. We demonstrate this procedure on two real examples, as well as on a series of simulated datasets. We show that the increased efficiency can have real-world consequences in terms of the conclusions that can be drawn from the experiments. We also discuss the relevance of this work to causal inference and statistical design and analysis more generally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fireside Chat with Kaggle Founder Anthony Goldbloom</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210520fireside-chat-with-anthony-goldbloom-founder-of-kaggle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210520fireside-chat-with-anthony-goldbloom-founder-of-kaggle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hear Anthony share his thoughts and experiences from the past 10 years at the forefront of competitive Machine Learning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What led him to start Kaggle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What have been the biggest changes over Kaggle’s 10 years?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is a Kaggle competition winner ever viable to be operationalised?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the pros and cons of being acquired by Google?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do organisations best use the Kaggle community?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is Kaggle good for its members? (is it a fair exchange?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s next for Kaggle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30th Bradford Hill Memorial Lecture: Life course epidemiology - from the Bradford Hill viewpoints to counterfactual comparisons</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/2021052030th-bradford-hill-memorial-lecture-life-course-epidemiology-from-the-bradford-hill-viewpoints-to-counterfactual-comparisons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 09:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/2021052030th-bradford-hill-memorial-lecture-life-course-epidemiology-from-the-bradford-hill-viewpoints-to-counterfactual-comparisons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Professor Bianca De Stavola will discuss how life course investigations may characterise the impact of exposures over time (e.g., continuous or time-specific) and across dimensions (e.g., via joint or distinct pathways), and how different study designs may aid them. She will also compare ‘traditional’ approaches to gather evidence for causality and potential areas of intervention with the formality and clarity of counterfactual-based estimands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA BIOP Webinar: Graphical approaches for the control of generalized error rates</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210520asa-biop-webinar-graphical-approaches-for-the-control-of-generalized-error-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210520asa-biop-webinar-graphical-approaches-for-the-control-of-generalized-error-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When simultaneously testing multiple hypotheses, the usual approach in the context of confirmatory clinical trials is to control the familywise error rate (FWER), which bounds the probability of making at least one false rejection. In many trial settings, these hypotheses will additionally have a hierarchical structure that reflects the relative importance and links between different clinical objectives. The graphical approach of Bretz et al (2009) is a flexible and easily communicable way of controlling the FWER while respecting complex trial objectives and multiple structured hypotheses. However, the FWER can be a very stringent criterion that leads to procedures with low power, and may not be appropriate in exploratory trial settings. This motivates controlling generalized error rates, particularly when the number of hypotheses tested is no longer small. We consider the generalized familywise error rate (k-FWER), which is the probability of making k or more false rejections, as well as the tail probability of the false discovery proportion (FDP), which is the probability that the proportion of false rejections is greater than some threshold. We also consider asymptotic control of the false discovery rate, which is the expectation of the FDP. In this presentation, we show how to control these generalized error rates when using the graphical approach and its extensions. We demonstrate the utility of the resulting graphical procedures on clinical trial case studies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Indian Statistical Association (IISA) 2021 Conference</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210520international-indian-statistical-association-iisa-2021-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210520international-indian-statistical-association-iisa-2021-conference/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI VisSIG Webinar: Grammar of Graphics - theory to implementation</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210519psi-vissig-webinar-grammar-of-graphics-theory-to-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210519psi-vissig-webinar-grammar-of-graphics-theory-to-implementation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk we&amp;rsquo;ll introduce the Grammar of Graphics, which allows you to compose graphs by combining independent components, and the implementation of this theory in R &amp;ndash; the ggplot2 package. We will describe the basics of building plots with ggplot2 and touch on a few approaches for customizing the plots. We will also highlight a few packages that are built to supplement ggplot2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytel Webinar: Utilizing Bayesian Analysis to Make Go/No-Go Decisions in a Platform Trial</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210518cytel-webinar-utilizing-bayesian-analysis-to-make-go-no-go-decisions-in-a-platform-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210518cytel-webinar-utilizing-bayesian-analysis-to-make-go-no-go-decisions-in-a-platform-trial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5/4/2021: A New Hybrid Phase I-II-III Clinical Trial Paradigm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=3142844&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=A7CFB7FFF093713391FB55CF327DC229&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5/11/2021: Early Phase Oncology Decision Making Using East Bayes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=3160410&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=60085D7BE81E0415ED79D2544918CD38&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5/18/2021: Utilizing Bayesian Analysis to Make Go/No-Go Decisions in a Platform Trial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=3160412&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=1929B8F3F563638562684BBA1B94BEF0&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5/25/2021: Information Borrowing in Clinical Trials: Methods for Basket Trials and External Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=3142848&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=A9D8F90D859FDD4C0B302215306E5EC9&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6/1/2021: Review of Adaptive Phase II Basket Trial Designs in East Bayes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=3160414&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=30D8B435E7CB53330197867CB2946152&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6/8/2021: Leveraging External Control Data for Clinical Trials with Time-to-Event Endpoints&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=3142854&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=43F18A126FB63CF47D1F98F398672305&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6/15/2021: Bayesian Inference Using Poisson-Gamma Model Under Non-Proportional Hazards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=3160482&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=E1B11F1518E7962566D16D13EB2C194E&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6/22/2021: Using Robust Bayesian Priors to Borrow Information from Historical Adult Trials for a Clinical Trial in Pediatric Multiple Sclerosis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>42nd Annual Meeting of Society of Clinical Trials (SCT)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/2021051742nd-annual-meeting-of-society-of-clinical-trials-sct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/2021051742nd-annual-meeting-of-society-of-clinical-trials-sct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration deadline: May 10, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conference highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plenary sessions, topical sessions and contributed presentations (both live and on-demand) on COVID-19 studies, the impact of COVID-19 on trials, along with many other clinical trial related topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-conference educational workshops, offering guidance on both classical and topical issues in clinical trials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annual Thomas C. Chalmers Student Scholarship and Sylvan Green Award competitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion of timely issues and research experiences among colleagues in the field of clinical trials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation of the 2020 David Sackett Trial of the Year Award&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation of the SCT Class of 2021 Fellows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISPOR 2021</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210517ispor-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210517ispor-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Statistical Methods in Imaging Conference 2021</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210517the-statistical-methods-in-imaging-conference-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210517the-statistical-methods-in-imaging-conference-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration ends on May 2, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DahShu Webinar: Automated Image Labeling for Medical Imaging AI</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210514dahshu-webinar-automated-image-labeling-for-medical-imaging-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210514dahshu-webinar-automated-image-labeling-for-medical-imaging-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computer vision application in the medical domain have recently become quite popular. Detecting, localizing, and diagnosing diseases and recognizing structures on MRI, CT, PET, XRay, ultrasound and photographic images is efficiently done by AI. What is rarely discussed, is how these AI systems are made. They require copious amounts of training data consisting of images and human-supplied labels. The labels are marked areas (either rectangles or free-form boundaries) that are attached to a word, e.g. “tumor.” Naturally, only highly qualified professionals are able to provide these labels making the process effortful and expensive. A technique called “active learning” from AI can help with this by reducing the manual effort by 90%. This allows the creation of state-of-the-art AI models for medicine using a significantly smaller budget of time and resources. This talk will present the method with several examples and will argue that this approach is a disruptive shift in medical AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Webinar: Building Effective Data Science Teams</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210513building-effective-data-science-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210513building-effective-data-science-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this panel webinar, you will hear from leaders at Warner Music Group, T-Mobile, Saturn Cloud, The Looma Project, and Caliber Home Loans, about what it takes to build successful a data science team:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their experiences and perspective on building great data science teams of both R and Python users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How their teams prioritize and deliver work in a way that adds value to their organizations, while also maintaining credibility among stakeholders even when the results aren’t necessarily good news&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their advice for advancing your own data science career and collaborating with non-data-science stakeholders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COPSS-NISS COVID-19 Data Science Webinar Series: Communication of Statistical and Epidemiologic Concepts to Broad Audiences</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210513copss-niss-covid-19-data-science-webinar-series-communication-of-statistical-and-epidemiologic-concepts-to-broad-audiences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210513copss-niss-covid-19-data-science-webinar-series-communication-of-statistical-and-epidemiologic-concepts-to-broad-audiences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past year has seen a huge increase in the communication of statistical, medical, and public health concepts, methods, and results to broad audiences.  The general public has been exposed to the ideas of reproduction numbers, exponential growth, randomized trials, and the challenges of program evaluation in ways that had rarely been seen at such a large scale.  This webinar will provide a discussion between two experts in scientific communication&amp;ndash;Jenn Dowd, co-founder of Dear Pandemic and Associate Professor at the University of Oxford, and Ed Yong, staff writer at The Atlantic. They will discuss what they have learned during the course of the pandemic about communicating statistical/epidemiological concepts to broad audiences, what challenges remain, and how might we best address them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FDA Grand Rounds: Project Orbis - Global Collaborative Oncology Review Program</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210513fda-grand-rounds-project-orbis-global-collaborative-oncology-review-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210513fda-grand-rounds-project-orbis-global-collaborative-oncology-review-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FDA Oncology Center of Excellence (OCE) launched Project Orbis in May 2019 with international regulatory authorities as a global collaborative review program for oncology marketing applications. Current Project Orbis partners include the regulatory health authorities of Australia, Brazil, Canada, Singapore, Switzerland, and the United Kingdom. The program aims to facilitate the submission, review, and approval of high impact oncology marketing applications across the participating countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning Objectives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss the general framework of Project Orbis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain how other FDA and OCE review programs interact with Project Orbis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Philadelphia Chapter Webinar on Machine learning in Neuroimaging: Applications to Clinical Neuroscience and Neurooncology</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210513asa-philadelphia-chapter-webinar-on-machine-learning-in-neuroimaging-applications-to-clinical-neuroscience-and-neurooncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210513asa-philadelphia-chapter-webinar-on-machine-learning-in-neuroimaging-applications-to-clinical-neuroscience-and-neurooncology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning has deeply penetrated the neuroimaging field in the past 15 years, by providing a means to construct imaging signatures of normal and pathologic brain states on an individual person basis. In this talk, I will discuss examples from our laboratory’s work on imaging signatures of brain aging and early stages of neurodegenerative diseases, brain development and neuropsychiatric disorders, as well as brain cancer precision diagnostics and estimation of molecular characteristics. I will discuss some challenges, such as disease heterogeneity, integration of data from multiple sites, and derivation of interpretable statistical maps from certain machine learning tools, and will present some of our work in these directions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Traveling Course: Introduction to Structural Equation Modeling with Health-Related Outcome Measures</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210513asa-traveling-course-introduction-to-structural-equation-modeling-with-health-related-outcome-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210513asa-traveling-course-introduction-to-structural-equation-modeling-with-health-related-outcome-measures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration Deadline: May 6, 2021 @ 3pm PST; ASA members: $45, non-members: $50&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontiers in Biostatistics Seminar: Single-cell RNA-Seq Data Analysis Via a Regularized Zero-Inflated Mixture Model Framework</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210511frontiers-in-biostatistics-seminar-single-cell-rna-seq-data-analysis-via-a-regularized-zero-inflated-mixture-model-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210511frontiers-in-biostatistics-seminar-single-cell-rna-seq-data-analysis-via-a-regularized-zero-inflated-mixture-model-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Applications of single-cell RNA sequencing in various biomedical research areas have been blooming. This new technology provides unprecedented opportunities to study disease heterogeneity at the cellular level. However, unique characteristics of scRNA-seq data, including large dimensionality, high dropout rates, and possibly batch effects, bring great difficulty into the analysis of such data. Not appropriately addressing these issues obstructs true scientific discovery. Herein, we propose a unified Regularized Zero-inflated Mixture Model framework designed for scRNA-seq data (RZiMM-scRNA) to simultaneously detect cell subgroups and identify gene differential expression based on a developed importance score, accounting for both dropouts and batch effects. We conduct extensive empirical investigation to demonstrate the promise of RZiMM-scRNA in comparison to several popular methods, including K-means and Hierarchical clustering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Virtual Conference on Advances in Statistics - Honoring the Contributions of Barry C. Arnold in Statistical Science </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210507international-virtual-conference-on-advances-in-statistics-honoring-the-contributions-of-barry-c-arnold-in-statistical-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210507international-virtual-conference-on-advances-in-statistics-honoring-the-contributions-of-barry-c-arnold-in-statistical-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The conference will feature research topics inspired by the substantial contributions of Professor Barry C. Arnold in areas including ordered data analysis, univariate distribution theory, multivariate distribution theory, goodness-of-fit tests, statistical inference, and statistical applications. The main objective of this conference is to bring together researchers to discuss recent developments and explore future directions on these topics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First CANSSI-NISS Health Data Science Workshop</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210506first-canssi-niss-health-data-science-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210506first-canssi-niss-health-data-science-workshop/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 4th Stat4Onc Annual Symposium (2021)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210506the-4th-stat4onc-annual-symposium-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210506the-4th-stat4onc-annual-symposium-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Topics for this symposium include big data and genomics, novel dose-finding designs, umbrella/basket designs, drug combinations, immune-based oncology, and engagement of under-representative population in oncology research.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: Mar 31, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI One-Day Meeting: Missing Data in Clinical Trials - Past, Present and Future [Part 2]</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210505psi-one-day-meeting-missing-data-in-clinical-trials-past-present-and-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210505psi-one-day-meeting-missing-data-in-clinical-trials-past-present-and-future/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI One-Day Meeting: Missing Data in Clinical Trials - Past, Present and Future [Part 1]</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210504psi-one-day-meeting-missing-data-in-clinical-trials-past-present-and-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 02:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210504psi-one-day-meeting-missing-data-in-clinical-trials-past-present-and-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Incomplete datasets due to missing data is an issue that has been, and will be, around for a long time. At this meeting we will present the evolution of missing data approaches, looking at how they have been handled in the past, the current established missing data approaches and the impact of the new ICH E9 R1 addendum on the handling of missing data, focussing in particular on the treatment policy estimand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Timings&lt;br&gt;
04:30 - Introduction &amp;amp; Welcome&lt;br&gt;
06:18 - Khadija Rantell&lt;br&gt;
44:30 - Jiawei Wei&lt;br&gt;
1:38:00 - Bohdana Ratitch&lt;br&gt;
2:23:50 - Panel Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing Frameworks and Methods for Competing Risks Data</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210430competing-frameworks-and-methods-for-competing-risks-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210430competing-frameworks-and-methods-for-competing-risks-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Competing risks data arise frequently in clinical and epidemiologic studies. Such data are characterized by a survival time that terminates due to one of several mutually exclusive causes. This webinar will cover the following: the two most commonly adopted frameworks for competing risks data; relevant estimands and estimators within each framework; the role of censoring as a competing risk; available modeling strategies; and causal inference in the competing risks setting. The main ideas will be illustrated through several real-data examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicating Statistics to the Media: Highs and Lows During the Pandemic (so far)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210429communicating-statistics-to-the-media-highs-and-lows-during-the-pandemic-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210429communicating-statistics-to-the-media-highs-and-lows-during-the-pandemic-so-far/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The current crisis is notable for the vast traffic in official and unofficial information and claims.  I will offer some personal insights into the challenges of trying to bring some illumination to the statistics about the pandemic, illustrated with some examples of things have gone fairly well, and some communication disasters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI One-Day Meeting: Non-proportional hazards and applications in immuno-oncology</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210429psi-one-day-meeting-non-proportional-hazards-and-applications-in-immuno-oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 03:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210429psi-one-day-meeting-non-proportional-hazards-and-applications-in-immuno-oncology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designs of clinical trials with time to event primary endpoints usually rely on hazards being constant over time. A major challenge in immuno-oncology is the delayed onset of benefit with such therapies and the presence of non-proportional hazards. The impact of this needs to be accounted for in sample size calculations, analysis methodology and reporting. In this meeting we will examine possible strategies to handle such features, which may not be fully known when the trial is initiated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DahShu Webinar: Dynamic Data Monitoring of Ongoing Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210423dynamic-data-monitoring-of-ongoing-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210423dynamic-data-monitoring-of-ongoing-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to a recent report, nearly 70% Phase II trials failed to move forward to Phase III. Part of the reasons caused such high failure rate could be inefficient trial design and trial monitoring. In this talk, we introduce the concept of dynamic data monitoring (DDM) for ongoing clinical trials. We develop the principles and procedures for dynamically monitoring on-going clinical trials and demonstrate that the accumulative treatment effect can be automatically estimated and continuously accessible over the information time. Building on the adaptive group sequential (AGS) methods, and by taking the advantage of modern eClinical technologies, we developed a clinical trial “radar” system on which the Wald statistics, conditional power, trend, timing for sample size re-estimation, alerting of early stopping for efficacy and/or futility can be automatically displayed. Thus, the trail can be intelligently monitored. Through simulation, we demonstrate the power of DDM in guiding a promising trial to success or detecting a “hopeless” trial to stop. We provide an example of DDM application in the 1st remdesivir trial in Wuhan China.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Causal Inference Meeting (EuroCIM) 2021</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210423european-causal-inference-meeting-eurocim-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210423european-causal-inference-meeting-eurocim-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virtual courses (exact times TBD)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 April: &amp;ldquo;Introduction to causal inference&amp;rdquo; by Rhian Daniel (Cardiff University)&lt;br&gt;
18 May: &amp;ldquo;Causal machine learning&amp;rdquo; by Stijn Vansteelandt (Ghent University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Events (exact times and ordering of talks for each theme TBD)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 May: Theme 1: Methods (propensity score; double robust &amp;amp; semiparametric estimation; machine learning; Bayesian methods; etc), Invited speaker: Edward Kennedy (Carnegie Mellon University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;26 May: Theme 2: Survival / longitudinal analyses, trials &amp;amp; estimands, Invited speaker: Jessica Young (Harvard Medical School)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 July: Theme 3: Mixed topics - including e.g., applications, designs (IVs etc), interference, econometrics, Invited speaker: Ingeborg Waernbaum (Uppsala University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 September: Theme 4: Foundations, causal DAGs, structural equation models, mediation analysis, Invited speaker: Thomas Richardson (University of Washington)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polygenic Risk Prediction and Equitable Disease Prevention</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210422polygenic-risk-prediction-and-equitable-disease-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210422polygenic-risk-prediction-and-equitable-disease-prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent discoveries from large scale genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have raised the prospect of using polygenic risk scores in routine health care setting for the prediction of future incidence of large variety of complex diseases. However, as GWAS studies to date have been heavily biased towards European origin populations, current polygenic risk scores often underperform in non-European populations and thus use of them can further exacerbate healthcare inequality. In this talk, I will review simple and advanced statistical methods for generating polygenic risk score using high-dimensional SNP data and describe theoretical characterizations of their expected performance, both in the population that underlies original studies and in a different population that is expected to have different distribution of allele frequencies and linkage disequilibrium (SNP-correlation). I will further describe novel Bayesian and machine learning based methods for building polygenic risk scores that can borrow information across GWAS studies of different ethnic groups, and thus makes best use of available data to generate more powerful polygenic risk scores across different ethnic groups. I will demonstrate potential utility for PRS in precision medicine using our recent studies on breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26th Pfizer/ASA/UConn Distinguished Statistician Colloquium: Four Excursions in Genomics </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/2021042126th-pfizer-asa-uconn-distinguished-statistician-colloquium-four-excursions-in-genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/2021042126th-pfizer-asa-uconn-distinguished-statistician-colloquium-four-excursions-in-genomics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the Colloquium is to provide a forum for a distinguished statistician to share and disseminate their unique perspective and work in the theory and/or application of statistics. This year’s speaker will be Professor Peter Bickel, from the Department of Statistics, University of California, Berkeley. The title of his presentation will be “Four excursions in genomics”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The colloquium will be followed by a discussion with Liza Levina from the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Purnamrita Sarkar from the University of Texas, Austin, and Rachel Wang, from the University of Sydney.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NISS-Merck Meet-Up: Open Source Software in Pharma</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210421niss-merck-meet-up-open-source-software-in-pharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210421niss-merck-meet-up-open-source-software-in-pharma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Use of open access software, especially R,  is becoming prevalent in pharma. There is a tremendous amount of interest, but many do not understand the basic landscape regarding regulators’ thoughts, the groups that have been working in this area and what has already been accomplished.  This meet-up will discuss this topic from different viewpoints, including an expert from the R Validation Hub (the group that has probably given the deepest thought to this topic), regulatory, and practitioners who have used open access software for submissions in the device field.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duke Industry Statistics Symposium</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210421duke-industry-statistics-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210421duke-industry-statistics-symposium/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford Drug Discovery Symposium (SDDS) 2021</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210419stanford-drug-discovery-symposium-sdds-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210419stanford-drug-discovery-symposium-sdds-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Advances in research and technology now afford us the unique opportunity to develop and test novel diagnostics and therapeutics. This conference takes advantage of the collective experience and expertise of our participants to cover a broad range of policy, research, and venture topics. This symposium provides an invaluable forum for interdisciplinary exchange at the forefront of drug research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Multivariate Probability of Success Using Historical Data with Family-wise Error Rate Control</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210416bayesian-multivariate-probability-of-success-using-historical-data-with-family-wise-error-rate-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210416bayesian-multivariate-probability-of-success-using-historical-data-with-family-wise-error-rate-control/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying the Plane While Improving It - Learning from COVID Patient Data in Close to Real Time</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210415flying-the-plane-while-improving-it-learning-from-covid-patient-data-in-close-to-real-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210415flying-the-plane-while-improving-it-learning-from-covid-patient-data-in-close-to-real-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the current pandemic the need to translate clinical data into actionable research to inform patient care has never been more urgent. Using the Precision Medicine Analytics Platform at Johns Hopkins University, a team of clinicians, biostatisticians and information technologists at the Precision Medicine Center of Excellence for COVID-19 rapidly created a COVID-19 patient registry and deployed an array of biostatistical methods to understand patient trajectories, conduct comparative effectiveness research for therapeutics, learn about pathobiology of COVID-19 and implement a real-time prediction model into the electronic health record (EHR). Join this session to hear about the lessons learned from conducting research in real time while building a complex data registry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIA/FDA Biostatistics Industry and Regulator Forum</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210414dia-fda-biostatistics-industry-and-regulator-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210414dia-fda-biostatistics-industry-and-regulator-forum/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMR 2021 Virtual Conference</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210413emr-2021-virtual-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210413emr-2021-virtual-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;7am-noon on April 13, 20 &amp;amp; 27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major theme will be work on the Covid-19 pandemic, spanning countries in our region (Bulgaria, Cyprus, Greece, Israel, Turkey, United Arab Emirates) and beyond (Belgium, India, Italy, Spain, United Kingdom, United States). There will also be talks on a variety of other topics, including machine learning in healthcare, brain imaging, statistical genetics, precision medicine, species dynamics, survival analysis, causal inference and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13th Annual University of Pennsylvania Conference on Statistical Issues in Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/2021041213th-annual-university-of-pennsylvania-conference-on-statistical-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/2021041213th-annual-university-of-pennsylvania-conference-on-statistical-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: green;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Presentation slides can be downloaded from the website&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series - A First Course with Bootstrap Sampler</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210408time-series-a-first-course-with-bootstrap-sampler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210408time-series-a-first-course-with-bootstrap-sampler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course will be a reprise of the main topics of the book by the same name, by Tucker McElroy and Dimitris Politis. The intended audience includes statisticians with little or no knowledge of time series, but a general knowledge of statistics. Prerequisites include a course on linear models, a course on mathematical statistics (such concepts as bias, variance, and the Gaussian distribution), and a familiarity with linear algebra (the transpose, inverse, and eigen-values of a matrix). The aim is to cover basic concepts of time series analysis at a level suitable for those with a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s or master&amp;rsquo;s degree in statistics, while including a few non-standard concepts such as volatility filtering and time series bootstraps. A second aim is to incorporate coding in R of all concepts, methods, and examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal Inference for Multiple Time-point (Longitudinal) Exposures</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210407causal-inference-for-multiple-time-point-longitudinal-exposures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210407causal-inference-for-multiple-time-point-longitudinal-exposures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop applies the Causal Roadmap to estimate the causal effects with multiple intervention variables, such as the cumulative effect of an exposure over time, controlled direct effects, and effects on survival-type outcomes with right-censoring. We will cover longitudinal causal models, identification in the presence of time-dependent confounding; and estimation of joint treatment effects using G-computation, inverse probability weighting (IPW), and targeted maximum likelihood estimation (TMLE) with Super Learner. During the workshop session, participants will work through the Roadmap using an applied example and implement these estimators with the ltmle R package. Prior training in causal inference in a single time-point setting is strongly recommended, but not required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Law of Robustness for Two-layer Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210402a-law-of-robustness-for-two-layer-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210402a-law-of-robustness-for-two-layer-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COPSS-NISS COVID-19 Data Science Webinar Series: Pandemics, Poverty and Public Health</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210401copss-niss-covid-19-data-science-webinar-series-pandemics-poverty-and-public-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210401copss-niss-covid-19-data-science-webinar-series-pandemics-poverty-and-public-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This presentation will focus on Dr. Kim’s 30 years of experience in battling a pandemics in developing countries.  A trained infectious disease physician, Dr. Kim has tackled multidrug-resistant tuberculosis, HIV, cholera, Ebola and now COVID-19 in developing countries in Latin America, Asia and Africa.  He has also been involved in the COVID-19 response in the United States through the organization he co-founded, Partners in Health.  Dr. Kim will first talk about his experiences in combatting both poverty and infectious diseases throughout his career and then looks forward to a robust question and answer session.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharp Inference on Selected Subgroups in Observational Studies</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210401sharp-inference-on-selected-subgroups-in-observational-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 08:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210401sharp-inference-on-selected-subgroups-in-observational-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In modern drug development, the broader availability of high-dimensional observational data provides opportunities for scientist to explore subgroup heterogeneity, especially when randomized clinical trials are unavailable due to cost and ethical constraints. However, a common practice that naively searches the subgroup with a high treatment level is often misleading due to the “subgroup selection bias.” More importantly, the nature of high-dimensional observational data has further exacerbated the challenge of accurately estimating the subgroup treatment effects. To resolve these issues, we provide new inferential tools based on resampling to assess the replicability of post-hoc identified subgroups from observational studies. Through careful theoretical justification and extensive simulations, we show that our proposed approach delivers asymptotically sharp confidence intervals and debiased estimates for the selected subgroup treatment effects in the presence of high-dimensional covariates. We further demonstrate the merit of the proposed methods by analyzing the UK Biobank data. The R package “debiased.subgroup&amp;quot; implementing the proposed procedures is available on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> ASA Biopharm&#39;s Podcast</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210401asa-biopharm-s-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210401asa-biopharm-s-podcast/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Significance Podcast</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210401practical-significance-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210401practical-significance-podcast/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats &#43; Stories Podcast</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210401stats-stories-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210401stats-stories-podcast/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pod of Asclepius</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210401the-pod-of-asclepius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210401the-pod-of-asclepius/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duke-Margolis Seminars</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326duke-margolis-seminars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326duke-margolis-seminars/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundations of Data Science - Virtual Talk Series</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326foundations-of-data-science-virtual-talk-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326foundations-of-data-science-virtual-talk-series/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Seminar on Selective Inference</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326international-seminar-on-selective-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326international-seminar-on-selective-inference/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Institute of Statistical Sciences (NISS) Meeting Recordings</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326niss-meeting-recordings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326niss-meeting-recordings/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) Video Archives</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326neurips-video-archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326neurips-video-archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Causal Inference Seminar</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326online-causal-inference-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326online-causal-inference-seminar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Seminar on  Mathematical Foundations of Data Science</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326online-seminar-on-mathematical-foundations-of-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326online-seminar-on-mathematical-foundations-of-data-science/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royal Statistical Society (RSS) Video and Audio</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326rss-video-and-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326rss-video-and-audio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royal Statistical Society (RSS) Webinars</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326rss-webinars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326rss-webinars/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio webinars</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326rstudio-webinars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326rstudio-webinars/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statisticians in the Pharmaceutical Industry (PSI) Video-on-Demand</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326psi-video-on-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/resource/20210326psi-video-on-demand/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Randomized Trial with Sample Size Re-estimation - Challenges and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210325designing-a-randomized-trial-with-sample-size-re-estimation-challenges-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210325designing-a-randomized-trial-with-sample-size-re-estimation-challenges-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, we will play the part of a sponsor consulting a statistician with the goal of designing a randomized trial with sample-size re-estimation. We will discuss the concept of conditional power and the promising-zone method, and we will present a pragmatic view of some issues, including when to plan the sample-size re-estimation in the course of the accrual, how to select the amount of sample-size increase, and how to operate such trials in practice. We will also discuss the pros- and cons- of using this type of design in relation to the clinical setting in which the trial is designed and endpoints it uses. Moreover, we will discuss the regulators’ views and illustrate our discussion with practical examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Control Mythbusters</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210325synthetic-control-mythbusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210325synthetic-control-mythbusters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Synthetic control arms leverage real world data from various sources or evaluations of historical clinical data to demonstrate the positive effects of a new therapy or treatment, without the need to use a placebo or standard of care as a control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulators in both the United States and Europe have responded positively to the use of SCAs in clinical development. While implementation of this method for regulatory purposes might be a new development, the majority of statistical and mathematical theories used for the design of SCAs are decades old and familiar to the scientific community. However, synthetic control arm studies are often subject to many misplaced industry myths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this webinar our panel of expert speakers from Cytel, Roche and CIOX Health, will share their insights and bust Real-World Data industry myths around the use of synthetic controls in research and regulatory applications. In addition, they will dispel and bust a number of myths related to their specific sector of industry, namely pharma, data vendor, and consulting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from COVID-19 Data on Transmission, Health Outcomes, Interventions and Vaccination </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210323learning-from-covid-19-data-on-transmission-health-outcomes-interventions-and-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210323learning-from-covid-19-data-on-transmission-health-outcomes-interventions-and-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Video Passcode &lt;span style=&#34;color: green;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;=TpGiw#6&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;br&gt;
ASA Members: $20&lt;br&gt;
Student ASA Member: $15&lt;br&gt;
Nonmembers: $35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will first provide a historical overview of the epidemic in Wuhan. I will then provide the analysis results of 32,000 lab-confirmed COVID-19 cases in Wuhan to estimate the transmission rates using Poisson Partial Differential Equation based transmission dynamic models. This model is also used to evaluate the effects of different public health interventions on controlling the COVID-19 outbreak, such as social distancing, isolation and quarantine. I will present the results on the epidemiological characteristics of the cases. The results show that multi-faceted intervention measures successfully controlled the outbreak in Wuhan. I will next present transmission regression models for estimating transmission rates in USA and other countries, as well as factors including intervention effects using social distancing, test-trace-isolate strategies that affect transmission rates. I will discuss estimation of the proportion of undetected cases, including asymptomatic, pre-symptomatic cases and mildly symptomatic cases, the chances of resurgence in different scenarios, prevalence, and the factors that affect transmissions. I will also present the US county-level analysis to study the demographic, social-economic, and comorbidity factors that are associated with COVID-19 case and death rates. I will also present the analysis results of &amp;gt;500,000 participants of the HowWeFeel project on health outcomes and behaviors in US, and discuss the factors associated with infection, behavior, and vaccine hesitancy. I will provide several takeaways and discuss priorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Framework for Optimal Data-Driven Optimization</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210319general-framework-for-optimal-data-driven-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210319general-framework-for-optimal-data-driven-optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We propose a statistically optimal approach to construct data-driven decisions for stochastic optimization problems. Fundamentally, a data-driven decision is simply a function that maps the available training data to a feasible action. It can always be expressed as the minimizer of a surrogate optimization model constructed from the data. The quality of a data-driven decision is measured by its out-of-sample risk. An additional quality measure is its out-of-sample disappointment, which we define as the probability that the out-of-sample risk exceeds the optimal value of the surrogate optimization model. The crux of data-driven optimization is that the data-generating probability measure is unknown. An ideal data-driven decision should therefore minimize the out-of-sample risk simultaneously with respect to every conceivable probability measure (and thus in particular with respect to the unknown true measure). Unfortunately, such ideal data-driven decisions are generally unavailable. This prompts us to seek data-driven decisions that minimize the out-of-sample risk subject to an upper bound on the out-of-sample disappointment - again simultaneously with respect to every conceivable probability measure. We prove that such Pareto-dominant data-driven decisions exist under conditions that allow for interesting applications: the unknown data-generating probability measure must belong to a parametric ambiguity set, and the corresponding parameters must admit a sufficient statistic that satisfies a large deviation principle. If these conditions hold, we can further prove that the surrogate optimization model generating the optimal data-driven decision must be a distributionally robust optimization problem constructed from the sufficient statistic and the rate function of its large deviation principle. This shows that the optimal method for mapping data to decisions is, in a rigorous statistical sense, to solve a distributionally robust optimization model. Maybe surprisingly, this result holds irrespective of whether the original stochastic optimization problem is convex or not and holds even when the training data is non-i.i.d. As a byproduct, our analysis reveals how the structural properties of the data-generating stochastic process impact the shape of the ambiguity set underlying the optimal distributionally robust optimization model. This is joint work with Tobias Sutter and Bart Van Parys.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Statistical Learning and Inference in EHR and Other Healthcare Datasets</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210309distributed-statistical-learning-and-inference-in-ehr-and-other-healthcare-datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210309distributed-statistical-learning-and-inference-in-ehr-and-other-healthcare-datasets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The growth of availability and variety of healthcare data sources has provided unique opportunities for data integration and evidence synthesis, which can potentially accelerate knowledge discovery and enable better clinical decision making.  However, many practical and technical challenges, such as data privacy, high-dimensionality and heterogeneity across different datasets, remain to be addressed. In this talk, I will introduce several methods for effective and efficient integration of electronic health records and other healthcare datasets. Specifically, we develop communication-efficient distributed algorithms for jointly analyzing multiple datasets without the need of sharing patient-level data. Our algorithms are able to account for heterogeneity across different datasets. We provide theoretical guarantees for the performance of our algorithms, and examples of implementing the algorithms to real-world clinical research networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Neural Networks through the Lens of Feature Interactions</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210226deciphering-neural-networks-through-the-lens-of-feature-interactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210226deciphering-neural-networks-through-the-lens-of-feature-interactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interpreting how neural networks work is a crucial and challenging task in machine learning. In this talk, I will discuss a novel framework, namely neural interaction detector (NID), for interpreting complex neural networks by detecting statistical interactions captured by the neural networks. Furthermore, we can construct a more interpretable generalized additive model that achieve similar prediction performance as the original neural networks. Experiment results on several applications, such as recommender systems, image recognition, sentiment prediction, demonstrate the effectiveness of NID.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veridical Data Science for biomedical discovery: detecting epistatic interactions with epiTree</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210226veridical-data-science-for-biomedical-discovery-detecting-epistatic-interactions-with-epitree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 09:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210226veridical-data-science-for-biomedical-discovery-detecting-epistatic-interactions-with-epitree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data Science is a pillar of A.I. and has driven most of recent cutting-edge discoveries in biomedical research. In practice, Data Science has a life cycle (DSLC) that includes problem formulation, data collection, data cleaning, modeling, result interpretation and the drawing of conclusions. Human judgement calls are ubiquitous at every step of this process, e.g., in choosing data cleaning methods, predictive algorithms and data perturbations. Such judgment calls are often responsible for the &amp;ldquo;dangers&amp;rdquo; of A.I. To maximally mitigate these dangers, we developed a framework based on three core principles: Predictability, Computability and Stability (PCS). Through a workflow and documentation (in R Markdown or Jupyter Notebook) that allows one to manage the whole DSLC, the PCS framework unifies, streamlines and expands on the best practices of machine learning and statistics - bringing us a step forward towards veridical Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lecture, we will illustrate the PCS framework through the epiTree; a pipeline to discover epistasis interactions from genomics data. epiTree addresses issues of scaling of penetrance through decision trees, significance calling through PCS p-values, and combinatorial search over interactions through iterative random forests (which is a special case of PCS). Using UK Biobank data, we validate the epiTree pipeline through an application to the red-hair phenotype, where several genes are known to display epistatic interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of a Statistician</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210226the-role-of-a-statistician/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210226the-role-of-a-statistician/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illuminating the Black Box: Variable Importance Measures for Interpretable Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210225illuminating-the-black-box-variable-importance-measures-for-interpretable-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210225illuminating-the-black-box-variable-importance-measures-for-interpretable-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recording passcode&lt;/strong&gt;: 6cleDgX+&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Dr. Wolf will provide an overview of common machine learning methods (e.g. ensemble methods, support vector machines and neural networks) and discuss currently implemented importance measures that provide semi-quantitative measures of associations between variables and outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 ASA Conference on Statistical Practice</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210217csp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20210217csp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of the conference is to provide participants with opportunities to learn new statistical methodologies and best practices in statistical analysis, design, consulting, and statistical programming.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration Deadline: Jan 11, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bias and Randomization 1980 - 2020 - 2060</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210211bias-and-randomization-1980-2020-2060/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210211bias-and-randomization-1980-2020-2060/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn on history of bias and randomization in oncology clinical trials and how to think about what constitutes persuasive evidence of treatment efficacy and safety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIONEERing estimands in Clinical Research</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210112pioneering-estimands-in-clinical-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20210112pioneering-estimands-in-clinical-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bringing estimands to life through a real case study. A year on after the final ICH E9 estimands addendum was published, we bring estimands to life from a real example from protocol to press release. Members of the estimands Implementation Working Group (EIWG) will describe the background and study objectives, intercurrent events of interest and chosen estimands in the PIONEER study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Randomized Studies and Utilization of Real-World Evidence</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201217non-randomized-studies-and-utilization-of-real-world-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201217non-randomized-studies-and-utilization-of-real-world-evidence/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Monitoring and Adaptive Designs</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201215data-monitoring-and-adaptive-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201215data-monitoring-and-adaptive-designs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Machine Learning &amp; Causal Inference Workshop</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201215interpretable-machine-learning-causal-inference-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201215interpretable-machine-learning-causal-inference-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 2 Fallacy: Or why interpretation needs more than transparency (Peter Tennant)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using causal machine learning to explore heterogeneous responses to policies (Noemi Kreif)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symbolic machine learning for interpretable AI: recent advancements and future directions (Alessandra Russo)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questioning the AI: towards human-centered interpretable machine learning (Vera Liao)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This year&#39;s most popular clinical trial designs topics</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201215this-year-s-most-popular-clinical-trial-designs-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201215this-year-s-most-popular-clinical-trial-designs-topics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase II Adaptive Trials Designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase III Adaptive Trial Designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further Webinar Highlights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Observations on SARS-CoV-2 and Crisis Vaccine Clinical Testing</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201210statistical-observations-on-sars-cov-2-and-crisis-vaccine-clinical-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201210statistical-observations-on-sars-cov-2-and-crisis-vaccine-clinical-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Traditional vaccine clinical development is an undertaking involving meticulous, multiple studies in multiple populations at risk of infection and disease over multiple years. SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19 vaccine development is following this traditional development pathway, but accelerated Phase I-II-III clinical programs are being applied (c.f., USA FDA guidances 2020). This is not the first time vaccines have been manufactured and tested quickly to meet a public health crisis (1976, 2009). Selected statistical concepts pertaining to vaccine efficacy and safety, relevant during the design and implementation of such crisis programs, are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal reasoning in survival and time-to-event analyses</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201204causal-reasoning-in-survival-and-time-to-event-analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201204causal-reasoning-in-survival-and-time-to-event-analyses/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head to Head Comparisons Using Real World Data - Practical Application</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201202head-to-head-comparisons-using-real-world-data-practical-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201202head-to-head-comparisons-using-real-world-data-practical-application/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Data Science in the Cloud?</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201202why-data-science-in-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201202why-data-science-in-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Present Your Research? - Focus and Intentionality Are Keys!</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201130how-to-present-your-research-focus-and-intentionality-are-keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201130how-to-present-your-research-focus-and-intentionality-are-keys/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propensity score weighting for covariate adjustment in randomized clinical trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201124propensity-score-weighting-for-covariate-adjustment-in-randomized-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201124propensity-score-weighting-for-covariate-adjustment-in-randomized-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U-Design: SaaS for Streamlining Trial Simulation and Report Writing Using Efficient Statistical Designs</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201124u-design-saas-for-streamlining-trial-simulation-and-report-writing-using-efficient-statistical-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201124u-design-saas-for-streamlining-trial-simulation-and-report-writing-using-efficient-statistical-designs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Trial Design and Decision Making in a Broader Context - Program and Portfolio Optimization</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201118clinical-trial-design-and-decision-making-in-a-broader-context-program-and-portfolio-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201118clinical-trial-design-and-decision-making-in-a-broader-context-program-and-portfolio-optimization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Judea Pearl</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201117interview-with-judea-pearl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201117interview-with-judea-pearl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Disease Risk from Genomics Data</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201117predicting-disease-risk-from-genomics-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201117predicting-disease-risk-from-genomics-data/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI Journal Club: Bayesian Methods</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201117psi-journal-club-bayesian-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201117psi-journal-club-bayesian-methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: green;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Replay links available on website&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Bayesian approach in design and analysis of pediatric cancer clinical trials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Speaker: Jingjing Ye (BeiGene)&lt;br&gt;
Publication: Jingjing Ye, Gregory Reaman, R. Angelo De Claro &amp;amp; Rajeshwari Sridhara, Pharmaceutical Statistics. 2020;1–13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estimation of group means using Bayesian generalized linear mixed models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Speaker: Amy LaLonde (Eli Lilly)&lt;br&gt;
Publication: Amy LaLonde &amp;amp; Yongming Qu, Pharmaceutical Statistics. 2020;19:482–491&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of COVID-19 in Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201117the-impact-of-covid-19-in-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201117the-impact-of-covid-19-in-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding the Impact of Covid-19 in the areas of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clinical Operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical Perspective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Composite Intercurrent Events vs ICE Categories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistical Covid-19 strategies including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Study Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measuring the effect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovations in Bayesian Trials Virtual Symposium</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20201108innovations-in-bayesian-trials-virtual-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20201108innovations-in-bayesian-trials-virtual-symposium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This dynamic program will cover a range of topics presented by Bayesian experts in academia, regulatory and industry. The presentations will include: Adaptive design, platform studies, complex innovative designs using Bayesian modeling; Regulatory acceptability of Bayesian designs; Leveraging external information using Bayesian priors.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color: green;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Replay links available&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, October 8, 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bayesian Statistics and FDA Regulatory Acceptability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Greg Campbell, PhD, President, GCStat Consulting (1hr)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=2691488&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=7C84CEA899224E2CDE4F7E22CFABDECB&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, October 22, 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bayesian Dose-finding Designs for Modern Drug Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Yuan Ji, Professor of Biostatistics, Department of Public Health Sciences, The University of Chicago (1hr)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=2691496&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=08500FE422DAFE88617C8485AB42E961&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, Novermber 05, 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bayesian Dynamic Borrowing for Partial Extrapolation and Bridging Studies: Methods and Case Studies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Nicky Best, Head, Advanced Biostatistics and Data Analytics Centre of Excellence, GSK (1hr)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;loginemail=peiwen.wu%40gilead.com&amp;amp;eventid=2691499&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=3C8FF73C92BC880B2A5989FDE9074FF5&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, November 19, 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistical Design and Conduct of Platform Trials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Jason Connor, President &amp;amp; Lead Statistical Scientist, ConfluenceStat (1hr)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=2691515&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=4B07CFCA81196A4A8DDB075F8E813266&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, December 3, 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bayesian Models for Precision Oncology Clinical Trials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Peter Mueller, Professor, Department of Mathematics and the
Department of Statistics &amp;amp; Data Science, The University of Texas at Austin (1hr)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=2691509&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=7B1DA30C7762FC9B3DB4A0EABBE36DD9&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, December 10, 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recent Development on Bayesian Clinical Trial Designs Using Historical Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ming-Hui Chen, Professor and Head of the Department of Statistics, The University of Connecticut (1hr) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=2691518&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=B3CA28FA4552CAB13C45A32C412748AD&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday March 11, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leveraging external evidence in medical device decision-making&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ram C. Tiwari, Ph.D. Head of Statistical Methodology, Bristol Myers Squibb&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=3024363&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=BD2CA3B8AB7D9856260F5287B7FE45B3&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint PSI, EFSPI &amp; ASA BIOP Webinar: Estimands</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201105joint-psi-efspi-asa-biop-webinar-estimands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201105joint-psi-efspi-asa-biop-webinar-estimands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following aspects are covered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with proposals submitted to FDA and EMA on implementation of Estimands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the estimands framework facilitates interaction with clinicians in different therapeutic areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common problems where the Estimands framework can help advance research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where further discussions and research is required, and particularly where industry and regulators can collaborate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issues related to alignment between different estimators to a given estimand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special considerations of estimand framework in COVID-19 vaccine trials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-imagining Clinical Trials: An Advanced Design Framework for the Era of Cloud-Computing</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201104re-imagining-clinical-trials-an-advanced-design-framework-for-the-era-of-cloud-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201104re-imagining-clinical-trials-an-advanced-design-framework-for-the-era-of-cloud-computing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Donald Rubin</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201103interview-with-donald-rubin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201103interview-with-donald-rubin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 New England Rare Disease Statistics (NERDS) Webinar Series</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/202011022020-new-england-rare-disease-statistics-nerds-webinar-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/202011022020-new-england-rare-disease-statistics-nerds-webinar-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Introductory NERDS Session&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to Select Endpoints and Quantify Treatment Effect in a Comparative Clinical Study on COVID-19 Diseases (L.J. Wei (Harvard))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Borrowing Information from Historical Data: A Double-edged Sword (Ying Yuan (MD Anderson))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pfizerevents.webex.com/pfizerevents/lsr.php?RCID=13985dd6a939e0e4f8998620b4a428b1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recording&lt;/a&gt; (Password: hWFURkY5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. CID Program Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Bayesian Adaptive Trial in Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy (Steve Lake (Wave Life Sciences))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovative Designs in the Rare Disease Setting (Dionne Price (FDA))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pfizerevents.webex.com/pfizerevents/lsr.php?RCID=1bc6e1d02b1002d62c170a17473e3d54&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recording&lt;/a&gt; (Password: pMbpsJT7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Gene Therapy in Rare Disease Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gene Therapy: Opportunities and Challenges for the Treatment of Hemophilia (Michelle Casey (Pfizer))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pfizerevents.webex.com/pfizerevents/lsr.php?RCID=ccaaeefdd89e63e72892e9650397f117&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recording&lt;/a&gt; (Password: NERDS456)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Case Studies in Rare Disease Drug Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lessons from Notable New Drug Application involving External Controls (Margaret (Meg) Gamalo (Pfizer))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design and Analysis of Drop the Losers Studies in the Rare Disease Setting (Glen Laird (Vertex))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Case Study Using Nature History Data to Understand Long Term Disease Progression (Cindy Lu (Biogen))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pfizerevents.webex.com/pfizerevents/lsr.php?RCID=e227bbfd8699459593dffc5ce07cd795&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recording&lt;/a&gt; (Password: Pq8pBWgU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Rs - Reliability, Reproducibility, Replicability: The Interplay Between Statistical Science and Data Science</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201030three-rs-reliability-reproducibility-replicability-the-interplay-between-statistical-science-and-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201030three-rs-reliability-reproducibility-replicability-the-interplay-between-statistical-science-and-data-science/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Trials for, and despite, COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201027clinical-trials-for-and-despite-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201027clinical-trials-for-and-despite-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the key characteristics of COVID-19 trials, particularly with regard to trial-design features such as trial mechanics (including factorial and multi-stage designs, as well as platform trials), outcome assessment, and other important methodological issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the impact the pandemic is having on clinical trials in several fields, including oncology and cardiology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;practical issues pertaining to trial design and conduct, including for data capture, data management, statistical analysis, and patient follow-up, all of which affected by the current crisis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomarker Analysis in Clinical Trials Using R</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201021biomarker-analysis-in-clinical-trials-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201021biomarker-analysis-in-clinical-trials-using-r/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Design For Non inferiority And Equivalence</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201021study-design-for-non-inferiority-and-equivalence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201021study-design-for-non-inferiority-and-equivalence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regulatory information on this type of study design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Considerations for study design and your sample size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practical worked examples of Non-inferiority Testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equivalence Testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovations in Bayesian Clinical Trials Interactive Workshops</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201015innovations-in-bayesian-clinical-trials-interactive-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201015innovations-in-bayesian-clinical-trials-interactive-workshops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive Workshop 1: Essentials of Bayesian Statistics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
October 15, 2020&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;loginemail=peiwen.wu%40gilead.com&amp;amp;eventid=2691551&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=109B6B88F22396785524BCAD42C50522&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive Workshop 2: Bayesian Meta-Analysis and Hierarchical Models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
October 29, 2020&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;loginemail=peiwen.wu%40gilead.com&amp;amp;eventid=2691558&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=8543F409BD3894D06579F92276808A5D&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive Workshop 3: Prior Distributions (Part I)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
November 12, 2020&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;loginemail=peiwen.wu%40gilead.com&amp;amp;eventid=2691561&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=238DEB3AC5D91E14B89095AF22C63D05&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Topics on COVID-19 vaccine and therapeutic clinical trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201015statistical-topics-on-covid-19-vaccine-and-therapeutic-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201015statistical-topics-on-covid-19-vaccine-and-therapeutic-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statisticians Debate Issues Central to Inference and Estimation</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201015statisticians-debate-issues-central-to-inference-and-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201015statisticians-debate-issues-central-to-inference-and-estimation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this event was to shed light on and explain the main features (pro and con) that surround some of the controversies on use of p-values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim Berger (Duke University) has been exploring the Bayesian and frequentist foundations of statistics for 50 years, and has recently been heavily involved in bringing these foundational perspectives to the p-value debate. David Trafimow (New Mexico State University) started the serious questioning of any use of p-values via the journal he edits, and Deborah Mayo (Virginia Tech) has developed a reformulation of frequentist error statistical methods within a full-blown philosophy of learning from error.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12th Annual Sentinel Initiative Public Workshop</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/2020101412th-annual-sentinel-initiative-public-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/2020101412th-annual-sentinel-initiative-public-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session I: A Robust Sentinel System for the 21st Century&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Objective: In response to new legislative mandates and the desire to diversify scientific expertise and enhance core key capabilities in the Sentinel System, the Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER) has awarded a new five-year contract that establishes a new organizational structure for the Sentinel Coordinating Center. This new contract builds on FDA successes integrating the active, post-market safety surveillance into regulatory decision-making. This session will feature key leads from each Sentinel coordinating center who will discuss plans on how to advance and transform Sentinel’s data infrastructure into a national resource for evidence generation. Panelists will also discuss opportunities for collaboration to broaden stakeholder involvement, improve access to new data sources and analytic tools, and ensure more efficient and effective safety surveillance activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session II: Building the BEST Network and Establishing New Capabilities for the Surveillance of Biologics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Objective: Launched in 2017, the BEST Initiative enacts the Agency’s mandate to implement active surveillance for biologic products. This session will highlight key achievements of BEST over the last year enhancing its capabilities to execute safety and effectiveness surveillance and inform regulatory decision making. CBER representatives will discuss ongoing work to support the expansion of the BEST data network and methods infrastructure as well as specific studies utilizing the infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session III: Leveraging the Sentinel Initiative for COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Objective: The U.S. FDA’s Sentinel Initiative is engaged in numerous activities to protect and promote public health during the COVID-19 pandemic. This session will highlight key ongoing efforts across CDER and CBER to leverage Sentinel data infrastructure to describe course of illness, and evaluate the utilization, safety, and effectiveness of available COVID-19 therapeutics and vaccines under real-world conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12th Annual Sentinel Initiative Public Workshop</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/2020101412th-annual-sentinel-initiative-public-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/2020101412th-annual-sentinel-initiative-public-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sentinel Initiative, an active medical product surveillance system, was established in response to the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) Amendments Act of 2007 and has become one of the Agency’s premier evidence generation platforms. The 12th Annual Sentinel Initiative Public Workshop is being convened on October 14, 2020 by the Robert J. Margolis, MD, Center for Health Policy under a cooperative agreement with the FDA. The workshop will be held as a virtual webinar and provides an opportunity to discuss recent achievements and developments and engage with the broader community of patients, consumers, and scientific stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session I: A Robust Sentinel System for the 21st Century&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Objective: In response to new legislative mandates and the desire to diversify scientific expertise and enhance core key capabilities in the Sentinel System, the Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER) has awarded a new five-year contract that establishes a new organizational structure for the Sentinel Coordinating Center. This new contract builds on FDA successes integrating the active, post-market safety surveillance into regulatory decision-making. This session will feature key leads from each Sentinel coordinating center who will discuss plans on how to advance and transform Sentinel’s data infrastructure into a national resource for evidence generation. Panelists will also discuss opportunities for collaboration to broaden stakeholder involvement, improve access to new data sources and analytic tools, and ensure more efficient and effective safety surveillance activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session II: Building the BEST Network and Establishing New Capabilities for the Surveillance of Biologics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Objective: Launched in 2017, the BEST Initiative enacts the Agency’s mandate to implement active surveillance for biologic products. This session will highlight key achievements of BEST over the last year enhancing its capabilities to execute safety and effectiveness surveillance and inform regulatory decision making. CBER representatives will discuss ongoing work to support the expansion of the BEST data network and methods infrastructure as well as specific studies utilizing the infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session III: Leveraging the Sentinel Initiative for COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Objective: The U.S. FDA’s Sentinel Initiative is engaged in numerous activities to protect and promote public health during the COVID-19 pandemic. This session will highlight key ongoing efforts across CDER and CBER to leverage Sentinel data infrastructure to describe course of illness, and evaluate the utilization, safety, and effectiveness of available COVID-19 therapeutics and vaccines under real-world conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Pfizer/ASA/UConn Distinguished Statistician Colloquium: From the Application to the General – Notation is Everything</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/202010142020-pfizer-asa-uconn-distinguished-statistician-colloquium-from-the-application-to-the-general-notation-is-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/202010142020-pfizer-asa-uconn-distinguished-statistician-colloquium-from-the-application-to-the-general-notation-is-everything/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Pharma</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20201013r-in-pharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20201013r-in-pharma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2020 R/Pharma conference was held as a virtual event between October 13th and 15th October. Over 1000 people from 26 countries registered for the main conference. In addition, 11 workshops were held the week before the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting confidentiality and privacy in clinical trial and medical data sets</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201007protecting-confidentiality-and-privacy-in-clinical-trial-and-medical-data-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201007protecting-confidentiality-and-privacy-in-clinical-trial-and-medical-data-sets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are increasingly living in a data driven world. Data are collected in many different ways for a variety of purposes. As such concerns around protecting the privacy of individuals have increased in recent times. Research into protecting the confidentiality of any data collected is an important and challenging area of research. In particular, there is often a trade-off between protecting confidentiality and preserving the utility in the data. This meeting seeks to explore and address issues of protecting confidentiality and privacy when it comes to collecting clinical trial and medical/health data. The session speakers comprise some of the world leaders and experts in the field bringing together researchers from both academia and the pharmaceutical industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randomization and Regression Adjustment</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201007randomization-and-regression-adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201007randomization-and-regression-adjustment/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cytel’s New Horizons Webinar Series</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20201005cytel-s-new-horizons-webinar-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20201005cytel-s-new-horizons-webinar-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: green;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Replay links available&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increasing the Power of Platform Trials: Efficient Multi-Arm Multi-Stage Adaptive Designs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Speaker: Cyrus Mehta&lt;br&gt;
October 5, 2020&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=2713671&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=DEC35F5F99E3B346CD3428FB63E00EA1&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Value of Detailed Statistical Trial Simulations – A Case Study for Rare Diseases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Speaker: Ursula Garczarek&lt;br&gt;
October 26, 2020&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=2754403&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=5190486304A26AF8A168A9EB5762E412&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Design Considerations for Adaptive Platform Trials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Speaker: Jay Park&lt;br&gt;
November 2, 2020&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=2803072&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=B00AA58DD8F16FD72214ED83EAE3F56C&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI in Clinical Research: Prediction and Causal Inference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Speaker: Alind Gupta&lt;br&gt;
November 9, 2020&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=reg20.jsp&amp;amp;mode=login&amp;amp;eventid=2803079&amp;amp;sessionid=1&amp;amp;key=F30F710608E4E55C3E02D0193E42FEAB&amp;amp;regTag=&amp;amp;V2=false&amp;amp;sourcepage=register&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Measurements-based Approach to Machine Learning for Bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201002a-new-measurements-based-approach-to-machine-learning-for-bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201002a-new-measurements-based-approach-to-machine-learning-for-bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Real World Evidence Conference: Applying Lessons Learned from RWE in the Time of COVID-19 to the Future</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20201001annual-real-world-evidence-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20201001annual-real-world-evidence-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 has disrupted the evidence-generation paradigm, resulting in the expanded use of novel technologies, data, and evidence. These new advancements not only improve clinical care and medical product development to fight the pandemic, but also have the potential to inform the future of drug development more broadly. This meeting will explore how COVID-19 has accelerated decision-maker understanding and use of real-world data (RWD) and real-world evidence (RWE) and its application in a post-COVID-19 environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detangle modern dose-finding designs: A tutorial</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201001detangle-modern-dose-finding-designs-a-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20201001detangle-modern-dose-finding-designs-a-tutorial/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Early Stage Oncology Research with Adaptive Designs and Master Protocols</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200929advancing-early-stage-oncology-research-with-adaptive-designs-and-master-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200929advancing-early-stage-oncology-research-with-adaptive-designs-and-master-protocols/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved determination of the maximum tolerated dose, comparing different designs for dose selection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantages of basket trial design for finding the most appropriate indication(s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current regulatory positions and outlook of the International Council for Harmonization of Technical Requirements for Pharmaceuticals for Human use (ICH)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operational implications of different designs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under the Hood of 1Point3Acres COVID-19 Map and Tracker</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200925under-the-hood-of-1point3acres-covid-19-map-and-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200925under-the-hood-of-1point3acres-covid-19-map-and-tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Yu will first discuss how her volunteer team fought to have brought data transparency to CovidNet. Then, Kyle will present his team’s novel approach to continuous data quality monitoring, which combines semantic analysis with time series anomaly detection methods, ending with some examples showing issues (known and benign) detected in the 1point3acres dataset. Prof Shan Lu will also provide an example how the high quality data source can be highly useful for even non-biological scientists to produce meaningful analysis in a situation like COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Biopharmaceutical Section Regulatory-Industry Statistics Workshop 2020</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20200922asa-biopharmaceutical-section-regulatory-industry-statistics-workshop-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20200922asa-biopharmaceutical-section-regulatory-industry-statistics-workshop-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ASA Biopharmaceutical Section Regulatory-Industry Statistics Workshop is sponsored by the ASA Biopharmaceutical Section in cooperation with the FDA Statistical Association. The conference lasts two days each year, with invited sessions co-chaired by statisticians from industry, academia, and the FDA. In addition, short courses on related topics are offered the day prior to the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head-to-Head Comparison Using Real-World Data: Study Design Considerations and an Update on the Pilot Investigation in Cancer</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200922study-design-considerations-and-an-update-on-the-pilot-investigation-in-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200922study-design-considerations-and-an-update-on-the-pilot-investigation-in-cancer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Companion Diagnostics and Clinical Development in Oncology: A Statistical Perspective</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200917companion-diagnostics-and-clinical-development-in-oncology-a-statistical-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200917companion-diagnostics-and-clinical-development-in-oncology-a-statistical-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This webinar provided a discussion around the need for integration of biomarker and IVD validation in clinical development, with a focus in oncology and companion diagnostics. It highlighted how flawed analytical and/or clinical validation can jeopardize a biomarker’s and drug’s clinical utility and showcase why biomarkers deserved statistical rigor throughout the development and validation process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NISS/Merck Meetup: Challenges and Potential in Vaccine Development</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200917niss-merck-meetup-challenges-and-potential-in-vaccine-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200917niss-merck-meetup-challenges-and-potential-in-vaccine-development/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending A Trial’s Design – Case Studies of Dealing with Study Design Issues</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200916extending-a-trial-s-design-case-studies-of-dealing-with-study-design-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200916extending-a-trial-s-design-case-studies-of-dealing-with-study-design-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-proportional Hazards&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Non-proportional hazards and complex survival curves have become of increasing interest, due to being commonly seen in immunotherapy development. This has led to interest in assessing the robustness of standard methods and alternative methods that better adapt to deviations. In this webinar, we look at methods proposed for complex survival curves and the weighted log-rank test as a candidate model to deal with a delayed survival effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cluster Randomization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Cluster-randomized designs are often adopted when there is a high risk of contamination if cluster members were randomized individually. Stepped-wedge designs are useful in cases where it is difficult to apply a particular treatment to half of the clusters at the same time. In this webinar, we introduce cluster randomization and stepped-wedge designs to provide an insight into the requirements of more complex randomization schedules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hree Armed Trials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Non-inferiority testing is a common hypothesis test in the development of generic medicine and medical devices. The most common design compares the proposed non-inferior treatment to the standard treatment alone but this leaves uncertain if the treatment effect is the same as from previous studies. This “assay sensitivity” problem can be resolved by using a three-arm trial which includes placebo alongside the new and reference treatments for direct comparison.  In this webinar we show a complete testing approach to this gold standard design and how to find the appropriate allocation and sample size for this study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSI Journal Club: Longitudinal Data</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200916psi-journal-club-longitudinal-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200916psi-journal-club-longitudinal-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two papers were discussed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Häckl, Armin Koch &amp;amp; Florian Lasch, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nam03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fonlinelibrary.wiley.com%2Fdoi%2F10.1002%2Fpst.1964&amp;amp;data=02%7C01%7Cpgokani%40amgen.com%7Cdb5d7738508f4769529708d84b2a54b7%7C4b4266a6136841afad5a59eb634f7ad8%7C0%7C0%7C637341992474201251&amp;amp;sdata=pLqJ8FoEEvKGIim4yecClhu92Ck4hzpJgUTLEms%2BcUw%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empirical evaluation of the implementation of the EMA guideline on missing data in confirmatory clinical trials: Specification of mixed models for longitudinal data in study protocols&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pharmaceutical Statistics, 2019; volume 18, Issue 6, Pages 636-644&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutamba T. Kayembe, Shahab Jolani, Frans E. S. Tan &amp;amp; Gerard J. P. van Breukelen, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nam03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fonlinelibrary.wiley.com%2Fdoi%2F10.1002%2Fpst.2041&amp;amp;data=02%7C01%7Cpgokani%40amgen.com%7Cdc9b7a71ede4491b426608d835372414%7C4b4266a6136841afad5a59eb634f7ad8%7C0%7C0%7C637317858232667163&amp;amp;sdata=zIb4UKtm%2FQq8jCsOf6YPYtaWGo8iSv4nV6WJ62vj0I4%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imputation of missing covariate in randomized controlled trials with a continuous outcome: Scoping review and new results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pharmaceutical Statistics, 2020; volume 19, Issue 6, Pages 840-860&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Optimization Methods for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200915statistical-optimization-methods-for-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200915statistical-optimization-methods-for-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Statistics and optimization are two of the foundational pillars of machine learning, and it is well recognized that optimization provides powerful tools for statistics. In recent years, techniques of the complementary nature, i.e., using statistics to improve optimization algorithms, have become increasingly successful. In this talk, we present several recent works on such statistical optimization methods. First, we discuss how to use statistical hypothesis testing to automatically adjust the learning rate of stochastic gradient methods in training deep neural networks. Then we overview some recent advances in structured nonconvex optimization using stochastic variance reduction techniques. Finally we will briefly explain how to leverage statistical preconditioning to accelerate distributed optimization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Health-Related Social Media Can Complement Traditional RWE Approaches to Access Unique Patient Insights</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200903how-health-related-social-media-can-complement-traditional-rwe-approaches-to-access-unique-patient-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200903how-health-related-social-media-can-complement-traditional-rwe-approaches-to-access-unique-patient-insights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of health-related social media data sources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ethical considerations of using these data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it is beneficial to use health-related social media as a real-world data source&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some methods used to generate insights from these data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Types of messages that can be generated from these data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Data Science at Your Organization (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200903scaling-data-science-at-your-organization-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200903scaling-data-science-at-your-organization-part-3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to Drive Agility in Clinical Reporting</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200903using-r-to-drive-agility-in-clinical-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200903using-r-to-drive-agility-in-clinical-reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The R language is used extensively throughout the pharmaceutical industry. But its use within the tightly regulated clinical reporting workflows has remained limited. GSK Biostatistics has embarked upon a journey to embed R as a primary statistical analysis tool for clinical reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enabling R within a global department of over 600 Statisticians, Programmers and Data Scientists is challenging! It requires planning, patience, and a strong foundation that enables consistency across the enterprise. We invite you to learn more about how we achieved this at GSK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll learn about our tidyverse-centric training program, a future-ready Working Area for R Programming (WARP) environment, and a leading-edge R for Clinical Reporting (R4CR) initiative. The goal: help embed R in every-day clinical reporting output.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Nearly Assumption-Free Tests of Nominal Confidence Interval Coverage for Causal Parameters Estimated by Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200901on-nearly-assumption-free-tests-of-nominal-confidence-interval-coverage-for-causal-parameters-estimated-by-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200901on-nearly-assumption-free-tests-of-nominal-confidence-interval-coverage-for-causal-parameters-estimated-by-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Conference on COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20200828data-science-conference-on-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20200828data-science-conference-on-covid-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying “Drop-Out” in Single Cell RNA-seq</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200828demystifying-drop-out-in-single-cell-rna-seq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200828demystifying-drop-out-in-single-cell-rna-seq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Droplet-based single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNA-seq) methods have changed the landscape of genomics research in complex biological systems by producing single cell resolution data at affordable costs. In the state-of-the-arts protocols, a step called barcoding unique molecular identifiers (UMI) has been introduced to remove amplification bias and further improve data quality. Recent literature suggests that barcoding has led to a different error structure in the count data with much less technical noise. Regardless, many tools do not acknowledge the differences between the read count data and UMI count data, still assuming that both suffer from excessive technical noise. In this presentation, I will make a brief overview of scRNA-seq data analysis pipelines and then present extensive analyses of publicly available UMI data sets that challenge the assumptions of most existing pre-processing tools. Our results suggest that resolving cell-type heterogeneity should be the foremost step of the scRNA-seq analysis pipeline. Normalizing or imputing the data set before resolving the heterogeneity can lead to adversary consequences in downstream analysis. As a result, we provide a new perspective on scRNA-seq data analysis by fully integrating pre-processing and clustering, which was classified as part of the downstream analysis. The proposed procedures have been implemented in software, HIPPO. If time permits, I will also talk about other single cell analysis tools developed in my group, VIPER, an imputation method for SMART-seq data, and dmatch, an alignment tool for multiple scRNA-seq samples batch correction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purdue University: Deep Learning Methods and Theory Webinar Series</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200828purdue-university-deep-learning-methods-and-theory-webinar-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200828purdue-university-deep-learning-methods-and-theory-webinar-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;August 28, &lt;strong&gt;Intuitive Introduction to Deep Learning&lt;/strong&gt;, Professor Lawrence Carin, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sVca43PstWA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September 4, &lt;strong&gt;Distributed Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;, Professor Heng Huang,  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5fFg4SLq4mU&amp;amp;t=10s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September 11, &lt;strong&gt;A Representational Model of Grid Cells Based on Matrix Lie Algebras&lt;/strong&gt;, Professor Ying Nian Wu, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lYQElUIaqEw&amp;amp;t=12s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September 18, &lt;strong&gt;Integrating Domain-Knowledge into Deep Learning&lt;/strong&gt;, Professor Ruslan Salakhutdinov, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gE78sONx_-k&amp;amp;t=4s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Data Science at Your Organization (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200827scaling-data-science-at-your-organization-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200827scaling-data-science-at-your-organization-part-2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debunking the R vs. Python Myth</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200826debunking-the-r-vs-python-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200826debunking-the-r-vs-python-myth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How many times have you heard the phrase “X is better than Y for data science”? This is a very common misconception among data scientists, and a very broad definition of data science as a whole. For data science to be impactful, it needs to be credible, agile, and durable. To be able to do this, we need to embrace the differences between R vs. Python. Maybe you prefer R for data wrangling and Python for modeling - that’s great! Why should serious data science be stifled for the sake of language loyalty? Data science teams need to use the wealth of tools available to them to deliver the most impactful results. This webinar will be a discussion among data science leaders, debunking this common myth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Clinical Trials from a Program Perspective</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200826designing-clinical-trials-from-a-program-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200826designing-clinical-trials-from-a-program-perspective/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost Matching Exactly</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200825almost-matching-exactly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200825almost-matching-exactly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will present a matching framework for causal inference in the potential outcomes setting called Almost Matching Exactly. In this setting, the goal is to match treatment and control units on as many covariates as possible. We use machine learning on a hold-out training set to learn which variables are more important to match on; in essence, the method learns a distance metric for matching. This way, our methods retain the interpretability of matching, but also use distance metrics that are automated rather than being hand-designed, and are adaptive to the data rather than being fixed. The key constraint is that units are always matched on a set of covariates that together can predict the outcome well. Our techniques for discrete variables are called Fast Large-Scale Almost Matching Exactly (FLAME), Dynamic Almost Matching Exactly (DAME), Matching After Learning to Stretch (MALTS), and Adaptive Hyper-boxes. FLAME and DAME match units on a weighted Hamming distance for discrete variables using techniques that are natural for query processing in database management. FLAME rapidly produces high quality matched groups for discrete data, even for datasets that are too large to fit in memory. DAME produces higher quality matched groups than FLAME, but is slower. MALTS is useful for continuous variables and learns distance metrics that stretch the covariates in an interpretable way. Adaptive hyper-boxes can gracefully handle both discrete and continuous covariates flexibly and interpretably by optimizing a box around each treatment unit. These methods rival black box machine learning methods in their estimation accuracy but have the benefit of being interpretable and easier to troubleshoot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Data Science at Your Organization (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200820scaling-data-science-at-your-organization-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200820scaling-data-science-at-your-organization-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IPTOP framework (Infrastructure, People, Tools, Organization and Processes) for building data strategies and systematically scaling data science within an organization&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duke-Margolis: Data Sharing to Accelerate Therapeutic Development for Rare Diseases (Day 2)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200819duke-margolis-data-sharing-to-accelerate-therapeutic-development-for-rare-diseases-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200819duke-margolis-data-sharing-to-accelerate-therapeutic-development-for-rare-diseases-day-2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Designs for Phase II Clinical Trials </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200818adaptive-designs-for-phase-ii-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200818adaptive-designs-for-phase-ii-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important aspects of Phase II trials designs to consider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practical worked examples of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MCP-Mod (continuous outcome)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MCP-Mod (binary outcome)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fleming GST (binary outcome)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duke-Margolis: Data Sharing to Accelerate Therapeutic Development for Rare Diseases (Day 1)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200818duke-margolis-data-sharing-to-accelerate-therapeutic-development-for-rare-diseases-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200818duke-margolis-data-sharing-to-accelerate-therapeutic-development-for-rare-diseases-day-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> testthat 3.0.0</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200813testthat-3-0-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200813testthat-3-0-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce some of the major changes coming in testthat 3.0.0. The biggest new idea in testthat 3.0.0 is the idea of an edition. You must deliberately choose to use the 3rd edition, which allows us to make breaking changes without breaking old packages. testthat 3e deprecates a number of older functions that we no longer believe are a good idea, and tweaks the behaviour of expect_equal() and expect_identical() to give considerably more informative output (using the new waldo package).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;testthat 3e also introduces the idea of snapshot tests which record expected value in external files, rather than in code. This makes them particularly well suited to testing user output and complex objects. I&amp;rsquo;ll show off the main advantages of snapshot testing, and why it&amp;rsquo;s better than our previous approaches of verify_output() and expect_known_output().&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over a bunch of smaller quality-of-life improvements, including tweaks to test reporting and improvements to expect_error(), expect_warning() and expect_message().&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimands: Not Just a Statistical Issue</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200813estimands-not-just-a-statistical-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200813estimands-not-just-a-statistical-issue/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive and Bayesian Designs for Dose-Finding</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200805adaptive-and-bayesian-designs-for-dose-finding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200805adaptive-and-bayesian-designs-for-dose-finding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding the right dose in Phase 2 gives a potential new therapy its best chance to demonstrate efficacy during Phase 3. A well-executed dose-ranging trial therefore has the potential to alter the course of the entire clinical development program. This webinar demonstrates how adaptive and Bayesian techniques can be implemented for optimal dose-finding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Stories of Causal Inference</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200804100-stories-of-causal-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200804100-stories-of-causal-inference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In social science we learn from stories.  The best stories are anomalous and immutable.  We shall briefly discuss the theory of stories, the paradoxical nature of how we learn from them, and how this relates to forward and reverse causal inference.  Then we will go through some stories of applied causal inference and see what lessons we can draw from them.  We hope this talk will be useful as a model for how you can better learn from own experiences as participants and consumers of causal inference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating US FDA Initiatives to Expedite Development, Approval, and Emergency Access to COVID-19 Treatments</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200730navigating-us-fda-initiatives-to-expedite-development-approval-and-emergency-access-to-covid-19-treatments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200730navigating-us-fda-initiatives-to-expedite-development-approval-and-emergency-access-to-covid-19-treatments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of the Coronavirus Treatment Acceleration Program (CTAP)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Emergency Use Authorization (EUA) and single patient expanded access pathways and processes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Securing meetings with the FDA for COVID-19 programs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key clinical development guidances specific to COVID-19 programs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingram Olkin Forum: Unplanned Disruptions in Clinical Trials (Day 2)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200729ingram-olkin-forum-unplanned-disruptions-in-clinical-trials-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200729ingram-olkin-forum-unplanned-disruptions-in-clinical-trials-day-2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Remote Data Science Teams</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200728enabling-remote-data-science-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200728enabling-remote-data-science-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up a remote and collaborative R environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Version control and Scrum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Shiny and RStudio Connect to share apps within and across teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to improve the UI and appearance of Shiny dashboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to scale Shiny dashboards to hundreds of users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to build and grow a remote data science team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head-to-head Comparisons using Real-World Data: Design and Data Source Considerations from Pilot Investigations in Cardiovascular Disease</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200728design-and-data-source-considerations-from-pilot-investigations-in-cardiovascular-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200728design-and-data-source-considerations-from-pilot-investigations-in-cardiovascular-disease/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Clinical Trial Design - Survival, Stepped-Wedge &amp; MAMS Designs</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200723flexible-clinical-trial-design-survival-stepped-wedge-mams-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200723flexible-clinical-trial-design-survival-stepped-wedge-mams-designs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible Survival Analysis Designs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Non-proportional hazards and other complex survival curves have become of increasing interest, due to being commonly seen in immunotherapy development. This has led to interest in assessing the robustness of standard methods and alternative methods that better adapt to deviations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, we will look at power analysis assuming complex survival curves and the weighted log-rank test as one candidate model to deal with a delayed survival effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stepped-Wedge designs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Cluster-randomized designs are often adopted when there is a high risk of contamination if cluster members were randomized individually. Stepped-wedge designs are useful in cases where it is difficult to apply a particular treatment to half of the clusters at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, we will introduce stepped-wedge designs and provide an insight into the more complex, flexible randomization schedules available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Arm Multi-Stage (MAMS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
MAMs designs provide the ability to assess more treatments in less time than could be done with a series of two-arm trials and can offer smaller sample size requirements when compared to that required for the equivalent number of two-arm trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, we will look at the design of a Group Sequential MAMS design and explore its design requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingram Olkin Forum: Unplanned Disruptions in Clinical Trials (Day 1)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200721ingram-olkin-forum-unplanned-disruptions-in-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200721ingram-olkin-forum-unplanned-disruptions-in-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Multiple Natural Experimental Designs to Triangulate the Impact of a Policy Change</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200717dahshu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200717dahshu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Estimating causal effects is best done using randomized controlled trials. Regrettably, for many policy-relevant questions only observational data are available. In this talk we explore how (i) decomposing a policy into multiple parts, and (ii) leveraging multiple study designs can produce stronger, more defensible causal estimates.&lt;br&gt;
We explore these statistical concepts through an example from health outcomes research: The feasibility and effectiveness of delaying surgery to transfer patients with acute type A aortic dissection—a catastrophic disease that requires prompt intervention—to higher-volume aortic surgery hospitals is unknown. We investigated the hypothesis that regionalizing care at high-volume hospitals for acute type A aortic dissections will lower mortality. We decomposed this hypothesis into subparts, investigating the isolated effect of transfer and the isolated effect of receiving care at a high-volume versus a low-volume facility. We used a preference-based instrumental variable design to address unmeasured confounding and matching to separate the effect of transfer from volume. We used the carefully deployed instrumental variable design, and contrast it with a decomposed propensity score study design, to gain deeper insights into the elements giving rise to confounding. We also develop a simple, but complete, form of sensitivity analysis to bound the effect of censored observations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimands and Analysis Considerations for Clinical Trials Impacted by COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200716estimands-and-analysis-considerations-for-clinical-trials-impacted-by-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200716estimands-and-analysis-considerations-for-clinical-trials-impacted-by-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of the estimand framework to assess and address pandemic-related disruptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis strategies for pandemic-related missing and unobservable values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Population Enrichment Trial Designs</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200715introduction-to-population-enrichment-trial-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200715introduction-to-population-enrichment-trial-designs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Statistical Practices to Tackle the Lack of Reproducibility in Preclinical Research</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200715good-statistical-practices-to-tackle-the-lack-of-reproducibility-in-preclinical-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200715good-statistical-practices-to-tackle-the-lack-of-reproducibility-in-preclinical-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4 key learnings attendees will take away from this webinar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of good design of experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider Bayesian statistics to answer your question&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;P-values is not always what you’re looking for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopt a life-cycle over the long-run, not just study by study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid Dashboard Fatigue</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200714avoid-dashboard-fatigue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200714avoid-dashboard-fatigue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, we’ll show you an easy way teams can solve these problems using proactive email notifications through the blastula and gt packages, and how RStudio pro products can be used to scale out those solutions for enterprise applications. Dynamic emails are a powerful way to meet decision makers where they live - their inbox - while displaying exactly the results needed to influence decision-making. Best of all, these notifications are crafted with code, ensuring your work is still reproducible, durable, and credible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll demonstrate how this approach provides solutions for data quality monitoring, detecting and alerting on anomalies, and can even automate routine (but precisely formatted) KPI reporting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duke MArgolis: Establishing a High-Quality Real-World Data Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20200713duke-margolis-establishing-a-high-quality-real-world-data-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20200713duke-margolis-establishing-a-high-quality-real-world-data-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EqffCIVzFt0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Day 1 video&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qm-qD8DTgOE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Day 2 video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Endpoints and Treatment Effect in Immuno-Oncology</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200707clinical-endpoints-and-treatment-effect-in-immuno-oncology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200707clinical-endpoints-and-treatment-effect-in-immuno-oncology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this webinar the speakers reviewed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptations to tumor response and progression criteria for immune therapies. Survival may be the endpoint of choice for clinical trials in some tumor types, but presence of delayed treatment effects and non-proportional hazards may complicate evaluation of treatment benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistical methods to best describe and test for treatment effects in immuno-oncology randomized clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal Inference in the Light of Drug Repurposing for SARS-CoV-2</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200707causal-inference-in-the-light-of-drug-repurposing-for-sars-cov-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 08:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200707causal-inference-in-the-light-of-drug-repurposing-for-sars-cov-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Massive data collection holds the promise of a better understanding of complex phenomena and ultimately, of better decisions. An exciting opportunity in this regard stems from the growing availability of perturbation / intervention data (drugs, knockouts, overexpression, etc.) in biology. In order to obtain mechanistic insights from such data, a major challenge is the development of a framework that integrates observational and interventional data and allows predicting the effect of yet unseen interventions or transporting the effect of interventions observed in one context to another. I will present a framework for causal structure discovery based on such data and characterize the causal relationships that are identifiable in this setting. We end by demonstrating how these ideas can be applied for drug repurposing in the current SARS-CoV-2 crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head-to-Head Comparisons using Real World Data: The Time for Causal Inference is Now</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200707the-time-for-causal-inference-is-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200707the-time-for-causal-inference-is-now/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biostats and Pharma Webinar: A Phase I–II Basket Trial Design to Optimize Dose-Schedule Regimes</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200625biostats-and-pharma-webinar-a-phase-i-ii-basket-trial-design-to-optimize-dose-schedule-regimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200625biostats-and-pharma-webinar-a-phase-i-ii-basket-trial-design-to-optimize-dose-schedule-regimes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Related Publication:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://projecteuclid.org/journals/bayesian-analysis/volume-16/issue-1/A-Phase-III-Basket-Trial-Design-to-Optimize-Dose-Schedule/10.1214/20-BA1205.full&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ruitao Lin. Peter F. Thall. Ying Yuan. &amp;ldquo;A Phase I–II Basket Trial Design to Optimize Dose-Schedule Regimes Based on Delayed Outcomes.&amp;rdquo; Bayesian Anal. 16 (1) 179 - 202, March 2021. https://doi.org/10.1214/20-BA1205&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP-Mod: Optimizing Phase II Dose Selection for Continuous and Non-Continuous Endpoints</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200617mcp-mod-optimizing-phase-ii-dose-selection-for-continuous-and-non-continuous-endpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200617mcp-mod-optimizing-phase-ii-dose-selection-for-continuous-and-non-continuous-endpoints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An introduction to MCP-Mod&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why use MCP-Mod for Phase II trials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steps to generate superior statistical evidence for dose-selection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MCP-Mod for various endpoints, including: Continuous Endpoint, Binary Endpoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poisson Rates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negative Binomial rates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked examples &amp;amp; case studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19: Pandemic Preparedness and Lessons Learned</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200610dia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200610dia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An overview of how COVID-19 progressed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can pharmaceutical companies be better prepared? Should there be plans and clinical development strategies in place?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we build resiliency? What steps could/should be implemented at various stages to ‘flatten the curve’?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vulnerable communities and minority populations are at a disadvantage. How do we address these health disparities?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replication and Evidence Factors in Observational Studies</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200602replication-and-evidence-factors-in-observational-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200602replication-and-evidence-factors-in-observational-studies/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimands in Oncology - A Virtual Panel Discussion</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200524estimands-in-oncology-a-virtual-panel-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200524estimands-in-oncology-a-virtual-panel-discussion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA-JDS Webinar Series: Data Science in Action in Response to the Outbreak of COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200417asa-jds-webinar-series-data-science-in-action-in-response-to-the-outbreak-of-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200417asa-jds-webinar-series-data-science-in-action-in-response-to-the-outbreak-of-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: green;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Replay links available on website&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curating a COVID-19 data repository and forecasting county-level death counts in the United States&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
07/24/2020,  Dr. Bin Yu, University of California, Berkeley&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The COVID-19 Forecast Hub: using statistics and data science to support decision-making in a pandemic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
07/17/2020, Dr. Nicholas Reich, University of Massachusetts, Amherst&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semiparametric Bayesian inference for the transmission dynamics of COVID-19 with a state-space model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
07/10/2020, Dr. Yuan Ji, University of Chicago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The opportunities and challenges of healthcare systems in the COVID-19 era&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
06/26/2020, Dr. Kimia Ghobadi, Johns Hopkins University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A statistical transmission model for COVID-19 outbreak with adjustment of external factors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
06/19/2020, Dr. Yifan Zhu, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistics and modeling in response to COVID-19 at NIAID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
06/12/2020, Dr. Dean Follmann, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A biostatistician&amp;rsquo;s encounter with COVID-19 in New York City&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
06/05/2020, Dr. Usha Govindarajulu, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can the reported COVID-19 data tell us the truth? Scrutinizing the data from the measurement error models perspective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
05/29/2020, Dr. Grace Yi, University of Western Ontario&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Predictions, role of interventions and implications of a national lockdown on the COVID-19 outbreak in India&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
05/22/2020, COV-IND-19 Study Group ( (Dr. Bhramar Mukherjee, University of Michigan; Dr. Debashree Ray, Johns Hopkins University; Rupam Bhattacharyya, University of Michigan; and Maxwell Salvatore, University of Michigan)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COVID-19: Analytic studies and opportunities for outside of epidemiology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
05/15/2020, Dr. David Corliss, Peace-Work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estimation of incubation period distribution of COVID-19 using disease onset forward time: A novel cross-sectional and forward follow-up study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
05/08/2020, Dr. Jing Qin, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COVID19 US dashboard: Spatiotemporal dynamics, nowcasting and forecasting of COVID-19 in the United States&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
05/01/2020, Dr. Lily Wang, Iowa State University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracking reproductivity of COVID-19 pandemic with varying coefficient epidemiological models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
04/24/2020, Dr. Song Xi Chen, Peking University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An epidemiological forecast model to assess the effect of social distancing on flattening the coronavirus curve in the USA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
04/17/2020, Dr. Peter X.K. Song University of Michigan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Conference 2020</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20200127rstudio-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/conference/20200127rstudio-conference/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
