<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSE Tracker</title>
    <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CSE Tracker</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>CSE Tracker</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Bootstrap Methods and Permutation Tests</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210618isi-short-course-bootstrap-methods-and-permutation-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210618isi-short-course-bootstrap-methods-and-permutation-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We begin with a graphical approach to bootstrapping and permutation testing, illuminating basic statistical concepts of standard errors, confidence intervals, p-values and significance tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We consider a variety of statistics (mean, trimmed mean, regression, etc.), and a number of sampling situations (one-sample, two-sample, stratified, finite-population), stressing the common techniques that apply in these situations. We’ll look at applications from a variety of fields, including telecommunications, finance, and biopharm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These methods let us do confidence intervals and hypothesis tests when formulas are not available, so we can do better statistics, e.g. use robust methods like medians, trimmed means, or robust regression. They can help clients understand statistical variability. And some of the methods are more accurate than standard methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Introduction to Machine Learning </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210615isi-short-course-introduction-to-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210615isi-short-course-introduction-to-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course describes nonparametric regression, including the additive model and its generalizations, also the LASSO, and LARS.  Then it proceeds to classification (SVMs, random forests, boosting). The Curse of Dimensionality is described in both contexts.  Bagging and stacking are covered. There is some coverage of cluster analysis, and some text analytics.  The emphasis is upon the strengths and weaknesses of the tools, and guidance on when a particular method should be used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Statistical Theory of Deep Learning </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210607isi-short-course-statistical-theory-of-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210607isi-short-course-statistical-theory-of-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course outline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation: The present great success of Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical learning theory: Regression and Classification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theory behind Deep Learning:&lt;br&gt;
a. Introduction of Neural Networks&lt;br&gt;
b. Different network architectures and activation functions&lt;br&gt;
c. Approximation theory: Which function classes can be efficiently   approximated by DNNs?&lt;br&gt;
d. Generalization: Convergence rates of DNNs for different regression and classification problems. When are those networks able to circumvent the curse of dimensionality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limits and open questions of DNNs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Reshaping Challenging Data to Produce Insightful Graphs - A Quick Start to Using R Tidyverse Tools </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210604isi-short-course-reshaping-challenging-data-to-produce-insightful-graphs-a-quick-start-to-using-r-tidyverse-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210604isi-short-course-reshaping-challenging-data-to-produce-insightful-graphs-a-quick-start-to-using-r-tidyverse-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this short course, you will learn to read and reshape a dataset from the World Bank, filter observations and select variables to produce an analysis data set and finally to produce figures. Customizing, enhancing and annotating data visualizations follows. R software with be used with functions included the tidyverse suite of packages being highlighted (dplyr, tidyr and ggplot2 in particular).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical University of South Carolina (MUSC) Short Course: Using R for Bayesian Spatial and Spatio-Temporal Health Modeling</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210601medical-university-of-south-carolina-musc-short-course-using-r-for-bayesian-spatial-and-spatio-temporal-health-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210601medical-university-of-south-carolina-musc-short-course-using-r-for-bayesian-spatial-and-spatio-temporal-health-modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration ends by May 10, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Recurrent Event Analysis in R with the reReg Package</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210531isi-short-course-recurrent-event-analysis-in-r-with-the-rereg-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210531isi-short-course-recurrent-event-analysis-in-r-with-the-rereg-package/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare recurrent event data in R with the Recur() function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploring recurrent event data with event plots and mean cumulative function with the plotEvent() and mcf() functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simulating recurrent event data and fitting regression models with the simSC() and reReg() functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: An Introductory Course in Competing Risks</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210528isi-short-course-an-introductory-course-in-competing-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210528isi-short-course-an-introductory-course-in-competing-risks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Survival function and hazard function. Right-censoring and left-truncation. Competing risks. Markov and non-Markov multi-state models. Time-homogeneity and time inhomogeneity. Motivating examples (real data).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing risks: The competing risks multi-state model. Non-identifiability in the latent failure time model. Cause-specific hazards (transition intensities) and sub-distribution hazards. Cumulative incidence functions. Simulating competing risks data. Nonparametric estimation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportional hazards regression models: Proportional cause-specific hazards model. Proportional sub-distribution hazards model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Traveling Course: Introduction to Structural Equation Modeling with Health-Related Outcome Measures</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210513asa-traveling-course-introduction-to-structural-equation-modeling-with-health-related-outcome-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210513asa-traveling-course-introduction-to-structural-equation-modeling-with-health-related-outcome-measures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration Deadline: May 6, 2021 @ 3pm PST; ASA members: $45, non-members: $50&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing Frameworks and Methods for Competing Risks Data</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210430competing-frameworks-and-methods-for-competing-risks-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210430competing-frameworks-and-methods-for-competing-risks-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Competing risks data arise frequently in clinical and epidemiologic studies. Such data are characterized by a survival time that terminates due to one of several mutually exclusive causes. This webinar will cover the following: the two most commonly adopted frameworks for competing risks data; relevant estimands and estimators within each framework; the role of censoring as a competing risk; available modeling strategies; and causal inference in the competing risks setting. The main ideas will be illustrated through several real-data examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polygenic Risk Prediction and Equitable Disease Prevention</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210422polygenic-risk-prediction-and-equitable-disease-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210422polygenic-risk-prediction-and-equitable-disease-prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent discoveries from large scale genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have raised the prospect of using polygenic risk scores in routine health care setting for the prediction of future incidence of large variety of complex diseases. However, as GWAS studies to date have been heavily biased towards European origin populations, current polygenic risk scores often underperform in non-European populations and thus use of them can further exacerbate healthcare inequality. In this talk, I will review simple and advanced statistical methods for generating polygenic risk score using high-dimensional SNP data and describe theoretical characterizations of their expected performance, both in the population that underlies original studies and in a different population that is expected to have different distribution of allele frequencies and linkage disequilibrium (SNP-correlation). I will further describe novel Bayesian and machine learning based methods for building polygenic risk scores that can borrow information across GWAS studies of different ethnic groups, and thus makes best use of available data to generate more powerful polygenic risk scores across different ethnic groups. I will demonstrate potential utility for PRS in precision medicine using our recent studies on breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series - A First Course with Bootstrap Sampler</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210408time-series-a-first-course-with-bootstrap-sampler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210408time-series-a-first-course-with-bootstrap-sampler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course will be a reprise of the main topics of the book by the same name, by Tucker McElroy and Dimitris Politis. The intended audience includes statisticians with little or no knowledge of time series, but a general knowledge of statistics. Prerequisites include a course on linear models, a course on mathematical statistics (such concepts as bias, variance, and the Gaussian distribution), and a familiarity with linear algebra (the transpose, inverse, and eigen-values of a matrix). The aim is to cover basic concepts of time series analysis at a level suitable for those with a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s or master&amp;rsquo;s degree in statistics, while including a few non-standard concepts such as volatility filtering and time series bootstraps. A second aim is to incorporate coding in R of all concepts, methods, and examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal Inference for Multiple Time-point (Longitudinal) Exposures</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210407causal-inference-for-multiple-time-point-longitudinal-exposures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210407causal-inference-for-multiple-time-point-longitudinal-exposures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop applies the Causal Roadmap to estimate the causal effects with multiple intervention variables, such as the cumulative effect of an exposure over time, controlled direct effects, and effects on survival-type outcomes with right-censoring. We will cover longitudinal causal models, identification in the presence of time-dependent confounding; and estimation of joint treatment effects using G-computation, inverse probability weighting (IPW), and targeted maximum likelihood estimation (TMLE) with Super Learner. During the workshop session, participants will work through the Roadmap using an applied example and implement these estimators with the ltmle R package. Prior training in causal inference in a single time-point setting is strongly recommended, but not required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
