<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSE Tracker</title>
    <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CSE Tracker</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>CSE Tracker</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Traveling Course: Introduction to Data Science,  Machine Learning and Deep Learning (in R and Python)</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210806asa-traveling-course-introduction-to-data-science-machine-learning-and-deep-learning-in-r-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210806asa-traveling-course-introduction-to-data-science-machine-learning-and-deep-learning-in-r-and-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This short course will provide an overview of using R and Python for some of the most popular machine learning and deep learning models in real-world data science applications in the cloud environment. The sessions will step through the basic theoretical concepts behind those models and mainly focus on applications. Students will learn the motivation and use cases of these models through hands-on exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main topics of the course include: big data cloud environment, tree-based models, regularization methods, feedforward neural network, convolutional neural network, and recurrent neural network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course syllabus, program, and materials are available on the website &lt;a href=&#34;https://course2021.scientistcafe.com/&#34;&gt;https://course2021.scientistcafe.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Cure Models - Methods, Applications, and Implementation</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210629isi-short-course-cure-models-methods-applications-and-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210629isi-short-course-cure-models-methods-applications-and-implementation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course will provide a comprehensive introduction to cure models, including basics of the cure models as well as many recent developments related to the methodological issues and software implementations of cure models for right-censored time-to-event data subject to non-informative censoring. The course will feature real-world examples from clinical trials and population-based studies and a detailed introduction to R packages, SAS macros, and WinBUGS programs to fit some cure models. Applications of cure models in other disciplines will be discussed. This course will be useful for statistical researchers and graduate students, and practitioners in other disciplines to have a thorough review of modern cure model methodology and to seek appropriate cure models in applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Precision Medicine - A Statistical Perspective on Estimating the Best Treatment Strategy </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210628isi-short-course-precision-medicine-a-statistical-perspective-on-estimating-the-best-treatment-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210628isi-short-course-precision-medicine-a-statistical-perspective-on-estimating-the-best-treatment-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidence-based medicine relies on using data to provide recommendations for effective treatment or prevention decisions. However, in many settings, effects may be heterogeneous across individuals, and within individuals over time. Healthcare providers are faced with the daunting task of making sequential therapeutic decisions having seen few patients with a given clinical history. Adaptive treatment strategies (ATS) operationalize the sequential decision-making process in the precision medicine paradigm, offering statisticians principled estimation tools that can be used to incorporate patient’s characteristics into a clinical decision-making framework so as to adapt the type, dosage or timing of intervention according to patients’ evolving needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yale Summer Course in Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210628yale-summer-course-in-clinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210628yale-summer-course-in-clinical-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Register by June 27; Registration fee: $450&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants will gain knowledge of the key components of clinical trials including but not limited to trial phase and design, randomization schemes, selection of outcome and appropriate statistical analysis including sample size and power considerations, ethics, and regulatory affairs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survival Outcome Data with High Dimensional Predictors: Methods and Applications</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210624survival-outcome-data-with-high-dimensional-predictors-methods-and-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210624survival-outcome-data-with-high-dimensional-predictors-methods-and-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ASA members: $40; non-members: $65&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the era of precision medicine, survival outcome data with high-throughput covariates and predictors are often collected. These high dimensional data defy classical survival regression models, which are either infeasible to fit or likely to incur low predictability because of overfitting. This short course will introduce various cutting-edge methods that handle survival outcome data with high dimensional predictors. I will cover statistical principles and concepts behind the methods, and will also discuss their applications to the real medical examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time permitting, I intend to cover the following topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival analysis overview: basic concepts and models, e.g. Cox, Accelerated Failure Time (AFT), and Censored Quantile Regression (CQR) Models;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival models with high dimensional predictors (p&amp;gt;n): Regularized methods and Dantzig selector;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival analysis with ultra-high dimensional predictors (p&amp;raquo;n): Screening Methods, e.g, Principled sure independent screening (PSIS), Conditional screening, IPOD, Forward selection, etc;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inference for survival models with high dimensional predictors (p&amp;gt;n).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience only needs to have some basic knowledge of regression analysis and survival analysis. The relevant papers and software for this short course can be found in: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~yili/resindex.html&#34;&gt;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~yili/resindex.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Communicating Health Data - The COVID-19 Experience</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210624isi-short-course-communicating-health-data-the-covid-19-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210624isi-short-course-communicating-health-data-the-covid-19-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two-day course on June 24 and July 1; Registration fee: €100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course  is an  introduction to effectively communicating, to general audiences,  complex statistical modelling and estimation related to Covid-19 data.  The instruction will be at a beginner level. The 6 hours course is split in 2 days and will cover “Basics of effective communication to a general audience” on day 1  and  “Introduction to estimation and  modelling of covid-19 data: prevalence, incidence, epi-curves, transmissibility and reproduction numbers” on day 2.  Classes  will include  stop&amp;amp;go discussion upon broadcasting of video-recorded interviews with experts and professionals  in media monitoring and communication of health data. A student assignment is scheduled at the end of day 1 lessons with feedback on day 2 for shared learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Bootstrap Methods and Permutation Tests</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210618isi-short-course-bootstrap-methods-and-permutation-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210618isi-short-course-bootstrap-methods-and-permutation-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We begin with a graphical approach to bootstrapping and permutation testing, illuminating basic statistical concepts of standard errors, confidence intervals, p-values and significance tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We consider a variety of statistics (mean, trimmed mean, regression, etc.), and a number of sampling situations (one-sample, two-sample, stratified, finite-population), stressing the common techniques that apply in these situations. We’ll look at applications from a variety of fields, including telecommunications, finance, and biopharm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These methods let us do confidence intervals and hypothesis tests when formulas are not available, so we can do better statistics, e.g. use robust methods like medians, trimmed means, or robust regression. They can help clients understand statistical variability. And some of the methods are more accurate than standard methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Data Science and Predictive Analytics</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210616isi-short-course-data-science-and-predictive-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210616isi-short-course-data-science-and-predictive-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The training will provide intermediate to advanced learners with a solid data science foundation to address challenges related to collecting, managing, processing, interrogating, analyzing and interpreting complex health and biomedical datasets using R. Participants will gain skills and acquire a tool-chest of methods, software tools, and protocols that can be applied to a broad spectrum of Big Data problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the mathematical algorithms, statistical computing methods, software tools, and health analytics, we will discuss a number of driving motivational problems. These will ground all the subsequent scientific discussions, data modeling, and computational approaches. The training will involve active-learning and integrate driving motivational challenges with mathematical foundations, computational statistics, and modern scientific inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on open-science principles, training will focus on effective, reliable, reproducible, and transformative data-driven discovery. Trainees will develop scientific intuition, computational skills, and data-wrangling abilities to tackle Big biomedical and advanced health data problems. The instructor will provide well-documented R-scripts and software recipes implementing atomic data-filters, as well as complex end-to-end predictive big data analytics solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Introduction to Machine Learning </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210615isi-short-course-introduction-to-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210615isi-short-course-introduction-to-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course describes nonparametric regression, including the additive model and its generalizations, also the LASSO, and LARS.  Then it proceeds to classification (SVMs, random forests, boosting). The Curse of Dimensionality is described in both contexts.  Bagging and stacking are covered. There is some coverage of cluster analysis, and some text analytics.  The emphasis is upon the strengths and weaknesses of the tools, and guidance on when a particular method should be used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Statistical Theory of Deep Learning </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210607isi-short-course-statistical-theory-of-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210607isi-short-course-statistical-theory-of-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course outline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation: The present great success of Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical learning theory: Regression and Classification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theory behind Deep Learning:&lt;br&gt;
a. Introduction of Neural Networks&lt;br&gt;
b. Different network architectures and activation functions&lt;br&gt;
c. Approximation theory: Which function classes can be efficiently   approximated by DNNs?&lt;br&gt;
d. Generalization: Convergence rates of DNNs for different regression and classification problems. When are those networks able to circumvent the curse of dimensionality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limits and open questions of DNNs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Reshaping Challenging Data to Produce Insightful Graphs - A Quick Start to Using R Tidyverse Tools </title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210604isi-short-course-reshaping-challenging-data-to-produce-insightful-graphs-a-quick-start-to-using-r-tidyverse-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210604isi-short-course-reshaping-challenging-data-to-produce-insightful-graphs-a-quick-start-to-using-r-tidyverse-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this short course, you will learn to read and reshape a dataset from the World Bank, filter observations and select variables to produce an analysis data set and finally to produce figures. Customizing, enhancing and annotating data visualizations follows. R software with be used with functions included the tidyverse suite of packages being highlighted (dplyr, tidyr and ggplot2 in particular).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical University of South Carolina (MUSC) Short Course: Using R for Bayesian Spatial and Spatio-Temporal Health Modeling</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210601medical-university-of-south-carolina-musc-short-course-using-r-for-bayesian-spatial-and-spatio-temporal-health-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210601medical-university-of-south-carolina-musc-short-course-using-r-for-bayesian-spatial-and-spatio-temporal-health-modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Early registration ends by May 10, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: Recurrent Event Analysis in R with the reReg Package</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210531isi-short-course-recurrent-event-analysis-in-r-with-the-rereg-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210531isi-short-course-recurrent-event-analysis-in-r-with-the-rereg-package/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare recurrent event data in R with the Recur() function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploring recurrent event data with event plots and mean cumulative function with the plotEvent() and mcf() functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simulating recurrent event data and fitting regression models with the simSC() and reReg() functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Short Course: An Introductory Course in Competing Risks</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210528isi-short-course-an-introductory-course-in-competing-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210528isi-short-course-an-introductory-course-in-competing-risks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration fee: €80&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Survival function and hazard function. Right-censoring and left-truncation. Competing risks. Markov and non-Markov multi-state models. Time-homogeneity and time inhomogeneity. Motivating examples (real data).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competing risks: The competing risks multi-state model. Non-identifiability in the latent failure time model. Cause-specific hazards (transition intensities) and sub-distribution hazards. Cumulative incidence functions. Simulating competing risks data. Nonparametric estimation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportional hazards regression models: Proportional cause-specific hazards model. Proportional sub-distribution hazards model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASA Traveling Course: Introduction to Structural Equation Modeling with Health-Related Outcome Measures</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210513asa-traveling-course-introduction-to-structural-equation-modeling-with-health-related-outcome-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210513asa-traveling-course-introduction-to-structural-equation-modeling-with-health-related-outcome-measures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: salmon;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registration Deadline: May 6, 2021 @ 3pm PST; ASA members: $45, non-members: $50&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing Frameworks and Methods for Competing Risks Data</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210430competing-frameworks-and-methods-for-competing-risks-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210430competing-frameworks-and-methods-for-competing-risks-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Competing risks data arise frequently in clinical and epidemiologic studies. Such data are characterized by a survival time that terminates due to one of several mutually exclusive causes. This webinar will cover the following: the two most commonly adopted frameworks for competing risks data; relevant estimands and estimators within each framework; the role of censoring as a competing risk; available modeling strategies; and causal inference in the competing risks setting. The main ideas will be illustrated through several real-data examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polygenic Risk Prediction and Equitable Disease Prevention</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210422polygenic-risk-prediction-and-equitable-disease-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210422polygenic-risk-prediction-and-equitable-disease-prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent discoveries from large scale genome-wide association studies (GWAS) have raised the prospect of using polygenic risk scores in routine health care setting for the prediction of future incidence of large variety of complex diseases. However, as GWAS studies to date have been heavily biased towards European origin populations, current polygenic risk scores often underperform in non-European populations and thus use of them can further exacerbate healthcare inequality. In this talk, I will review simple and advanced statistical methods for generating polygenic risk score using high-dimensional SNP data and describe theoretical characterizations of their expected performance, both in the population that underlies original studies and in a different population that is expected to have different distribution of allele frequencies and linkage disequilibrium (SNP-correlation). I will further describe novel Bayesian and machine learning based methods for building polygenic risk scores that can borrow information across GWAS studies of different ethnic groups, and thus makes best use of available data to generate more powerful polygenic risk scores across different ethnic groups. I will demonstrate potential utility for PRS in precision medicine using our recent studies on breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series - A First Course with Bootstrap Sampler</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210408time-series-a-first-course-with-bootstrap-sampler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210408time-series-a-first-course-with-bootstrap-sampler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course will be a reprise of the main topics of the book by the same name, by Tucker McElroy and Dimitris Politis. The intended audience includes statisticians with little or no knowledge of time series, but a general knowledge of statistics. Prerequisites include a course on linear models, a course on mathematical statistics (such concepts as bias, variance, and the Gaussian distribution), and a familiarity with linear algebra (the transpose, inverse, and eigen-values of a matrix). The aim is to cover basic concepts of time series analysis at a level suitable for those with a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s or master&amp;rsquo;s degree in statistics, while including a few non-standard concepts such as volatility filtering and time series bootstraps. A second aim is to incorporate coding in R of all concepts, methods, and examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal Inference for Multiple Time-point (Longitudinal) Exposures</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210407causal-inference-for-multiple-time-point-longitudinal-exposures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/course/20210407causal-inference-for-multiple-time-point-longitudinal-exposures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop applies the Causal Roadmap to estimate the causal effects with multiple intervention variables, such as the cumulative effect of an exposure over time, controlled direct effects, and effects on survival-type outcomes with right-censoring. We will cover longitudinal causal models, identification in the presence of time-dependent confounding; and estimation of joint treatment effects using G-computation, inverse probability weighting (IPW), and targeted maximum likelihood estimation (TMLE) with Super Learner. During the workshop session, participants will work through the Roadmap using an applied example and implement these estimators with the ltmle R package. Prior training in causal inference in a single time-point setting is strongly recommended, but not required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
