<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RStudio | CSE Tracker</title>
    <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/tag/20200903rstudio/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/tag/20200903rstudio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>RStudio</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>RStudio</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/tag/20200903rstudio/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to Drive Agility in Clinical Reporting</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200903using-r-to-drive-agility-in-clinical-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200903using-r-to-drive-agility-in-clinical-reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The R language is used extensively throughout the pharmaceutical industry. But its use within the tightly regulated clinical reporting workflows has remained limited. GSK Biostatistics has embarked upon a journey to embed R as a primary statistical analysis tool for clinical reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enabling R within a global department of over 600 Statisticians, Programmers and Data Scientists is challenging! It requires planning, patience, and a strong foundation that enables consistency across the enterprise. We invite you to learn more about how we achieved this at GSK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll learn about our tidyverse-centric training program, a future-ready Working Area for R Programming (WARP) environment, and a leading-edge R for Clinical Reporting (R4CR) initiative. The goal: help embed R in every-day clinical reporting output.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debunking the R vs. Python Myth</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200826debunking-the-r-vs-python-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200826debunking-the-r-vs-python-myth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How many times have you heard the phrase “X is better than Y for data science”? This is a very common misconception among data scientists, and a very broad definition of data science as a whole. For data science to be impactful, it needs to be credible, agile, and durable. To be able to do this, we need to embrace the differences between R vs. Python. Maybe you prefer R for data wrangling and Python for modeling - that’s great! Why should serious data science be stifled for the sake of language loyalty? Data science teams need to use the wealth of tools available to them to deliver the most impactful results. This webinar will be a discussion among data science leaders, debunking this common myth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> testthat 3.0.0</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200813testthat-3-0-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200813testthat-3-0-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce some of the major changes coming in testthat 3.0.0. The biggest new idea in testthat 3.0.0 is the idea of an edition. You must deliberately choose to use the 3rd edition, which allows us to make breaking changes without breaking old packages. testthat 3e deprecates a number of older functions that we no longer believe are a good idea, and tweaks the behaviour of expect_equal() and expect_identical() to give considerably more informative output (using the new waldo package).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;testthat 3e also introduces the idea of snapshot tests which record expected value in external files, rather than in code. This makes them particularly well suited to testing user output and complex objects. I&amp;rsquo;ll show off the main advantages of snapshot testing, and why it&amp;rsquo;s better than our previous approaches of verify_output() and expect_known_output().&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over a bunch of smaller quality-of-life improvements, including tweaks to test reporting and improvements to expect_error(), expect_warning() and expect_message().&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Remote Data Science Teams</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200728enabling-remote-data-science-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200728enabling-remote-data-science-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up a remote and collaborative R environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Version control and Scrum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Shiny and RStudio Connect to share apps within and across teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to improve the UI and appearance of Shiny dashboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to scale Shiny dashboards to hundreds of users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to build and grow a remote data science team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid Dashboard Fatigue</title>
      <link>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200714avoid-dashboard-fatigue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://master--youthful-lamport-190a0e.netlify.app/webinar/20200714avoid-dashboard-fatigue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, we’ll show you an easy way teams can solve these problems using proactive email notifications through the blastula and gt packages, and how RStudio pro products can be used to scale out those solutions for enterprise applications. Dynamic emails are a powerful way to meet decision makers where they live - their inbox - while displaying exactly the results needed to influence decision-making. Best of all, these notifications are crafted with code, ensuring your work is still reproducible, durable, and credible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll demonstrate how this approach provides solutions for data quality monitoring, detecting and alerting on anomalies, and can even automate routine (but precisely formatted) KPI reporting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
