<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PSI | BIG Event Tracker</title>
    <link>/tag/20211021psi/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/20211021psi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PSI</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 06:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>PSI</title>
      <link>/tag/20211021psi/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint PSI, EFSPI and ASA BIOP Webinar - Complex Innovative Designs</title>
      <link>/webinar/20211021joint-psi-efspi-asa-biop-webinar-complex-innovative-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20211021joint-psi-efspi-asa-biop-webinar-complex-innovative-designs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PSI, the European Federation of Statisticians in the Pharmaceutical Industry (EFSPI) and the Biopharmaceutical Section of the American Statistical Association (ASA) are jointly organising a webinar on Complex Innovative Designs (CID) in practice.  Speakers from regulatory authorities and industry will present on their experience, which will include the following aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of the FDA Complex Innovative Trial Design pilot program and the applications received to date together with details on some of them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of the FDA guidance on interacting on Complex Innovative Trial Designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detailed case study of a clinical trial in children which was evaluated within FDA’s CID pilot program, applying borrowing of information from external trials in adults&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of statistical and regulatory considerations on master protocols, focusing on Phase III confirmatory trials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of a Statistician</title>
      <link>/webinar/20210226the-role-of-a-statistician/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20210226the-role-of-a-statistician/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Observations on SARS-CoV-2 and Crisis Vaccine Clinical Testing</title>
      <link>/webinar/20201210statistical-observations-on-sars-cov-2-and-crisis-vaccine-clinical-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20201210statistical-observations-on-sars-cov-2-and-crisis-vaccine-clinical-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Traditional vaccine clinical development is an undertaking involving meticulous, multiple studies in multiple populations at risk of infection and disease over multiple years. SARS-CoV-2 and COVID-19 vaccine development is following this traditional development pathway, but accelerated Phase I-II-III clinical programs are being applied (c.f., USA FDA guidances 2020). This is not the first time vaccines have been manufactured and tested quickly to meet a public health crisis (1976, 2009). Selected statistical concepts pertaining to vaccine efficacy and safety, relevant during the design and implementation of such crisis programs, are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Statistical Practices to Tackle the Lack of Reproducibility in Preclinical Research</title>
      <link>/webinar/20200715good-statistical-practices-to-tackle-the-lack-of-reproducibility-in-preclinical-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20200715good-statistical-practices-to-tackle-the-lack-of-reproducibility-in-preclinical-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4 key learnings attendees will take away from this webinar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of good design of experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider Bayesian statistics to answer your question&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;P-values is not always what you’re looking for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopt a life-cycle over the long-run, not just study by study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
