<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science | CSE Tracker</title>
    <link>/tag/20220106data-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/20220106data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Data Science</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 08:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Data Science</title>
      <link>/tag/20220106data-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Data &amp; AI - How Shopify Applies ML for Anomaly Detection and Forecasting At Scale</title>
      <link>/webinar/20220106enterprise-data-ai-how-shopify-applies-ml-for-anomaly-detection-and-forecasting-at-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 08:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20220106enterprise-data-ai-how-shopify-applies-ml-for-anomaly-detection-and-forecasting-at-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Shopify, we have over 1.7 million merchants across over 175 countries, with hundreds of millions of consumers shopping at their stores. We’re focused on leveraging the scale of our data to not only empower Shopify, but to create new experiences for our merchants that are impossible without data. In our daily operations at Shopify, we are highly data informed. Some of the ways we’re leveraging advanced analytics is by building an anomaly detection engine that allows us to process over hundreds of thousands of metric/segment combinations in a very accessible way. In her talk, Dr. Hilal will share key tips on how you can apply machine learning for anomaly detection and forecasting at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Webinar: Hiring Great Data Science Teams</title>
      <link>/webinar/20211012rstudio-webinar-hiring-great-data-science-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20211012rstudio-webinar-hiring-great-data-science-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this panel webinar, you will hear from leaders at RStudio, Pandora, Beam Dental, &amp;amp; Amwell, about what it takes to hire for a successful data science team:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their experiences and perspective on hiring to build great data science teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How their teams prioritizes skills and experience in new positions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How they think about skill assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their advice to data scientists just getting started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
