<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epidemiology | CSE Tracker</title>
    <link>/category/20210513epidemiology/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/20210513epidemiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Epidemiology</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Epidemiology</title>
      <link>/category/20210513epidemiology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>COPSS-NISS COVID-19 Data Science Webinar Series: Communication of Statistical and Epidemiologic Concepts to Broad Audiences</title>
      <link>/webinar/20210513copss-niss-covid-19-data-science-webinar-series-communication-of-statistical-and-epidemiologic-concepts-to-broad-audiences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20210513copss-niss-covid-19-data-science-webinar-series-communication-of-statistical-and-epidemiologic-concepts-to-broad-audiences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past year has seen a huge increase in the communication of statistical, medical, and public health concepts, methods, and results to broad audiences.  The general public has been exposed to the ideas of reproduction numbers, exponential growth, randomized trials, and the challenges of program evaluation in ways that had rarely been seen at such a large scale.  This webinar will provide a discussion between two experts in scientific communication&amp;ndash;Jenn Dowd, co-founder of Dear Pandemic and Associate Professor at the University of Oxford, and Ed Yong, staff writer at The Atlantic. They will discuss what they have learned during the course of the pandemic about communicating statistical/epidemiological concepts to broad audiences, what challenges remain, and how might we best address them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from COVID-19 Data on Transmission, Health Outcomes, Interventions and Vaccination </title>
      <link>/webinar/20210323learning-from-covid-19-data-on-transmission-health-outcomes-interventions-and-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20210323learning-from-covid-19-data-on-transmission-health-outcomes-interventions-and-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Video Passcode &lt;span style=&#34;color: green;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;=TpGiw#6&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;br&gt;
ASA Members: $20&lt;br&gt;
Student ASA Member: $15&lt;br&gt;
Nonmembers: $35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will first provide a historical overview of the epidemic in Wuhan. I will then provide the analysis results of 32,000 lab-confirmed COVID-19 cases in Wuhan to estimate the transmission rates using Poisson Partial Differential Equation based transmission dynamic models. This model is also used to evaluate the effects of different public health interventions on controlling the COVID-19 outbreak, such as social distancing, isolation and quarantine. I will present the results on the epidemiological characteristics of the cases. The results show that multi-faceted intervention measures successfully controlled the outbreak in Wuhan. I will next present transmission regression models for estimating transmission rates in USA and other countries, as well as factors including intervention effects using social distancing, test-trace-isolate strategies that affect transmission rates. I will discuss estimation of the proportion of undetected cases, including asymptomatic, pre-symptomatic cases and mildly symptomatic cases, the chances of resurgence in different scenarios, prevalence, and the factors that affect transmissions. I will also present the US county-level analysis to study the demographic, social-economic, and comorbidity factors that are associated with COVID-19 case and death rates. I will also present the analysis results of &amp;gt;500,000 participants of the HowWeFeel project on health outcomes and behaviors in US, and discuss the factors associated with infection, behavior, and vaccine hesitancy. I will provide several takeaways and discuss priorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Multiple Natural Experimental Designs to Triangulate the Impact of a Policy Change</title>
      <link>/webinar/20200717dahshu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/webinar/20200717dahshu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Estimating causal effects is best done using randomized controlled trials. Regrettably, for many policy-relevant questions only observational data are available. In this talk we explore how (i) decomposing a policy into multiple parts, and (ii) leveraging multiple study designs can produce stronger, more defensible causal estimates.&lt;br&gt;
We explore these statistical concepts through an example from health outcomes research: The feasibility and effectiveness of delaying surgery to transfer patients with acute type A aortic dissection—a catastrophic disease that requires prompt intervention—to higher-volume aortic surgery hospitals is unknown. We investigated the hypothesis that regionalizing care at high-volume hospitals for acute type A aortic dissections will lower mortality. We decomposed this hypothesis into subparts, investigating the isolated effect of transfer and the isolated effect of receiving care at a high-volume versus a low-volume facility. We used a preference-based instrumental variable design to address unmeasured confounding and matching to separate the effect of transfer from volume. We used the carefully deployed instrumental variable design, and contrast it with a decomposed propensity score study design, to gain deeper insights into the elements giving rise to confounding. We also develop a simple, but complete, form of sensitivity analysis to bound the effect of censored observations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
